本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：十九罗汉  老麦  笨熊猫  小饭  我不是青椒  不悛熊
时间轴：菜六水  小萌  小仓鼠   校对：何何  米苏  Joanna
后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
最高机密禁止外泄
导弹发射命令
紧急行动通知
来源: 国防部南极紧急司令部
至: 美军舰  科罗拉多号
最高机密禁止外泄
导弹发射命令
紧急行动通知
来源: 国防部南极紧急司令部
至: 美军舰  科罗拉多号
472 查普林
北约属地
发射源不明
正追踪导弹轨迹并识别
传感器
总统受到抨击
弹劾投票迫近
赤道
巴基斯坦
目标锁定
反制措施已启动
米
爆炸性新闻
巴基斯坦击沉美军军舰科罗拉多号
150名美军船员极可能阵亡
美海军上将千金也名列死亡名单之上
世界格局悬于一线
美国指责巴基斯坦袭击行为  战争一触即发？
爆炸性新闻: 全世界恐慌  死亡人数攀升
导弹发射
一号导弹即将发射
T5呼叫主舰
Hospitality, this is Tango Five.
我们还有四分钟到达  请求紧急救援
We're four mikes out, requesting hot extract.
霍普  挺住啊
Hopper, stay with me.
T5呼叫主舰
Hospitality, this is Tango Five.
已到达指定会合地点  完毕
We're at the rendezvous. Over.
T5呼叫主舰  收到请回答
Hospitality, this is Tango Five. Do you read?
主舰  收到请回答
Hospitality, do you read?
转舵  准备再次下潜
Helm, ready for dive.
我们不会在此停留太久
We're not gonna be here long.
水手长请协助海豹突击队员登舰
Chief of the boat, you get those SEALs on board
越快越好
as fast as you can.
收到多个信号
I have multiple contacts.
航线外部出现巨大目标
Something big outside the lane.
正在分析
Classifying now.
先生们  我们浮出的位置位于海上要道
Gentlemen, we have just surfaced in the middle of a highway.
有任何异常立刻通知我
Let me know if anything acts pissy.
谢帕德上尉
Lieutenant Shepard,
请准备三条安全撤离路线
I need three good ways out of here.
是  长官
Aye-aye, sir.
长官  雷达发现巴基斯坦佐勒菲卡尔号护卫舰
Sir, big boy at sea is a Pakistani Zulfiquar class frigate
正向我方位置驶来
turning on our position.
舰长  舱口已关闭
Captain, the hatch is shut.
准备就绪
Straight board.
开始下潜  上尉
Submerge the boat, lieutenant.
下潜  下潜  前舱排气
Dive! Dive! Venting forward.
后舱排气
Venting aft.
全速三分之二  操275度
Ahead two-thirds. Come to 2-7-5.
谢帕德上尉  你接管指挥台
Lieutenant Shepard, you have the conn.
副舰长  跟我来
X.O., you're with me.
-长官  -放松  上尉
- Sir. - Relax, lieutenant.
这不是真的战争
We aren't actually at war.
只是要让他认识到
Just make him realize
如果这是在战争中他会死得多惨
how incredibly dead he'd be if we were.
水手长  谢谢你
Thanks, chief.
没事  孩子
You bet, son.
小心这些人
Careful with these boys.
他们口风特别紧
They're wound tight.
我是队长吉尔・兰斯顿
Gil Langston, captain.
谢谢你们的支援
Thank you for the pickup.
随时效劳
Anytime.
你的弟兄怎么样了
How's your man?
需要送往医院
Needs a hospital.
我们正要与艾森豪威尔号航母攻击群会合
We're headed towards the Eisenhower Group
测试新装备
to test a new piece of equipment.
五小时内我们就会进入直升机接应范围
Five hours, we'll be in range of the choppers.
你们的处境似乎非常不妙啊
That's some serious heat that came after you guys.
能向我们透露点情况吗
Anything we should know?
再次感谢你们的支援  舰长
Once again, captain, thank you for the pickup.
你就非得问  对吧
You had to ask, didn't you?
那里到底怎么回事
What the hell happened back there?
科泰兹  雷纳尔兹  别老让我追着你们
Cortez, Reynolds, don't make me chase you down.
现在是下午两点
1400 hours,
出海第五十六天
day 56 of the tour,
此次会议的目的
this is a meeting to allow you to inform me
是向两位询问  是否有任何舰队成员
if any member of the crew has acted towards you
以任何形式冒犯了你们
in a manner offensive to yourself
或是任何你们姐妹团的其他女性
or to the other female members of your rack,
或者以任何形式
or in a manner contrary...
违反海军的管理条例
to the rules and regulations of Navy policy.
你既然要负责敏感问题
But how are you--how are you supposed to
那为什么还会叫我们姐妹团
do sensitivity duty and you all talking about "Racks"?
回答问题  科泰兹
Just answer the question, Cortez.
没有人冒犯  打扰  骚扰
No one has offended, bothered, copped a feel,
或是调戏任何一位姐妹团成员
or otherwise molested any member of my rack.
不过我真喜欢每周聊这些
Love these weekly chats, though.
欢迎加入海军  水手
Welcome to the Navy, sailor.
不对不对  兄弟  听着
No, no, no, no, man, look.
他的音乐就像这样...
He's like, he's like...
-就是一种感觉  伙计  不是理智  -真傻
- It's a feeling, V. It's not intellectual. - Stupid.
你是亚利桑那州来的吧
No, I mean, look, you're-- you're from Arizona, right?
没错
Yeah.
好吧  我无意冒犯
Okay, I'm not even being offensive,
我还有个表亲就住在图森
'cause I got a cousin from Tucson...
但你根本不懂他的音乐
But it just means that you have no idea what he's doing.
我不懂?
I have no idea?
没错  在你眼中他完全不入流
No. You think he's all "Ho this" And "Bitch that"...
我可没这么说
That's not what I said.
但其实不是的  其实
And it's just not the case. It's just not the...
不是吧  你们还没扯完啊
Really? Are you guys still at this?
副舰长  我申请
X.O., permission to shoot
一枪打穿布兰伦士官的脑袋
petty Officer Brannan in the head.
批准了
Permission granted.
这可能是我们会遇到的最像真实战争的事情了
Closest thing to an actual engagement we'll probably ever see,
他居然让她指挥
and he gives her the conn?
就那么轻易移交给她
Just hands it over,
"来吧  宝贝儿  好好乐一把哦"
like "Here you go, sweetheart. You have fun with that."
作为海军上将的千金可真好啊
Yeah, nice being an admiral's kid.
"舰长哥哥  我真的能开这艘小船船吗"
"Oh, captain, are you really gonna let me drive the boat?"
长官
Ma'am.
副舰长  舰长让你完事后去舰长室找他
X.O., captain wants to see you in his quarters when you're done.
副舰长接管指挥台
X.O. on the conn.
你手下的劳伦斯和斯特恩
Your guys Lawrence and Stern,
他们在背后嘲讽格蕾丝
they're busting Grace's balls.
我不知情  长官
I wasn't aware of the presence of those, sir.
我会处理好的
Consider it taken care of.
谢谢
Thank you.
请进
Come in.
杰弗里怎么样啊
How's Jeffrey doing?
你肯定很骄傲吧
You must be proud.
是啊  他说他嫉妒我
Yeah, he says he's jealous of me,
能天天待在水里
being surrounded by water.
估计他那儿特别缺水吧
Guess it's pretty dry where they are.
凯姆伦正在追踪那舰队
Listen, Cameron's been tracking the fleet.
做他专长的事情呢
He's doing that thing that he does.
你有艾森豪威尔号攻击群改变航向的消息吗
What do you know about the Eisenhower Group changing course?
这是刚播出的新闻
Here's the latest surface grab
华府乱成一团了
D.C. is falling apart.
四名上将辞职以示抗议
Four generals resigned in protest,
声称总统的新政策是鲁莽而不负责任的
calling the president's policies reckless and irresponsible.
随着弹劾投票的迫近
As the impeachment vote approaches,
四面楚歌的总统...
the embattled president...
罗纳德・里根
Ronald Reagan
把所有空中交通管制员都解雇了
fires all the air traffic controllers.
他的手下都找到他问道
And his guys come to him, and they say,
"总统阁下  你为什么要这么做
"Mr. President, why did you go and do such a thing?
所有人都会认为你疯了"
Everyone's gonna think you're crazy."
而里根
And Reagan...
他指着总统办公室里
He points out the window of the Oval Office
面向俄罗斯的窗户
toward Russia,
他说  "这就对了
and he says, "That's right.
这正是我想让那混蛋认为的情况"
That's exactly what I need that bastard to think."
我们庆祝什么呢
Uh, what are we celebrating?
每个人都认为勃列日涅夫是个疯子
You see, everyone knew Brezhnev was crazy.
勃列日涅夫:1960年任苏联最高苏维埃主席团主席
阿富汗战争的发动者
他入侵了阿富汗
Hell, he invaded Afghanistan.
问题在于
The problem was,
没有人知道里根是否如此
nobody knew if Reagan was.
但是要想成为大权在握的人
And if there's one absolute truth to being the man
绝对要做到的一点
with your finger on the button,
就是要如此
that's it.
他们得认为你疯了
They have to think you're crazy.
这杯敬置身水下五百英尺
Here's to being 500 feet under
并且暂时远离这一切
and half a world away from it all.
威尔・弗瑞尔斯正在为弗吉尼亚州海军司令部
Will Frears is looking for a second
寻找一名副手
at Naval Command, Virginia.
我举荐了你
I recommended you.
我们回去后你可以和克里斯蒂待一周
You can take a week with Christine once we get back
然后就做好调动吧
and make the move.
马库斯
Marcus..
山姆  不管你认为是否对我有所亏欠
Whatever you think you owe me, Sam,
你早已经百倍地还我了
you've paid a hundred times over.
你的妻子还等着你呢
You have a wife.
回家吧  做份文职
Go home. Take a desk.
要个孩子
Start a family.
水手长
Chief of the boat.
听着  格蕾丝
Listen, Grace, um...
劳伦斯和斯特恩
Lawrence and Stern,
他们正在接受一周打扫厕所的惩罚
they'll be pulling latrine duty for a week.
我只希望你知道  这不是因为你是女人
I just hope you understand it's not about you being a woman.
他们对我毫无敬意
I just haven't earned their respect.
他们两个负责打扫两周厕所
- Well...  - Two weeks latrine duty for both of them,
水手长  称呼我时请用军衔或者长官
and, C.O.B., you address me by my rank or ma'am,
而不是我的名
not my first name.
谢帕德上尉  汇报当前位置
Lieutenant Shepard, position report.
长官  斯里兰卡西南方向1012公里
1,012 clicks south west of Sri Lanka, sir.
穿越赤道时间为
Crossing the equator in...
现在正在穿越赤道  长官
Oh, crossing now, sir.
格蕾丝  第一次在舰艇上穿越赤道吧
First time crossing the equator on a warship, Gracie?
长官
Sir.
回各自战位
Battle station.
长官  我已解密导弹发射命令
Sir, I have a decoded missile fire order
发自国防部南极紧急司令部
from D.O.D. Emergency Antarctic Network.
南极
Antarctica?
鉴定命令
Authenticate the order.
发射命令
Fire order.
鉴别代码
Authentication code
VZZC  MYXW
Victor-zulu-zulu-Charlie, Mike-yankee-X-ray-whiskey-
ZDDK
zulu-delta-delta-kilo.
代码确认无误
The order's authenticated.
我同意
I concur.
老天啊
Sweet mother of God.
他们不应该用南极司令部
They shouldn't be using the Antarctica network.
他们用它时只可能因为
They would only do that if--
华府在攻击中被完全摧毁
If the main one was taken out by a full strike.
准备发射
Weapons conn,
我们收到确认后的发射命令
we have an authenticated fire order.
导弹一到四号准备发射
Spin up missiles one through four.
准备发射  我是副舰长
Weapons, this is the X.O.
我同意舰长命令
I concur with the captain.
转舵  操020度
Helm, come to heading 0-2-0.
到达导弹发射深度
Come to missile firing depth.
发射准备 目标锁定
Conn, weapons. Targets locked.
导弹自旋预备
Missiles spinning up.
副舰长
X.O...
将钥匙插入点火装置
Insert your key into the firing station.
我们都在想那个问题  说出来吧
We're both thinking it. Go ahead and say it.
为什么是南极司令部
Why the Antarctic Network?
他们只有在华府司令部被毁了
They'd only use it if D.C. Command was gone
或者不能使用的时候才会用它
or it was rendered inoperable.
舰长  让我们再看一下
Captain, let's just take a look.
通讯部门  推出天线
Communications, roll out the antenna.
让我们看一下
Get us something to look at.
长官  发射已被批准了
Sir, we're cleared to fire.
接通国家司令部
Get me national command.
长官  你会打破无线电静默
Sir, you break radio silence,
这直接违反了操作规程
we're in direct contradiction to procedure.
知道了
Noted.
克利斯  接通通话
Get 'em on the horn, Chris.
美军舰科罗拉多号舰长  这里是国家司令部
U.S.S. "Colorado" Command, this is National Command.
我是美军舰科罗拉多号舰长
This is captain Marcus Chaplin,
马库斯・查普林
U.S.S. "Colorado."
我通过南极后备司令部
I have an authenticated fire order
收到了确认后的发射命令
through the Antarctic secondary network.
我舰请求通过
Requesting confirmation of the order
标准紧急行动通讯网络发送命令确认
through the standard E.A.M. Network.
舰长  你已经收到确认的发射命令了
Captain, you have an authenticated fire order.
我知道
I'm aware of that.
请通过正规频道再次发送
Now send it through the proper channel.
我们为什么不发射
Why aren't we firing?
这是上级直接下达的命令  长官
It's a direct order, sir.
舰长  你要抗命不尊吗
Captain, are you refusing the order?
听着  不管你是谁
Listen, whoever the hell you are,
我没有接到宣战的指令
I don't have a declaration of war
而且我不明白为什么这个命令
and I see no reason for this order
来自备用频道
to come through a secondary channel,
我们都知道它存在的目的
which we all know was designed only to be used in the event
只是在华府司令部被摧毁时使用
that D.C. Command was wiped out.
但我现在在电视上看到了汉娜・蒙塔纳的节目
But I'm sitting here watching "Hannah Montana,"
你去把有权力下达这个命令的人叫来
so I'm not going to annihilate 4.3 million Pakistanis
否则我绝不会屠杀
without hearing directly from someone
430万巴基斯坦民众
whose authority I recognize.
给我接通管事的人
Get me someone I can talk to.
科罗拉多号  通讯结束
"Colorado" Out.
美军舰科罗拉多号
The U.S.S "Colorado"--
俄亥俄级核潜艇
Ohio class nuclear submarine,
舰上一百五十名男性
150 men on board.
事实上  从去年起
Actually, since last year,
还有九名女兵以及两位女性军官
nine enlisted women and two female officers as well.
这使它充满了力量
It makes its own air power.
它拥有四枚MK48鱼雷发射管
It's got four mark 48 torpedo tubes,
二十八枚战斧式导弹
28 Tomahawks,
和十八枚三叉戟核弹
and 18 Trident nuclear missiles,
它基本上可以摧毁任何东西
which can basically wipe out anything,
在任何地方  任何时间
anywhere, anytime.
天哪  我喜欢你谈论军事装备的样子
God, I love it when you talk military hardware.
是的  我知道  我很棒  对吧
Yeah, I know. I'm good, right?
但是呢  科罗拉多号有个和你一样的毛病
But see, the "Colorado" Has the same problem you do.
太有"吸引力"了
Magnetism.
像那么一艘大块头潜艇
Big sexy boat like that,
必然有特殊的磁场特征
it has its own magnetic signature,
磁场特征: 因舰体金属材质扰乱了地球磁场而形成
易被敌舰探测到或易受磁性水雷攻击
让这艘造价四十亿美元的潜艇
which turns a $4-billion sub
变成了活靶子
into a sitting duck.
而现在艇上装上了老娘的样机
Except now with the prototype I've put on board,
再也不会暴露磁场特征了
no signature.
海军军方早就对这项技术垂涎三尺了
The Navy is already drooling over this thing.
明天测试以后  他们肯定要大批订货
And after tomorrow's test, they're gonna want lots of them.
这就要用到你那个参议员了
That is where your senator comes in.
我没法儿拒绝你
Who can say no to you?
你敢...别接
Oh, don't you... dare. No.
不
No.
不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
你来真的吗
You can't be serious.
472 查普林  是个地址吗
What's "472 Chaplin"? Is that an address?
不是
No.
-别告诉我你今晚又要开会  -不是
- Tell me you don't have another meeting tonight.  - No.
相信我罗伯特
Trust me, Robert,
我其实哪里都不想去
there is nowhere I would rather be,
什么事什么人都不想见
and nothing and no one I would rather be doing,
但我得走了
but I've gotta go.
这...
Hey, this...
这可是你的公寓啊
This is your apartment.
我是马库斯・查普林舰长
Captain Marcus Chaplin.
舰长  我是国防部副部长威廉・科利
Captain, this is Deputy Secretary of Defense William Curry.
我们大概一年前在第二潜艇集团军演中见过
We met about a year ago at a CSG2 event.
你能听出我的声音吗
Do you recognize my voice?
能  长官
I do, sir.
不过为何不是部长本人
Although, why isn't the secretary himself
或者总统听电话呢
or the president on the line?
马库斯・查普林舰长
Captain Marcus Chaplin,
根据海军军规第472条
you are relieved of your command
你现被免除指挥权
under section 472 of the naval code.
请将电话递给你的大副
Please pass me to your first officer.
我是科罗拉多号副舰长山姆・肯德尔
This is "Colorado" X.O. Sam Kendal.
肯德尔少校
Lieutenant Commander Kendal,
从现在起你被晋升为潜艇舰长
as of this moment, you are advanced to Captain of the Boat.
你接到了准许开火命令  对吗
You have an authorized fire order, do you not?
对  长官
Affirmative, sir.
谢帕德上尉
Lieutenant Shepard,
请取走查普林舰长点火装置的钥匙
take the firing key from Captain Chaplin
并插入点火装置中
and insert it into the firing computer.
科利长官  我是代理舰长山姆・肯德尔
Mr. Curry, this is the acting Captain Sam Kendal.
请求通过正规的
Request that you send the order
紧急行动通讯频道下达命令 长官
via the regular E.A.M. Channel, sir.
好  舰长
Okay, Captain.
请待命
Stand by.
通讯被切断了  长官
Line's dead, sir.
这到底怎么回事
What the hell's going on here?
为什么船员都在说你们拒绝执行命令
Why is the crew talking about you refusing orders?
水手长  请让这些人离开指挥台
Chief of the Boat, remove these men from the conn.
除非亲眼见到命令  否则我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere till I see those orders.
凭什么  你有资格吗
You have no authority here. This is my boat.
敢在老子的地盘上撒野  给我滚出指挥台
So get your ass off this conn now.
听不懂舰长的命令吗
You heard the man.
我们看不到那条命令决不罢休
There's no way we're not seeing that order.
你们无权看那条命令
They are not your orders to see.
我本以为你们海豹突击队员该聪明点
I thought you SEAL boys were supposed to be smart.
在潜艇里开枪可不是闹着玩的
Bullets and submarines don't get along so well.
没事  舰长  我们从来弹无虚发
That's okay, Captain. We don't miss.
长官  有巡航导弹向我方袭来
Sir, I have inbound cruise missile on our position!
老天啊  还剩二十秒
Oh, my God. 20 seconds out.
紧急下潜
Emergency deep!
全体船员注意  紧急下潜  紧急下潜
All hands! Emergency deep! Emergency deep!
-右满舵  -抓牢了
- Right full rudder! - Grab on to something.
还有十秒
Ten seconds out.
下潜至海底  抓紧了
Point us at the bottom. Hold on!
炸弹来了
Here it comes!
迅速拉起潜艇
Bring us up!
不行  推进系统失灵
Negative! Control surfaces are nonresponsive.
系统重启中
Rebooting the system.
全体船员注意  船舱进水
All hands, we have water in the boat!
撤离前部船舱
Evacuate forward compartment.
封闭副发动机室  封闭医务室
Seal auxiliary engine. Seal sick bay.
医务室  霍普还在那里
Hey, sick bay? Hopper.
等等  医务室先别封  我到那去关
Wait! Hold sick bay. I'll do it on-site.
系统恢复正常
We're back online.
-紧急上浮  -压载舱强行排水
- Emergency blow. - Blowing tanks.
即将撞击海底
Bottom approaching!
五十英尺
50 feet!
四十  三十  快要撞到了
40. 30. We're going in.
全体船员注意  准备撞击
All hands, brace for impact!
组织营救小组怎么样
What about an extraction team?
太深了  我们正处一千五六百英尺深处
Too deep! We're 1,500, maybe 1,600 feet down!
潜艇自救的理论深度  只有一千三百英尺
Hull's only rated to 1,300.
我们得马上撤出去
We gotta leave right now!
我带上霍普随后就来
We're right behind you with Hopper.
吉尔
Gil!
快点  帮我把它关上
Come on! Help me close this!
不是我们的设备失灵
We're not having a malfunction of our equipment yet.
不  听我说
No, excuse me.
这明显就是导弹轨迹
We're looking at a clear missile signature.
我理解
Yes, I understand.
但我们是北约预警站
But we're a NATO early warning station.
你们的规定中要求...
Your regulations require...
看看这加速轨迹
Look, the acceleration here.
是一枚美国战斧式导弹
That's an American tomahawk.
是美国战斧式导弹
It's a tomahawk.
对  你们的一枚导弹出现在了
Yes, one of your missiles was in the air
印度和巴基斯坦附近的上空
in the vicinity of India and Pakistan,
这可能导致核大国间的核武冲突
which could lead to a nuclear power shooting back at you,
那可就...
and that's...
不太好了
you know, not good.
明白了
Understood.
-一群混蛋  -盯紧目标地区
- Bastards. - Focus on the target area.
回去查记录
Go back into the record,
之前一小时的每一条都不要放过
everything for the past hour.
挖出点能让我在北约司令部说上话的证据来
Give me something I can take to NATO command.
朱利安
Julian,
我知道这岛上的人差不多都要拍你的马屁
I know the rest of this island pretty much kisses your ass,
但你不能就这么大摇大摆地进来
but you can't just waltz in here.
天下本就没有"门"
There's no gate in this world,
只有你不想要的  没有打不开的
there's not something somebody wants won't unlock it.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
谢谢
Thank you.
但你现在得走了  多少钱
But now you need to go. Uh, how much?
这是一件礼物  索菲
It's a gift, Sophie.
改天你回赠我一份礼物就成
Someday, you'll give me a gift.
舰体受损
Boat's damaged.
并有人员伤亡
We got casualties.
我们不知道是谁袭击了我们
We don't know who hit us
也不知道对方是否正伺机发动第二波袭击
or if they're waiting up top for a second shot.
全舰上下一百五十人正命悬一线
We got 150 lives at stake here,
你是救我们于水火的不二人选
and the man best equipped to lead us out of this mess
可你却坐在房间里听起了莫扎特
is sitting in his room chilling out to Mozart.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
他们也需要你
They need your help.
他们已经有舰长了
They have a captain.
就是你
You.
舰长接管指挥台
Captain on the conn.
一切正常了
We're clear, sir.
左右引擎推进  微速前进  操090度
All ahead, dead crawl coming to 0-9-0.
谢谢
Thank you.
还有别的事吗
Something else?
很多船员都在疑惑
Well, a lot of the crew's been wondering...
接下来该怎么办
what happens next?
这里是...
This is...
这里是代理舰长
this is the acting captain.
科罗拉多号已恢复正常运作
The "Colorado" has been returned to operational status.
本次遇袭牺牲了12名战友
We lost 12 souls in the attack.
以后我们一定会好好悼念他们
There will be time to mourn them later.
全舰的军官们
The officers of this vessel
早晚会向相关部门
will eventually appear before the proper authorities
解释我们此举的用意
to explain our actions.
在那之前  我们先找个避风港
Till then, let's get somewhere safe
这样大家才能再与家人团圆
so we can all see our families again.
所有人各司其职
Everybody do their job.
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
我查出袭击我们的是哪艘舰艇了  长官
I got a fix on the boat who shot us, sir.
是伊利诺斯号
It's the "Illinois."
自己人居然想击沉我们
Our own people tried to sink us?
违抗军令  你说还会是什么下场
What do you think happens when you ignore orders?
这不是违抗军令  只是请求解释
We didn't ignore anything. We questioned.
难道光凭这点就打自己人吗
You don't hit your own people for that.
你这是疯了  在全国海军的追击之下
This is insane. We can't hide from
躲得了初一躲不过十五
the entire U.S. Navy forever.
上尉说得对
The Lieutenant's right.
我们得浮出水面并举白旗投降
We need to surface and wave the white flag.
要是那面白旗反而让我们成了活靶子呢
And what if they use that flag as a target?
我们根本不知道他们奉命何为
We don't know what their orders are.
只知道华府高层一定出了严重问题
All we know is that there's something seriously wrong in D.C.,
所以我们还是抽身走人
so we're leaving this party.
这算哪门子计划
That's your damn plan?
当逃兵  逃到哪里  逃多久
To run? To where? For how long?
说够了没  水手长  去巡你的视吧
That's enough, C.O.B.! Go make your rounds!
老海军中流行这么一句话
Old Navy saying...
"愚人必自食恶果"
"The stupid will be punished."
你这是在违抗我的命令吗
Are you challenging my authority?
我再问一次
I'll repeat the question.
你还服不服从我指挥
Do you acknowledge my authority or not?
服从
I do.
我们被自家舰艇袭击了吗
We get shot by an American boat?
是伊利诺斯号干的  你怎么知道的
The "Illinois." How did you know?
转舵  操083度
Helm, come to 0-8-3.
你已经被免去舰长一职了
The captain was relieved of duty.
坚守你的战位  上尉
Man your station, Lieutenant.
你无权对我发号施令  长官
Not on orders from you, no, sir.
水手长  请让凯希尔上尉离开指挥台
Chief of the Boat, remove Lieutenant Cahill from the conn.
还等什么
Now!
这是大错特错了  你们心知肚明
You all know this is wrong.
舰长接管指挥台
Captain has the conn.
格蕾丝  请标识一下航线
Grace, I need you to plot a course.
看来我们这是久旱逢甘霖啊
I think I found our oasis.
说得漂亮
Nice speech.
总之  山姆又得在潜艇中再待两个月了
Well, anyway, Sam's underwater for two more months.
如果我都没有真去做生意的勇气
Why have I been taking business classes
何必要一直上着金融课程呢
if I don't have the guts to start a real business?
妈  我得挂了  艾玛来了
Mom, I gotta go. Emma's coming over.
我们打算聊聊材料和定价的问题
We're going to talk materials and pricing.
不
No.
五角大楼有消息称
Pentagon sources say a Pakistani warship
一艘巴基斯坦战舰毫无预警地攻击了
fired without warning at the Ohio class
俄亥俄级核潜艇是美海军一个核动力潜艇等级
俄亥俄级核潜艇所属美军舰科罗拉多号
nuclear submarine U.S.S. "Colorado".
当时该潜艇正执行...
As it was conducting...
谢帕德上将
Admiral Shepard.
我有事跟您说
I think you'll want to talk to me.
是关于科罗拉多号的  长官
It's about the "Colorado," Sir.
我们认识吗
Do I know you?
我是来自辛克莱科技公司的凯莉・辛克莱
Kylie Sinclair from Sinclair Dynatronic.
科罗拉多号上安装有我公司的样机
We had a prototype on board the "Colorado."
令千金身遭不幸  我深感遗憾
I'm sorry about your daughter, sir.
我们因遇袭而进入二级防备状态
We've been attacked, we're at Defcon 2,
二级防备状态:仅次于最高级警报: 随时动用核武器
而你却想跟我聊你的那些小玩意儿
and you want to talk about your toy?
你我心知肚明  潜艇根本不是巴基斯坦人击沉的
We both know the Pakistanis didn't sink her.
那只是你们编出来的官方说法
No matter what you're telling the American people.
-你说什么  -我花了一年时间
- What? - It took me a year
才在科罗拉多号上安装上我公司的系统
to get my system on the "Colorado",
我绝不会再等一年
and I am not gonna wait another year.
所以你若想让我守口如瓶
So if you want me to keep quiet,
下一艘出航的船上必须装上我的设备
you put my equipment on the next boat that goes out.
给我滚
You get the hell out of my face.
有个海军情报部的朋友给我发了这条短信
A friend in Navy intelligence sent me this text...
472 查普林
"472 Chaplin"...
-就在科罗拉多号遇袭前五分钟 -你哪个朋友
- five minutes before the "Colorado" Was hit. - What friend?
海军总部当时准备执行
Naval command was processing
海军军规第472条  撤掉查普林的舰长一职
a 472 protocol removal of Captain Chaplin.
你所面对的是一名叛变的核潜艇舰长
You had a rogue captain of a nuclear submarine.
舰上满载着十八枚三叉戟核弹
And with 18 tridents on board,
没人敢以身犯险
no one was gonna take any chances.
是你亲手击沉了自己的核潜艇  长官
So you sank your own boat... sir.
你个畜生
You son of a bitch.
你女儿还在船上
You sank your own daughter's boat.
你居然不知情
You didn't know?
长官
Sir?
我们得走了
We need to go now.
我知道我自私  但我不想你走
I know it's selfish, but don't go.
就擅离职守一次嘛
Go awol.
我们一起私奔
We'll go on the run together...
周游世界  销声匿迹  自给自足
town to town, hiding out, living off the land.
-就像雌雄大盗那样吗  -雌雄大盗...
- What, like Bonnie and Clyde? - Bonnie and Clyde...
《雌雄大盗》是好莱坞著名电影  男女主人公最后双双被击毙
下场是双双被子弹打成马蜂窝
Minus all the bullets at the end.
没错
Right.
四个月后我就回来了
I'll be back in four months.
我好爱你
Oh, I love you.
"全舰军官早晚自会向相关部门
"We'll appear before the proper
解释我们此举的用意"  是这意思吗
authorities to explain our actions"?
下一步呢
Then what?
这要看到底是谁下的令
Depends who really sent the order.
我去过船员餐厅
Well, I've been down in the crew's mess,
他们都看着我
and they're all looking at me,
而我却无言以对
and I don't know what to say to them.
那就什么都别说
You don't say anything.
你要让他们懂得如何坚强
You show them how to be strong.
如果你当时让我转动那把钥匙  我本会照做的
If you had told me to, I would've turned that key.
谢谢你没那样做
Thank you for not making me.
比做爱都爽
Better than sex.
说明你不够性福
Well, you're having the wrong kind of sex.
下面播报一则爆炸性新闻  巴基斯坦袭击
In breaking news, Pakistan has attacked and sunk
并击沉了一艘美国核潜艇...
an American nuclear submarine...
你看这条新闻了吗
Do you see this?
都是骗人的  是美国人在搬弄是非
They're lying. That was the American tomahawk.
接通司令部
Call command.
呼叫司令部  这里是北约驻圣玛丽娜监测站
Command, this is NATO listening post, Sainte Marina.
发现两条始于印度洋的核弹轨道
We're reporting two tracks originating in the Indian Ocean.
目标巴基斯坦
Are we shooting at Pakistan?
动真格的了
It's real.
天哪
Oh, God.
你就不能阻止它们吗
Can't you do anything?
来不及了
No. It's too late.
天哪
Oh...
长官  低频段收到大量波动
Sir, major shock waves on low frequency.
巴基斯坦附近有核弹爆炸
Those are nukes going off near Pakistan.
好了
Okay.
战争打响了
The fight's started.
现在加入战局还不算晚
It's not too late to get into it.
长官  突击队已经就绪
Sir, assault teams are ready.
浮出水面拥抱阳光吧
Let's grab some sunlight, people.
散开  你们去那边
Come on. Get 'em out of the streets!
退后
Get back!
所有人都退后
Get back! Get back!
你会说英语吗
You speak English?
医院在哪
Where's the hospital?
医院  就在那边
The hospital? It's over there.
詹姆斯  照顾好吉尔  霍普有我们呢
James, take care of Gil. We got Hopper.
我得找个地方把我朋友放下
I need a place to keep my friend
直到能带他回家
until I can get him home.
一千美元租你的储藏柜够吗
$1,000 U.S. Cover it?
剩下的是酒钱
Rest is to start a tab.
把你最好的酒都拿来
Best scotch you have.
趴下  快趴下
Get down! Get down! Get down!
趴下
Get down!
安全
Clear!
你们是谁
Who are you?
凯姆伦  有什么发现
Talk to me, Cameron.
跟科罗拉多号一样的系统
Same interface as the "Colorado",
一样的软件
same software.
很好  雷达通讯全开
Good. Get us eyes and ears.
-一切安全就绪  -你们以为这是哪里啊
- We're clear. - I don't know where you think you are,
这个监测站归北约所有
but this station belongs to NATO.
你错了
No.
这个监测站和外面停靠的那艘潜艇
This station and that sub parked outside,
现在起都归我管
they all belong to me now.
谢帕德上将办公室
Admiral Shepard's office.
亚瑟  我是马库斯
Arthur, it's Marcus.
格蕾丝就在我旁边
Grace is right here.
爸  是我
Dad, it's me.
我以为你死了
I thought I'd lost you.
爸
Dad...
你一直告诉我荣誉高于一切
You always told me, honor before all.
等你了解事情始末后
So... when you learn what happened...
希望你能为我们自豪
I hope you're proud of us.
亚瑟  我们从南极司令部收到开火指令
Arthur, we got fire orders on the Antarctic Network.
当我们请求确认时  伊利诺伊号向我们开火
When we asked for confirmation, the "Illinois" Shot us up,
差点被击沉
damn near killed us.
白宫说是巴基斯坦人干的
The White House said it was the Pakistanis.
现在是战时
We're at war.
亚瑟  你还在吗
Arthur, are you there?
我没法不注意到今天一下子
I couldn't help but notice an increase in...
多了不少游客
tourists today.
你到我这个可爱小岛
Afraid I need to ask you your intentions
来干什么
towards my beautiful little island.
我就是想来喝个大醉
My only intention is to get fall-down drunk.
不过你可能发现他们已经接管这里了
Although you may have noticed the guy invading the place.
他们准备什么时候滚蛋
And when does this man plan on leaving?
我觉得
Wild guess--
直到一个小时前
up until about an hour ago,
这里还是你说了算
you ran things here--
毒品  枪支  美女
drugs, guns, girls.
不管你有什么  都跟外面港口
Whatever it is, it's no match
停的那个大家伙比不了
for the boomer floating in your harbor.
这没你事了  "朋友"
You're done, friend.
我理解咱俩之间有些
I understand there might be some, uh,
文化差异
cultural differences here,
我帮你翻译下
so I'll translate.
我们那边  一般管你叫朋友的
When someone where I'm from calls you "Friend,"
都不把你当朋友看
they don't consider you one.
这是我的岛
This is my island.
想让我同意你们留下
If I allow your presence,
可是有条件的
it comes with certain terms and conditions.
明白吗
Is that clear...
"朋友"
friend?
第一个就是他
He's first.
你这堆人里就他真会开枪
He's the only real shooter in your bunch,
所以他先死
so the first bullet's his.
两枪打穿胸口
Big fella's probably gonna need two in the chest
确保他这个大胖子
to make sure his fat ass goes down,
死翘翘
so two he gets.
他还没摸到枪
And while dopey over there
这边这个两眼之间
fumbles for his gun in his back waistband,
就中一枪了  他也跑不了
grumpy gets one between the eyes, and so does he.
至于你
You, though...
"白雪公主"
Snow White...
我要一枪打穿你脖子
You I'm gonna shoot clean through the neck.
血大片涌出来
And that way, as the blood is gushing out your choking throat
你呛着想求我饶你一命
and you desperately beg me for your life,
可惜你一个字也说不出来
you won't be able to make a sound.
不想这样
Or...
就离我远点  让我好好喝酒
You could leave me in peace to enjoy my drink.
你们美国人
Americans...
有种  够自信
Such confidence.
你好  这里是克里斯蒂和山姆家  请留言
Hi, you've reached Christine and Sam. Please leave a message.
克里斯蒂
Christine?
你在吗  宝贝是我
Are you there, baby? It's me.
天哪  山姆  是你
Oh, my God. Sam? Sam, Sam, is that you?
真的是我  宝贝  我没事
It's me, baby. It's me. I'm okay.
不管你听说了什么  我都可以解释
Listen to me. I don't know what you've heard, but I can explain it all.
我得先安全回家
I just need to get home first.
宝贝  当初我就不该离你而去
You were right, baby. I never should've left you.
没关系  都没关系  别想这些
No, no, no, no. None of that matters.
求求你  回家就好
Just come home to me, baby. Please.
我会回去的  一定会回去的
I will. I'm gonna get back.
我保证好好补偿你
I'm gonna make it up to you. I promise.
请你相信我
Just...please believe in me.
记着我有多爱你
Please remember how much I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
不管他们说什么  都别...
Whatever they say about me, you d--
-山姆  山姆  -经常这样吗
- Sam? Sam! - Is this normal?
-不是  -发电机在哪
- No. - Where's the power?
所有系统都已瘫痪
All their systems are offline.
有我  水兵斯特恩和水手长
It's myself, Seaman Stern, and the C.O.B.
是的  长官  他们完全失去与外界联系
Yes, sir. They are blind.
不知道能坚持多久
I don't know for how much longer.
不用  长官  这是我们职责所在
No, no need, sir. It's our duty.
-退后  劳伦斯  -山姆把枪放下
- Step back, Lawrence. - Put the gun down, Sam.
不然我把你们俩都打死
I swear, I'll shoot you both.
你切断了电源
You cut the power,
还告诉司令部我们失去了与外界的联系
you called command, and you told them we'd be blind.
咱们无论如何都是死路一条
We're all dead anyway.
只不过你还不知道
You just don't know it yet.
跪下
Now get on your knees.
快跪下
On your knees!
我是不会让你得逞的
I'm not gonna let you do this.
山姆  抱歉  谁让你那么听老舰长的话
Sorry, Sam. You've always put too much faith in the old man.
你们到底干了些什么
What the hell did you just do?
来电了  系统正在重启
The power's back. Rebooting.
凯姆伦 什么情况
What have we got, Cameron?
两架飞机正向我方飞来
Two birds heading our way.
是B-1轰炸机  十五分钟后到达
B-1 bombers. 15 minutes out.
召集所有人回潜艇  要快
Get everyone back to the sub. Now.
轰炸机正在逼近  七分钟后到达
Bombers seven minutes out. Closing.
所有人员均已到齐
All crew accounted for except two.
除了布兰伦和科泰兹
We're short Brannan and Cortez.
去找他们  准备下潜
Find them. Prepare to dive.
慢着  我们绝不丢下一个人
Delay that. We're not leaving crew behind.
轰炸机会让整个小镇生灵涂炭
And hiding in the ocean is not gonna stop them
可我们深藏在海中  是阻止不了他们的
from bombing this town and all the people in it.
这样不行  我们得化守为攻了
No. We need to change the game.
准备发射  将一号导弹就位
Weapons, conn. Spin up missile one.
发射准备  一号导弹已装载完毕
Conn, weapons. Missile one is loaded and ready.
坐标已锁定  长官
Coordinates set, sir.
听我的口令  三  二  一
On my mark. Three, two, one.
这回可要出大事了
That's not good.
轰炸机四分钟后到达
Bombers four minutes out.
我是科罗拉多号核潜艇舰长马库斯・查普林
This is captain Marcus Chaplin of the U.S.S. "Colorado".
你向我方派来了两架轰炸机
You have two bombers bearing down on our position.
作为回击  我们向华府发射了一枚导弹
In response, we have a bird in flight toward D.C.
你应该已经监测到了吧
I'm sure you're reading it.
我是科利  别虚张声势了  马库斯
This is Curry. You're bluffing, Marcus.
立即启动导弹自毁装置
Initiate missile destruct immediately
这是美国总统的命令
by order of the President of the United States.
拒绝执行
Negative.
若轰炸机未在两分钟内掉头
If those bombers aren't turned around within two minutes,
我敢打包票  那枚导弹定会在华府引爆
you have my word, that missile will detonate.
科罗拉多号报告完毕
"Colorado" out.
轰炸机一分钟后到达  它们没有掉头
Bombers one minute out. Still coming. They're not turning around.
全体注意  我是舰长
Attention all hands, this is your captain.
一切努力徒劳无功  遭袭在所难免
Despite our best efforts, an attack is imminent.
我们不可能生还
We won't survive it.
能与诸位并肩作战  我荣幸之至
It's been my honor to have served with each and every one of you.
能与诸位一同赴死  我别无他求
There's no one else I'd rather be with right now.
导弹经过印第安纳州上空了  长官
Missile passing over Indiana, sir.
准备启动导弹自毁装置
Prepare to destruct missile.
轰炸机三十秒后到达
Bombers' 30 seconds out.
看来你不能马上去司令部赴任了
Guess that desk job will have to wait.
反正我也不太适合坐在办公室里  长官
I wasn't built for desks anyway, sir.
听我下令  启动导弹自毁装置  三  二
On my mark, initiate missile destruct sequence. Three, two--
等等  轰炸机掉头回去了
Wait! The bombers are turning back!
科罗拉多号  我是科利
"Colorado," this is Curry.
轰炸机已撤离  快启动导弹自毁装置
Bombers have disengaged. Initiate missile destruct now.
晚了  截止时间是九十秒前
Too late. You missed the deadline by 90 seconds.
舰长  请您插入钥匙
Captain, put your key in,
启动导弹自毁装置  快
and initiate missile destruct sequence, now.
若他们不认为我们对其构成威胁
If they don't think we'll back up our threats,
不出一周  我们必死无疑
we'll be dead in a week,
这座小镇上的所有居民也难以幸免
along with everyone else in this town.
必须让他们明白  我言出必行
They need to understand, I'm a man of my word.
马库斯  求你了
Marcus...please.
我作出的任何决定  何时损害过
Have I ever done anything other than what was in the best interest
这艘潜艇  全体艇员以及国家的利益
of this boat, this crew, and our nation?
爆炸很成功  落点在华盛顿以东两百英里
We have a good detonation, 200 miles east of Washington.
在那里引爆  不会造成人员伤亡
That distance, no one will be hurt.
但却能起到足够的威慑作用
But I'd say we got their attention.
我是科罗拉多号核潜艇舰长马库斯・查普林
I'm captain Marcus Chaplin of the U.S.S. "Colorado".
不久前  我艇接到命令
A short time ago, my submarine was ordered
向巴基斯坦发射四枚洲际弹道核导弹
to fire four nuclear I.C.B.M.s at Pakistan.
但这些命令来自一个备用
These orders came through a secondary,
且可靠性较差的通讯频道
less secure network.
兹事体大  牵涉到几百万人的生命
With millions of lives at stake,
我向政府高层请求  核准此条命令
I requested confirmation of the order
并通过正规渠道下达
be sent through the normal and proper channel.
然而  紧接着
In response,
美国伊利诺伊号攻击型潜艇便袭击了我们
an American attack sub, the U.S.S. "Illinois" fired on us
并对我艇上的船员安危置之不理
and left my crew for dead
听任我们在印度洋底自生自灭
at the bottom of the Indian Ocean.
格蕾丝  你等着瞧
You little bitch, Grace.
你该说  "上尉  你等着瞧"
It's "You little bitch, lieutenant".
我艇所经历的事  不禁令我们意识到
From our submarine, we have watched as the fabric of trust
政府与人民之间的纽带正慢慢断裂
between government and its people has been torn.
当我们大胆地向政府提出质疑
And when this boat dared to question
为何要夷平一个
why a nation without the capability
对美国本土并无威胁的国家
to directly harm the homeland was to be destroyed,
政府中的决策者竟下令杀害
elements of that government tried to kill
我艇上这一百五十名志愿服役的水手
the 150 volunteer sailors on my boat.
长官  那条情报是错的
Sir, the intell is wrong!
我们...我们杀错人了
We...we killed the wrong people.
并且他们还继续一意孤行
And then these same elements continued on their course...
-毫无缘由地...  -门没锁
- A first strike... - It's open.
向我艇发动了进攻
Unprovoked.
全体船员皆可作证
We have all borne witness.
我们接管了圣玛丽娜岛上的
We have commandeered the NATO early warning station
北约预警监测站
on the island of Sainte Marina.
运用站内设备
From this facility,
可监测世界各国军队的动向
we can see the movements of all the world's militaries.
一切尽在我们的掌控之中
We are in control.
我宣布  这座岛周围
I am declaring a 200-mile
两军交战的无人地带  是双方要争夺的地方
方圆两百英里的地区为无人地带
no-man's-land around this island,
即刻生效
effective immediately.
至于我  以及科罗拉多号上全体船员
As for myself and the men and women of the U.S.S. "Colorado"...
-看见新闻了吗  -我们深爱着祖国
- You see that? - We love our country.
都怪我  要不是我  这一切就不会发生
That was my fault. I made that happen.
为国捐躯  我们在所不辞
We would gladly die for what it represents.
都怪我  都怪我  都怪我
It was me. It was me. It was me.
我闯下大祸了
What did I do?
但我们绝不承认  也不听命于一个
But we do not recognize or obey
曾试图屠戮自己的子民的政府
a government that tries to murder its own.
若美国当局或世界上任何一个国家
If the current United States executive
派兵非法侵入了我们的领地
or any other nation violates this perimeter,
我们定会用艇上所余十七枚核弹
we have 17 more nuclear missiles aboard,
对来者予以坚决反击  绝不手软
and we will not hesitate to unleash fiery hell down upon you.
我言出必行
I give you my word.
若敢挑衅
Test us,
我们便同归于尽
and we will all burn...together.
勿谓言之不预
You've been warned.
关上吧
Cut it.
真是太疯狂了  长官
Just crazy enough, sir.
这是维修潜艇的人员找到的
Repair crews found it.
看来她还真是不想离开你啊
She's not easy to lose, is she?
多谢
Thank you.
这个曾养育我的祖国到底出了什么乱子
What happened to the country I grew up in?
被那些政客搞得一团糟
They've made it all a mess.
我们有能力做得更好
We could do better.
就在这里
Right here.
从零开始
Start from scratch.
我们的所做的一切努力  只有一个目的
Everything we did was to stay alive long enough
就是恢复清白之身并活着回家
to get our names cleared and to get home.
也许现在这里就是我们的家了
Maybe this is home now.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：笨熊猫  小侠  麦结  我不是青椒  插线  十九罗汉  宁馨儿
翻译：hammer_tank  不悛熊    校对：米苏  不悛熊  插线
时间轴：Ans  小萌    后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
《破釜沉舟》前情提要
珀尔修斯系统启动中
发现鱼雷
鞑靼海峡[俄罗斯]
新闻头条
马库斯・查普林
艾森豪威尔号: 美国航空母舰
美国陆军特种部队  主要负责反恐任务
格罗兹尼巷战  越战以后俄罗斯军队与车臣武装的惨烈战役
美国在冷战时期建造的一种高速多用途核潜艇
无人区遭到进犯
雷达合成影像  身份匹配  747商务航空  准确性评估: 97%
海军总部
克里斯蒂
没有未读信息
998号命令
长官  刚通过南极紧急通讯网
Sir, I have a missile fire order
收到导弹发射命令
from the Antarctic Network.
为什么是南极通讯网
Why the Antarctic Network?
你去把有权力下达这个命令的人叫来
I'm not going to annihilate 4.3 million Pakistanis
否则我绝不会屠杀430万巴基斯坦国民
without hearing from someone whose authority I recognize.
我查出袭击我们的是哪艘潜艇了  长官
I got a fix on the boat who shot us, sir.
是伊利诺伊号
It's the Illinois.
自己人居然想击沉我们
Our own people tried to sink us?
科罗拉多号必然有特殊的磁场特征
The Colorado has its own magnetic signature,
让这艘造价四十亿美元的潜艇变成了活靶子
which turns a $4-billion sub into a sitting duck.
而现在艇上装上了老娘的样机
Except now with the prototype I've put on board--
再也不会暴露磁场特征了
no signature.
我们接管了圣玛丽娜岛上的
We have commandeered the NATO early warning station
北约预警雷达站
on the island of Sainte Marina.
我宣布  这座岛周围
I am declaring a 200-mile
方圆两百英里的地区为无人地带
no-man's-land around this island.
山姆  是你
Sam? Sam, is that you?
真的是我  我没事
It's me. I'm okay.
不管你听说了什么
Listen to me, I don't know what you've heard,
我都可以解释
but I can explain it all.
请你相信我
Just please believe in me.
快跪下
On your knees!
我是不会让你得逞的
I'm not gonna let you do this.
你们到底干了些什么
What the hell did you just do?
若美国当局派兵非法侵入了我们的领地
If the current United States executive violates this perimeter,
我们便同归于尽
we will all burn together.
勿谓言之不预
You've been warned.
爸爸  短时间内我没法再给你发录像了
Hey, dad. So this will be the last of these for a while.
我们明天要开拔
We're headed out tomorrow.
我特别激动
I'm excited.
都准备好了
We're ready.
艇长接管指挥台
Captain's on the conn.
情况报告
Status?
航向070度  深度200英尺  长官
Heading 0-7-0 to a depth of 200 feet, sir.
很好  声纳报告
Very well. Sonar?
普林斯顿号和蒙特雷号已经到达无人区边界
The Princeton and the Monterey have reached the perimeter.
还有16艘舰艇正在逼近
I'm tracking 16 other signatures, all closing on us.
兄弟们  咱们现在简直是万人迷
Well, people, we are now the popular girl at the dance.
谢帕德中尉  你那里有什么情况
Lieutenant Shepard, what do you see?
雷达上显示  另有20余艘战舰
We're reading some 20 other warships
正在逼近200英里无人区边界
closing in on the 200-mile line,
大部分将于48小时内到达
most should arrive within the next 48 hours.
准备开始测试样机
We're preparing to test the prototype.
注意监测
Keep those eyes on us.
索菲  我们应该帮他们吗
Sophie, should we be helping these people?
这你得自己决定
You have to decide that for yourself.
我可不趟这浑水
I won't be a part of it.
工程舱  我是指挥台
Engineering, conn.
准备启动珀尔修斯样机
Stand ready to engage the Perseus prototype.
是  长官
Aye-aye, Sir.
样机和潜艇所有重要系统紧密相连
The prototype is tied in to every major system on the sub.
它一旦失灵  潜艇就瘫痪了
It goes down, we're done.
恕我直言  长官
And with respect, sir,
我们应该在事情彻底失控前
we should be on the phone with D.C.
跟华府取得联系
sorting through this mess
协调解决方案
before it can't be sorted out.
全体注意  我是艇长
Attention, all hands. This is your captain.
目前有20余艘战舰正向我方逼近
There are some 20-plus warships descending on us.
昔日的战友现在却要来取我们的性命
These are our brothers in arms, sent now to kill us.
我们会找机会寻求谈判和解
There will be a time to talk,
但要先让他们知道我们的实力
but right now we show strength.
艇长讲话完毕
Captain out.
工程舱  我是指挥台  启动珀尔修斯系统
Engineering, conn. Engage the Perseus.
是  长官
Aye-aye, sir.
发动机系统依然正常
SSDG still online sir.
长官  潜艇从雷达上消失了
You just vanished off our screen, sir.
看来样机达到了预期效果
Looks like the prototype works.
他们还在追踪我们
They're hunting for us.
长官  边界附近有战舰在巡逻侦察
Sir, something patrolling low right outside the perimeter.
已确认对方身份
I.D. off those screws,
是伊利诺伊号
it's the Illinois.
它一直在边界线上来回穿梭
She's dipping back and forth across the line.
这是在试探
She's testing the fence.
若我们不给他们个教训
We don't make that line real to them,
它早晚会开进来灭了我们
sooner or later, she'll cross over to kill us.
全员进入战斗状态
Man battle stations.
伊利诺伊号上可有134名官兵呢
134 on board the Illinois, Sir.
舵手  调整航向  拦截伊利诺伊号
Helm, put us on intercept with the Illinois.
艇长  他们从声纳上消失了
Captain, they've just disappeared.
看来马库斯搞了个新玩意儿
Looks like Marcus has a new toy.
仔细监听
Listen carefully.
我艇正后方有鱼雷袭击
Launch transients dead astern!
规避机动  右满舵
Evasive maneuver, right full rudder.
启动紧急应对措施
Launch countermeasures now!
来不及了  鱼雷即将命中
Too late. Torpedo is homing.
撞击倒计时  五  四...
Impact in five, four...
三  二...
three, two...
无战斗部的鱼雷命中目标  长官
Disabled warhead's a hit, sir.
伊利诺斯号已调头
Illinois turning away.
它转动艇身
She's rolling over,
露出肚皮  向我们示弱了
showing us her belly.
但它还会伺机反咬一口
But she'll still bite if she gets the chance.
火控室  我是指挥台
Weapons, conn.
下一枚鱼雷准备  继续锁定目标
The next torpedo's armed. Keep your lock.
领航员  带我们返航
Nav...take us back.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
看见了吗
Do you see?
他们的行径可能会造成巨大灾难
The devastation could have been so much--
什么叫"可能"
"Could have"?
核弹落点距离海岸线有200英里远
That's gotta be maybe 200 miles off the coast.
比拉斯韦加斯到内华达州核试验基地还远
That's further than Vegas was to the Nevada test range.
在那个基地  可进行了数百次核试验
And they set off a couple hundred nukes there.
你的丈夫与所有追随马库斯・查普林的
Your husband and all the men and women
男女士兵都将死无葬身之地
following Marcus Chaplin will die
除非我们让这场闹剧赶紧结束
if we can't end this now.
现在山姆孤身在外
Now Sam is out there alone.
他很困惑
He's confused.
他可能一心只想
He probably wants, more than anything,
履行一名士兵应尽的义务
just to do the right thing.
那就帮帮他
Then help him.
上尉  报告军情
Sitrep, lieutenant.
监测站与巡逻哨的岗位都已安排好
We've manned stations and patrols,
但约有四分之一的艇员尚未到岗
but about a quarter of the crew aren't reporting for shifts.
科泰兹和布兰伦仍未归队
Cortez and Brannan are still missing
目前判定为擅离职守
and assumed awol.
科泰兹是第三次出海了  她不会擅离职守
Cortez is third tour. She's not awol.
我们得开始搜寻他们了
We gotta start looking for 'em.
长官  还有  水手长...
And, sir, the C.O.B.--
他被关押在小镇的监狱
he's under guard in what the town uses as a jail,
但始终不肯安分一点
and he is not making things any easier.
水手  开门
Sailor, open the gate.
瑞德  告诉她  这可不是在潜艇上
Tell her we ain't home, Red.
水手  你没听到我下达的直接命令吗
Sailor, I just gave you a direct order.
抱歉  长官  我手里没钥匙
Sorry, ma'am. I don't have the key.
要知道  格蕾丝
You know, Grace,
等你背上叛变与谋杀的罪名
when they find you guilty of mutiny, of murder,
到时牢狱之灾都不足为惧
it's not gonna be the jail cell that gets to you.
而在民众的欢呼声中
It's gonna be the sound of the people outside
被送上刑场
chanting for your death.
那才会把你逼疯
That's what's gonna drive you insane...
把锁砸烂
Break it down.
而且你那位海军上将老爹
And knowing that your admiral daddy
甚至都无法到你的坟前悼念你
is not gonna be able to visit your grave.
我说了  给我把锁砸烂
I said, break it down. Now.
上尉
Lieutenant.
开门
Open it up.
她根本就不配当军人
She should've never been wearing those stripes to begin with.
你却让她担任要职
But you put her there,
如今  她杀死了我一个水手
and she killed one of my men.
你还有什么需要吗  水手长
You have everything you need, C.O.B.?
我至今仍不敢相信
I never would've believed
我的朋友兼我的艇长
that my friend and commanding officer
在需要他担负起职责时  竟会心慈手软
would go soft when it came time to do his duty.
我很清楚我的职责
Oh, I know my duty.
是吗
Do you?
您的职责  就是接到发射命令就发射导弹
Your duty, sir, is to fire when you're told to fire.
您的职责  就是在祖国需要的时候
Your duty, sir, is to be the strong
毫不迟疑地强力出击
and unwavering fist of our nation.
为什么他们通过南极紧急通讯网下达命令
Why'd they send the orders through the Antarctic channel?
为什么他们朝我们开火
Why would they fire on us?
我只是个水手
I'm a sailor.
我没资格质疑这些
I don't have the luxury to ask.
是的  你没有
No, you don't,
所以你只是个水手长  而我才是艇长
which is why you're the C.O.B., and I'm the captain.
你是我的朋友  马库斯
You're my friend,  Marcus.
但我再不会承认你是我的艇长
But you're no longer the captain of my boat.
你还好意思穿着这身军装
That uniform you're still wearing?
你根本不配
That's borrowed glory.
我向来欣赏你的直言不讳  水手长
I've always appreciated your candor, C.O.B.
锁上门  水手
Lock it up, sailor.
你还好吗  上尉
You all right, lieutenant?
不是很好
Not really.
副艇长  请求您免除我的职务
X.O., you're gonna have to relieve me.
抱歉  我没有为官兵们树立一个好榜样
I'm sorry, but I'm not setting an example for the enlisted.
这不是他们的问题  是我的错
And it's not their fault, it's me.
我不知道自己究竟在这里做什么
I don't know who I am here.
那就去想明白
Well, then figure it out.
如果这里局面失控  我们就都会命丧黄泉
Look, we lose control here, we're all dead.
明白吗
You get that?
虽然我对此无能为力  但是我需要你
I can't fix this for you, but I do need you.
如果他们不相信你
They don't believe in you?
你就想办法让他们相信  从今天起
You make them, today.
这少于200英里了
That's closer than 200 miles.
飞机在15秒前穿过了无人区
Aircraft crossed the perimeter 15 seconds ago.
这家伙大得很  正在查明该机身份
Whatever it is, it's big. Working the ident.
打开导弹舱门  确保他们看到
Open hatches. Make sure the world can see it.
艾森豪威尔号上的F-18战斗机紧急起飞
"Eisenhower" is scrambling F-18s
前来拦截了  长官
to intercept, sir.
他们询问是否能跨越界线  以便转向
They're asking if they can cross our line to turn around.
查明该机身份  快
I.D. the bird, now.
等等
Wait.
台湾航空29-76号的飞行员  请转向
Pilot of Taiwan Air 29-76, turn around.
能听见吗
Do you hear me?
是一架波音747客机
It's a Passenger 747.
你觉得它离我们有多近
How close do you think it got?
说不准  也许有40英里
I don't know. Maybe 40 miles.
也许会有一队三角洲特种兵从飞机上伞降
A Delta force team could H.A.L.O. down from that plane,
降落在远处海面上  再划艇上岸
hit the water on the far side, paddle in.
六个小时后他们就能到这里
They could be here six hours after that.
他们不会浪费时间
They didn't waste any time.
我去阻击他们
I'll go.
我带一队人  想办法拦截他们
I'll take a team, try and cut 'em off.
山姆  如果真是三角洲部队...
Sam, if those are Deltas-
我知道
I know.
但如果他们轻敌
If they don't think we made 'em,
也许我们尚有胜算
maybe we get the upper hand.
你留在这儿  尽你所能
You stay here. You do what you can.
我去阻击他们
I'll go.
先展示实力
Show strength.
然后谈判
Then talk.
如果你的估计没错
If you're right,
你作战时还需要一名可信任的副官
you'll need a second out there you can trust.
我报名参加此次任务  长官
Volunteering for the mission, sir.
解酒药
Hangover cure.
都喝掉  吧台上还有一杯
Drink it. There's another at the bar.
我以为受过特种训练的人不会这么容易醉
I thought you special forces hot shots could handle your liquor.
你有船吗
Do you have a boat,
或其他能离开这岛的交通工具
some way off the island?
这里有很多船  但...
There are boats, but--
快逃离这个岛
Get yourself off this rock.
这里就要变成全球最大的靶子了
This whole place just became the biggest bull's-eye on the planet.
不是我笑你...
I'm sorry. It's just...
整个岛就是一座火山
This whole island is a volcano.
我们从小就听故事说
The stories we heard as kids,
海岛是用一枚巨大的鱼钩
they were about lands plucked from the bottom of the ocean
从海底钓起来的
by a giant fish hook
或是被愤怒的天神从天上扔下来的
or tossed down from the sky by angry gods.
你若对岛民说大难将至  人人死无全尸
Telling an islander they're going to die violently
他们会觉得自己的家乡一向如此
is just reminding us we're home.
淋浴收费10美元
Shower's $10.
我又没问
Didn't ask.
早晚会的
You will.
二位有何贵干
Gentlemen.
你也看到那架飞机了吧
You saw that plane?
没错
Yeah.
依我看  你们会遭遇到
I'd say you got yourself a bad case
七到十人的特种兵小队
of between seven and ten special forces.
基本肯定是三角洲部队
Almost certainly Delta.
你认为他们会先找我们还是先攻击潜艇
So you think they'll move for us or for the sub first?
艇长觉得你也许能帮助我们
My captain seems to think you might be of some help
想出一个应对方案
coming up with a plan here.
方案
A plan?
对  方案
Yeah, a plan.
不会有什么应对方案的
You're not coming up with a plan.
你们想出来的只会是个略复杂的自杀方式
What you're working on is just a really complicated suicide.
好吧  我实话跟你说吧
Okay, let me get one thing straight.
我只是应艇长的要求才来这儿的
I'm only here because my captain asked me to be.
要是我能做主  我宁愿一枪打爆自己的头
'Cause me? I'd rather beat my own brains out
也不要你的帮助
than have you help me with anything.
所以拜托你
So do me a favor.
继续泡在这里  争取越喝越傻
Why don't you stay here and drink yourself more stupid,
傻到无人能敌吧
if that's humanly possible?
谢谢帮忙
Thanks for your help.
还真挺解酒
That is good.
我们潜艇上的十三名水手
13 of our sailors are about
将在毫不了解敌方情况的状态下应战...
to face off with something they don't understand--
你知道完美的空降
Do you want to know what's the really great thing
最赞的一点是什么吗
about a perfect H.A.L.O. Jump?
在跳下去之前
It's that, before the jump,
你脑子里还想着家里的事
you're still stateside in your head--
房租  前女友  车贷等等
rent, ex-girlfriends, car payment, whatever.
但那自由落体的感觉会扫清一切烦恼
That free fall-- it cleans you right out.
在你拉开降落伞的那一刻
By the time you rip your chute,
所有的烦恼都消失了
everything's gone.
剩下的只有一股专注的力量
And what's left is a single-minded focus
驱使你完成任务
to accomplish the mission,
现在他们就带着这股力量来杀你和你的战友
which in this case would be killing you and your pals.
起码你可以告诉我们...
Look, the least you could do is tell--
如果要我选  我会站在他们那边
If I had to choose sides, I'd be out there with them.
所以
So this?
我只能说这么多了
This is the very least I can do.
根据我们的情报  会有特种兵进攻这座岛
So we think there might be some soldiers coming over the island.
既然你比任何人都熟悉这里
Since you know this place better than anyone,
我希望能得到你的帮助
I was hoping to get your help.
我觉得你还没搞清现在的形势吧
You know, I don't really think you get what's going on here, do you?
我很清楚
Oh, I do.
我为昨天死于非命的上百万人而惋惜
I understand that millions of people died yesterday.
但你会吗
But do you understand?
你不会
No, you can't.
因为你是一名士兵
Because you're a soldier.
军队告诉你  生命的逝去稀松平常
You're made to believe such things are normal.
你看电视报道了吗
Have you even looked at the TV?
你看到那些死者的脸了吗
Have you seen the faces--
我们潜艇可没有发射核弹
Hey, we're the ones that didn't fire.
明白吗
Do you get that?
你明白吗
Do you get it?
我和艇长没有向巴基斯坦发射核弹
Me and my captain, we didn't fire nukes at Pakistan.
你知道抗命不从的军人是什么下场吗
You know what the prize is for being such stand-up guys?
有人要杀我们  拦路者皆死
Men come to kill us and kill anyone that gets in their way.
我们现在唯一的胜算就是出奇制胜
And right now our only advantage is surprise.
所以我才来向你求助
And I'm here asking for your help.
副艇长  有电话找你
X.O., a call's come in for you.
我以为电话线路断了
I thought the phones were dead.
我们也以为  这电话你一定得接
So did we. You should take this.
喂
Hello.
亲爱的
Hey, babe.
我一直努力想再联系你  你还好吗
I've been trying to reach you again. Are you okay?
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
这里发生了很多疯狂的事
Things have been pretty crazy here.
你那边也一样吧
And I bet for you, too, right?
克里斯蒂  告诉我  你还好吗
Christine, talk to me. Are you okay?
山姆  他们会对你既往不咎...
Sam, they'll give you full amnesty...
你还有艇员们
you and the crew.
只要你交出潜艇
All you have to do is give them the sub.
并交出马库斯
And you have to give them Marcus.
他们就会让你回来找我
They're ready to let you come back to me.
山姆
Sam...
别信他们
Don't trust them.
无论他们说什么
Whatever they say to you,
无论我说什么  都别信
whatever I say to you, don't trust it!
只需记住我爱你  山姆  我爱你
Just know that I love you, Sam! I love you!
我料到他们会软硬兼施
We knew this wouldn't just be bullets.
还会挑你内心最脆弱的地方下手
They'll come at you where it hurts the most.
还好吗
You okay?
我们到达内陆后  建立埋伏圈
We'll get inland and we'll set up a kill zone.
也许他们就会被请君入瓮
Maybe they walk right into it.
运气差的话  被识破  死的是我们
Worst-case scenario, they get wise, they kill us all.
运气好的话
Best-case scenario,
我们用装尸袋把一队美国军人送回老家
we send a complement of American body bags home.
不管怎样都糟透了
Either way, this sucks.
94年格罗兹尼巷战的时候
The siege of Grozny in '94.
2000名俄国军人死于同胞之手
2,000 Russians died fighting their own.
结果是  将军辞职  其他人被审判
In the aftermath, generals resigned, others were tried.
但是那成千上万的兄弟手足
But for days, they fought,
在冰天雪地里互相残杀的日子里
brother killing brother by the thousands in the freezing cold.
如何能扪心自问这是为什么
And you have to ask yourself why.
有时候  敌人
Sometimes the enemy
仅仅是阻碍你回家的人
is just the man keeping you from getting home.
作为冷战的象征
A symbol of the cold war,
这艘俄亥俄级潜艇是18个同级别潜艇之一
the Ohio class submarine is one of 18 in its class
可以匿迹潜形  给敌人致命一击
designed to run silent and deep and then deliver deathly...
我出20美元赌24小时内这家伙准完蛋
20 bucks says we take this guy out within 24 hours.
一枚巡航导弹了事  谁要赌
Cruise missile. Who's in?
你个脑科大夫懂什么
Hey, brain surgeon.
科罗拉多号5分钟之内
The "Colorado" can launch
就可以发射剩余17枚核弹
its remaining 17 nukes in under five minutes.
你说的巡航导弹慢的要死
Your cruise missile is a slow weapon.
大概得用20分钟才能击中目标
Takes maybe 20 minutes.
洲际导弹快一点  但是得先上太空再降下来
I.C.B.M.'s faster, but you gotta launch it up and down.
这也要花时间
That takes time.
还不能确保彻底解决了那潜艇
And you better be 100% sure you kill her,
因为查普林现在占领了北约雷达站
'cause Chaplin's got eyes now.
一旦科罗拉多号的三叉戟导弹升空
And once the "Colorado's" tridents are airborne,
世界上没有任何东西能够阻止它们
there is not a thing in this world that stops them
因为20年前有人阻止了我爸
'cause somebody kept my daddy
实行星球大战计划
from building star wars 20 years ago.
告诉我  你到底要怎么把那艘潜艇消灭掉
So tell me exactly how you would take out that submarine?
莱纳斯
Linus.
我最爱的国防部卧底
What is my favorite deep cover mole
今晚喝点什么
in the defense department drinking this evening?
-看在上帝的份上  凯莉  -放轻松
- For God's sake, Kylie. - Oh, relax.
今天我就算现场给你跳个大腿舞
I could give you a lap dance right here
也没人会注意到的
and no one would notice today.
我会的
I would.
有什么消息吗
So what's your news?
你那个珀尔修斯样机
Your Perseus prototype?
查普林今天早上亲自试用了
Chaplin went ahead and tested it this morning, on his own.
科罗拉多号立即从所有雷达屏幕上消失了
The "Colorado" dropped right off everyone's screens.
凯莉  样机奏效了
Kylie, it works.
服务生  上香槟
Waiter, champagne.
现在就上  我们要庆祝
Right away. We're celebrating.
不  不  你不明白
No, no, no, no. You don't understand.
他们会把你的这项专利抢走的
They will take it away from you.
以爱国行为为由  或是以国家安全为由
They will go patriot act, they will go national security,
永远地从你手里夺走它
and they will take it away from you.
而你毫无办法
And there's nothing you can do about it.
查普林说  曾试图击沉科罗拉多号的
Chaplin said it was actually the "Illinois"
是伊利诺伊号
that tried to sink the "Colorado."
查普林疯了
Chaplin's insane.
是吗  24小时前  你会说
Really? 24 hours ago, you would've said
他是忠贞爱国  道德高尚的典范
he was the paragon of virtue and patriotism.
现在有人命令伊利诺伊号开火
Now someone ordered the "Illinois" to fire.
这命令一定记载在案  如果你说的对
Somewhere that was recorded, and if you're right
他们要夺走我的技术发明专利
and they're trying to take my tech,
那么那条命令就是我的免罪金牌
then that order is my get-out-of-jail-free card.
我要你为我拿到它
I need you to get that for me.
你听我说话了吗
Are you not hearing me?
我不能再帮你了
I can't help you anymore.
你单身派对上
What was the name
那个咖啡色头发的女人叫什么来着
of that brunette at your bachelor party?
太性感了
God, she was hot.
性感到让我想左右开弓
Like, make-me-want-to-switch-hit hot,
是她吗
wasn't she?
叫凯洛的女孩
Was it Carole?
啊不是  那是你妻子的名字
Oh, no. No, no. That's your wife's name.
我还以为我们是朋友
I thought we were friends.
我们是朋友啊
We are friends.
但是你是我付过很多钱的朋友
But you're a friend I pay a lot of money to.
莱纳斯  去把那条命令找来给我
Linus, go find me that order.
再见  爸爸
Good-bye, dad.
我敢说你并没想到会有这样的周末
I bet this isn't how you saw your weekend going.
我的周末并没有你想象的那么无聊
My weekends are not as boring as you imagine.
好吧  是我没想到我的周末会这样
Yeah. Well, it isn't how I saw mine.
我当时在场
I was there.
如果你当时不杀掉那个人  我们都死定了
If you hadn't killed that man, we'd all be dead.
你别无选择
You didn't have a choice.
现在也无关紧要了  不是吗
It doesn't matter now, does it?
谢帕德杀死了我们其中的一员
Shepard killed one of us.
有时在战场上
Sometimes in battle,
这种事情总能合理的存在
these things have a way of working themselves out.
抱歉  凯姆  上面才更需要你
Sorry, Cam, you're too important up there.
恕我冒犯  长官
With all due respect, sir.
如果这行动不成功  上面也保不住
If this doesn't work, there will be no "up there."
整装待发了  长官
Full complement ready to go, sir.
很好
Good.
出去要小心  别晒伤了
Careful out there. Don't get a sunburn.
你用不着这个  这个还有这
You don't need this or this or this.
还没等你
This will get you shot
摘下这玩意  人家就把你崩了
while you're busy trying to unstrap it.
你倒是把装具带穿对了
You got your rig strapped right.
但这不代表你准备好迎接那里的一切
Doesn't mean you're ready for what's out there.
有一条他们要到这里的必经之路
There is a place they will have to go through to get here.
我来指给你
I'll show you where.
可以走了
That's all.
协助和鼓动恐怖组织
Aiding and abetting a terrorist enterprise,
协助和鼓动恐怖份子
aiding and abetting known terrorists,
煽动叛乱罪  叛国罪
sedition, treason,
协助和鼓动攻击祖国
aiding and abetting an attack on the homeland--
这可不只关系到你丈夫
And this isn't just your husband.
刚才一通闹  现在连你自己也搭进去了
After that stunt, this is now you as well.
看见中指了吗
Read between the lines.
你以为你了解他
You think you know him?
其实不然
You don't.
你了解的不过是单纯的表面
You just know the easy parts,
他故意秀给你看的部分
the parts he wanted you to see.
我比任何人都了解山姆
I know Sam better than anyone.
你确定
You sure?
我不会谈这个的
I'm not gonna talk about that.
我说了不想谈这个
I told you I'm not gonna talk about it
所以我不会谈的
so we're not talking about it.
这是什么
What is this?
你们18个人被俘
There were 18 of you taken prisoner.
这是什么时候录的  什么东西
When was this taken? What is this?
你手下有7人未能生还
Seven men under your command didn't survive.
到底发生了什么
What the hell is going on?
你不会没有压力的
That has to weigh on you.
我很惊讶你能来
I was surprised you showed.
我也是
So am I.
你要对付的这些人
These men you're ready to fight,
他们也是你的同胞
they might as well be your brothers.
好了  我知道
Hey, you know, I get it.
你讨厌杀戮  厌恶战争
You don't like killing, you don't like war,
希望大家都相安无事
you want us to all just get along.
是个人都这么想
That's what anybody thinks
因为他们没被逼得走投无路
that's never had their back up against a wall.
你以为我是谁
Who do you think I am?
我见识了你们的战争所带来的
I've seen what your wars do.
而且这些战争都是可以避免的
And there's always some other way.
对  我以前也是这么想的
Yeah, I used to think that, too.
我错了
I was wrong.
是什么让你改变了看法
What happened to change your mind?
谢谢你给我们指路
Thank you for showing us this spot.
你该走了
You should go now.
能帮我检查一下武器吗
Can you check my weapon for me?
我想确保它就绪了
I want to make sure it's ready.
谢谢长官
Thank you, ma'am.
我心里更踏实了
I feel much safer now.
你就这么让他们自己去了
You just let them go off alone.
我管不着
It's not my business.
在圣玛丽娜这座岛上
Here on sainte marina,
有时因为家庭离异
sometimes a family breaks apart--
婚姻恶化  欠债不还
a marriage goes bad, a debt goes unpaid,
会有一些小争端
a small war starts.
别担心  我不会浪费这香料的
Don't worry. I'm not gonna break out the patchouli.
在这里  这些事情发生的时候
But here when this happens,
我们要选出一个人  给他纹饰
a man is selected and marked
任命他来解决争端
to make the peace.
这纹饰是一项荣耀
The marks are an honor.
你担当得起来吗
Do you deserve them?
他们凌晨三四点的时候来
It would be 3:00 or 4:00 in the morning when they would come.
把我们拖出牢房
They'd drag us out of our cells.
在院子里执行枪决
They would march us out into the yard.
是一起吗
Together?
不  一个一个来
Mnh-mnh. Alone.
有张桌子  一支枪一颗子弹
There would be a table and gun. One bullet.
他们会让你自己填弹
They'd make you load the gun.
他们转一下弹轮把枪口指向你
They'd spin the chamber and put the gun to your head.
咔
Click.
那扣扳机的声音
That sound...
你的丈夫曾在
Your husband was a captive
北朝鲜人民共和国
of the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea
做过17天俘虏
for over 17 days.
不  那不可能
No, that's not possible.
马库斯・查普林采取了非常规手段
Marcus Chaplin went off the reservation
使他得以被释放
to force his release.
为此还赌上了自己的前途
Put his career on the line.
山姆告诉你那是一次常规部署吗
Sam just tell you that was a regular deployment?
男人为什么要对自己的妻子撒谎呢
Why does a man lie to his wife?
我不知道
I don't know.
马库斯指使他骗了你
Well, Marcus had him lying to you,
骗了所有人
to everyone.
如果他能做出这种事
And if he's capable of that,
天知道马库斯还能怂恿他做出什么别的事
what else could Marcus get him to do?
你以为你丈夫就骗过你这一回吗
You think that's the only lie your husband ever told you?
我不知道  好了吧
I don't know, okay?
你为什么不告诉我  因为我真的不知道
Why don't you tell me? Because I don't know what this is.
我失去了7名部下  你问我他们的名字
I lost seven of my men. You want their names?
听着  事情都过去了  我都忘了
Look, it happened. I'm over it.
能换个话题吗
Could we move on, please?
这就是你的丈夫
That's your husband...
正在学着撒谎
Learning to lie.
国防部副部长科利
Deputy Secretary of Defense Curry,
很高兴再次与你通话
it's good to talk to you again.
现在是部长了  艇长
It's Secretary now, Captain.
至少过去的24小时对某些人来说是好事
Well, I'm glad the last 24 hours has been good to someone.
听着  我们这里有很多人被吓坏了
You know, we have a lot of frightened people here.
你们派出了一支三角洲小队进入我的岛屿
You have a team of Delta on my island.
我希望他们离开  马上
I want them gone. Now.
我们需要面对16亿愤怒的穆斯林
We got about 1.6 billion Muslims deeply pissed at us.
我们正试图使事态得到缓解
We're trying to de-escalate this situation,
而非步步升级
not make it worse.
你的岛上没有三角特遣队  完毕
There are no Delta on your island. Over.
谁会射击
So who can shoot?
我是说真的能射中目标
I mean actually hit something.
我可以吧
I suppose I can.
好的
Okay.
算了  我大概也行
Ah, hell. Guess I can, too.
好的
Good.
战斗打响后  他们会向后撤
When this starts, they're either gonna fall back
或者向掩体移动
or try to make it to cover.
你们要阻止他们
You do not let them.
懂了吗
You got it?
很好
Good.
副艇长  我们已经就位
X.O., we're all set up here.
你认为还有多长时间
How long do you think we have?
一小时左右  但随时做好准备
Probably an hour or more, but be ready.
这感觉一定很怪吧  杀自己人
Must feel weird, killing one of your own,
尤其还是在他们毫不知情的情况下
especially like this, without them knowing it's coming.
听着  霍克斯
Hey, Hawkes,
我们现在需要每一支枪
we're gonna need every gun we have.
所以如果你想打黑枪杀了我
So if you're gonna shoot me in the back,
最好等打完仗再说
maybe you could wait until we're done here.
整个区域都在火力范围内
We've got the whole thing ranged.
如果他们来  我们能够应付
If they come, we'll take 'em.
很好
Good.
副艇长
X.O...
上尉  有朝一日你会结婚吧
You gonna get married someday, lieutenant?
那些人就要来了
'cause these men are coming,
不是他们死  就是你死
and only one of you gets to have a future.
我还挺想参加你的婚礼呢
I plan on being at that wedding.
我会确保你收到请柬  长官
I'll make sure and invite you, sir.
隐蔽  迅速隐蔽
Go, quick. Go.
艇长  他们来了
Captain, they're here.
如果我们还想留条后路  现在是最后的机会
If we're gonna find another way out of this, it's gotta be now.
山姆  现在你得靠自己
You're on your own for now, Sam.
我还帮不上你
I can't help you yet.
科利部长
Secretary Curry,
再告诉我一遍  你们没派部队上我的岛
tell me again how you have nothing on my island.
那我又如何能想象出我的副艇长正准备
Tell me how I'm imaging my X.O. is going up against
和一只武装小队交火
an armed contingent.
如果我觉得你是在骗我  那就别无选择
And if I think you're lying to me, then I'm gonna have to
只能让老天决定事态发展了
leave this in the hands of a higher power.
打扰一下  先生
Excuse me, sir.
你想让我说什么  马库斯
Wh-what do you want me to say, Marcus?
是  我们派了特遣队  不  我们没有
Yes, we sent Delta? No, we didn't send Delta?
现在我说什么都没用了吧
Does it really matter what I say?
不要射击
Hold your fire.
长官
Sir?
我已瞄准目标
I have the shot.
长官
Sir?
我要出来对话  我没带武器
I'm coming out to talk! I am unarmed!
重复一遍  我没带武器  我要出来对话
I repeat, I am unarmed! I'm coming out to talk!
不要开枪
Do not fire!
长官  你在干什么
Sir... what are you doing?
我们已从两翼将你们包围
We got you ranged from both sides.
你们处于火力范围内
You are in a kill zone.
我只想和你们谈谈
I just want to talk.
我们都是美国人  你们之中肯定有人
We are all Americans. At least some of you
会怀疑你们到底来这里干什么
gotta be wondering what you're doing here.
我更不知道我来这儿干吗
Hell, I don't even know what I'm doing here.
又出现了
There it is again.
他们正通过水下
They're essentially beaming it through the water
从基地向分队发射信号
from their base to the team
然后利用超低频信道
and then using an ultra-low frequency.
谁在通过水下发射信号
Who is beaming it through the water?
他们
They are.
我只知道  我们今天不必造成任何牺牲
All I know is, none of us has to die today.
山姆  他们不是三角洲部队的
Sam, they're not Deltas.
他们是俄罗斯特战队的
They're Russian Spetsnaz.
山姆  收到吗
Sam, do you read?
我靠
Ah, hell.
三个撤到后面了  前面还有两个
Three went back! Two forward!
我们有两个人...
We got two but--
格蕾丝  敌军正要迂回
Grace, they flanked us
试图登上你们所在的山坡
to the top of the hill you're on.
你们最好先往上走
You gotta get up there.
我们已经在路上了
We're already on our way.
但现在被敌人压制  山姆
But we're pinned down, Sam.
没法上山
There is no way up.
我们这样下去没活路的  上尉
We're not gonna survive like this, lieutenant.
我命令你去占领那个位置
I need you to take that position out.
听到吗
Do you hear me?
霍克斯
Hawkes.
霍克斯  需要掩护
Hawkes, we need cover.
不要
No!
声音关小  水手
Turn that down, sailor.
长官
Sir?
你听到了  关小音量
You heard me. Turn it down.
马库斯・查普林
Marcus Chaplin.
什么风把您吹来了
This is an unexpected honor.
维克多  你有一支特战队在我岛上
Viktor, you have a team of Spetsnaz on my island,
从台湾的747客机上跳伞后登陆
dropped off the back of a taiwanese 747.
并从我禁区外50英里的乌克兰货船上
You're running support off a Ukrainian container ship
向其提供指挥支援
50 miles beyond my perimeter.
可能这不是你的行动  维克多
And it might not be your mission, Viktor.
但克里姆林宫里有人正企图得到我的潜艇
But someone in the Kremlin is making a play for my submarine.
没人想要发动攻击
No one would want to attack.
我会下令击沉那艘船的  维克多
I'll sink the ship, Viktor.
然后对准塞瓦斯托波尔基地
And then I'll target the Sevastopol base
也就是你两个儿子服役的基地
where your two sons are stationed
将那里夷为平地
and I'll turn it to glass.
格蕾丝  立刻告诉我
Grace, I need to know right now,
你能否攻下那个高地
can you take care of that position or not?!
抱歉  山姆
I'm sorry, Sam.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
俄方打出信号  希望进行谈判
Russians are signaling, they want to talk.
给我接通科利的电话
Get Curry back on the line.
让他听听这一切  但要把这混蛋搁静音
Let him hear everything, but mute that son of a bitch.
马库斯
Marcus,
这边很多人已经睡着了
many people are asleep here.
事情不好办
It's not easy.
没关系  维克多
That's okay, Viktor.
我随时奉陪
I've got all the time in the world.
无线电坏了  所有人听好
Radio's dead. Everybody listen up.
我一下令  你们就去卡车那里
On my go, you're gonna get to the truck
然后离开这儿
and get the hell out of here.
如有人倒下  其他人继续前进
One of you guys go down, you just keep moving.
听我口令
On my go.
瑞德  瑞德
Red. Red.
我们准备行动  听到了吗
We're gonna do this. Do you hear me?
才23米不到  明白吗
It's not more than 25 yards. Do you understand me?
我做不到  我做不到
I can't. I can't.
抱歉  我做不到
I'm sorry. I can't.
维克多  那孩子叫什么名字
Viktor, what is that kid's name...
就那天你船上的那个
on your boat back in the day?
在冰下吓坏了的那个
The one who got so freaked out under the ice.
我们中断冷战一个小时
You and I called off the cold war for an hour
让你救他上来
so you could get him topside.
这叫信任
That's called trust.
是尼古拉
Ah, Nikolai.
海军上将的儿子
Admiral's son.
马库斯
Marcus,
这话就我们两个老兵间说说
just between two old warriors,
看在我们都有人出生入死的份上
let's say for argument's sake we had our people there.
或许你可以交出潜艇
Maybe you could surrender your submarine.
这样也许就不会有任何伤亡了
Maybe then nobody would have to be hurt.
维克多  我是国防部部长科利
Viktor! This is Secretary of Defense Curry.
你已经开始行动  这是我们内部的冲突
You put a play in motion? This is our conflict.
除非你想引发第三次世界大战
Unless you want to start World War III,
立即撤回这些人
you pull those men back now.
我还以为你是个守信用的人
And I thought you were a man of your word.
我并没有给你任何承诺  维克多
I didn't give you my word, Viktor.
但我会让你和国防部部长科利
But I'll let you work out the ramifications
去解决窃取美国潜艇的问题
of trying to steal a U.S. Sub with SecDef Curry.
我算了一下
I did the math.
我们谈恋爱两年  结婚一年
We dated two years. Married one.
但我们真正在一起的时间只有124天
Yet, we have actually only spent 124 days together.
你算过吗
You did the math?
你是谁  山姆・肯德尔
Who are you, Sam Kendal?
我们会好好的
We're gonna be okay.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我只想要你
I just want you.
副艇长
X.O.
X.O.!
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this.
快走  走
Go, go, go, go!
不能死  今天不能死
Don't die. Not today.
不能死
Don't die.
副艇长  听到请回答
X.O., are you there?
副艇长
X.O.
剩余的俄国人都已撤退
Remaining Russians have bugged out.
我们五人阵亡  格蕾丝负伤
We lost five. Grace is wounded.
但伤得不重
She'll be okay.
我们俘获两人  正在回来的路上
We have two prisoners. We're coming home.
很可能是浪费时间
Probably a waste of time.
你真觉得你能打破这份信仰吗
You really think you can break that kind of devotion?
她有信念  坠入了爱河
Well, she's got faith. She's in love.
但这些都是可矫正的
But both those things are curable.
那就矫正她
Then cure her.
我已经见到她了
Okay, I'm here with her now.
克里斯蒂
Christine...
我是保罗・威尔斯
My name is Paul Wells.
我们一直在找你
We've been trying to find you.
你还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
你是山姆的朋友
You're Sam's friend.
是的  从大学开始
Yes. Yes, from college.
我是一名律师
Look, I'm a lawyer, okay?
政府已经
The government has...
彻底越权了
radically exceeded its authority here.
一切到此为止
But that all stops now.
来吧
Come on.
我带你回家
Let me take you home.
好的  把他们关起来
All right, lock 'em up.
天哪  别这样
Oh, hell, no.
他们杀了我们五个弟兄  五个
They killed five of us, man. Yeah, five.
我们的五个朋友  五个战友
Five of our friends, five of our people.
这些人已经没用了
These guys get wasted.
立刻放下你的武器
Put your weapon down right now!
瑞德  这是命令  放下武器
Red, that is an order! Put it down!
什么命令
An order?
我们是在一个破岛上  不是在潜艇里
We're on a damn island, not a sub.
请原谅
So excuse me
我已经不知道命令意味着什么了
If I'm not even sure what an order means anymore!
我知道这并不是你们想要的
I know you didn't ask for this.
我知道你们都很害怕
I know you're all scared.
你们想知道我们到底在这里做什么
And you're wondering what we're doing here
还有你们怎么才能回家
and how you're gonna get back home.
现在你们失去了朋友
And now you've lost friends.
心中充满着杀戮欲
And you have bloodlust in your hearts.
也许复仇能带给你一丝满足
Vengeance might give you some satisfaction,
但我要提醒你们  记得自己的身份
but let me remind you who you are.
你们是俄亥俄级弹道导弹潜艇
You are the American crew
科罗拉多号上的美国军人
of the Ohio class ballistic missile submarine "Colorado."
你的领口上标注着你的军衔
Your rank is what it says on your collar.
你们懂得要向长官敬礼
You salute the sailor above you...
也希望下属能对你如此
And you expect the same of the one below.
你最终的职责就是当我说"跳"时
And your final duty is to say "How high?"
你问"要跳多高"
when I say "Jump."
明白了吗
Are we clear?
-是的  长官  -是的  长官
- Yes, sir. - Yes, sir.
明白了吗
Are we clear?!
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
作为美国人
Now as Americans,
对战俘的处理无需争议
there's no debate about the fate of our P.O.W.S.
谢帕德上尉
Lieutenant shepard,
关押囚犯
secure the prisoners.
我知道你干了什么
I know what you did.
再试一次  我仍会活着回来
Try it again. I'll still be here.
马库斯
Marcus!
告诉他们我们还是兄弟时你对我说过的话
Tell them what you told me when we were still pals.
告诉他们你的儿子两周前在阿富汗
Tell them that your son got killed by friendly fire
被友军误杀
two weeks ago in Afghanistan.
说啊
Go on.
这些年轻人已经跟着你下了地狱
These young people have followed you into a hell.
永世不得超生
They'll never be able to climb back out of.
为了什么
For what?
就是因为你想报复这个
Because you wanted payback on the country
害死了你儿子国家
that took your son away from you?!
把真相告诉他们  马库斯
Tell 'em the truth, Marcus!
告诉他们到底是为何而战
Tell them what they're really fighting for!
你了解我  乔
You know me, Joe.
你们所有人
All of you...
都了解我
You know me.
再来一杯给我
One more for me.
一杯给这位脸蛋受伤的女士
One more for the lady with the, uh, face.
你觉得我是来感谢你吗
You think I came to thank you?
我们损失了六个人
We lost six people.
我觉得也许你想知道他们的名字
I thought you might want to know their names.
在我身边牺牲的战友  比这要多得多
I got my own list a lot longer than that.
终有一天  你得搞清楚
One of these days, you're gonna have to decide
自己到底信仰什么
what you believe in.
看见战友倒下是什么感觉
What did it feel like?
脑子里不停地嗡嗡作响吧
It's a hell of a buzz, isn't it?
你可能没意识到  但你今天的确很了不起
You may not know it, but you did something today.
你是和平卫士
Peace...maker.
塔妮  你以为我是为和平而战吗
You think I made the peace, Tani?
我只不过是好久没杀人了
I just ran out of people to kill.
今天国会刮起了一阵
The so-called "Pledge of allegiance"
对祖国宣誓效忠的风潮
swept through congress today
国会议员们纷纷表示愿意支持总统
as legislators lined up in support of the president,
尽管白宫此次发动的
even as international condemnation mounts
所谓"箭在弦上不得不发"的攻击行为
for the attack the white house has called
引发了国际舆论的强烈谴责
"Necessary and unavoidable."
终于来了
Oh, finally.
我已经办妥了  你进行得如何
I did my part. How about...
他们说这是对所吃食物的过敏反应
They said it was an allergic reaction to something he ate.
但当他被送到医院的时候
But by the time they got to him,
大脑已经缺氧十分钟了
his brain had been without oxygen for ten minutes.
这怎么可能是意外呢
So how could that be an accident?
是你把他害成这样的
It's your fault, isn't it?
你笑着向他承诺能挣一笔大钱
You smiled and promised him so much money.
知道吗  他曾对我说  "你真该见见她
You know, he used to say, "You should see her.
她似乎所向披靡"
It's like nothing can touch her."
说的没错  你的确毫发未伤
It's true, isn't it? Nothing touches you.
我祝你孤身终老
I hope you die alone.
我派了两支搜救小组去找布兰伦和科泰兹
We've got two teams looking for Brannan and Cortez.
如果他们还活着  一定能把他们带回来
If they're out there to be found, we'll find them.
我记得那是7月出海执行任务
I think it was July deployment.
你马上就要来艇上进行总体验收了
You're due any minute for general inspection,
可当时的情况...实在是糟糕透顶
and, man...it's not good.
凯姆安装的新型声呐系统根本无法使用
Cam's got some new sonar display that's not even working.
而炊事员在食堂不小心弄炸了
The cook, he's got, like, 200 cans of stew
200个炖菜罐头  那浓郁的味道
that exploded in the mess and the smell...
遍布整个潜艇
the smell is everywhere.
忽然之间  艇长来了  你出现了
And here comes the captain. Here you come.
大家都惊慌不已
Everybody's freaking out
害怕这无比混乱的景象会让你大发雷霆
because the place is a complete disaster.
然而  在接下来的两小时中
Except instead, for two hours,
你一直微笑着  轻拍着大家的后背
you're all smiles and back slaps.
还给我们讲述了你当年在洛杉矶级
You told some story about fishing off the back
攻击型核潜艇顶上钓鱼的事
of an L.A. Class attack sub.
终于  出海的时刻到了
Finally, it's time to put to sea.
我去找克里斯蒂  向她告别
I find Christine and I say good-bye.
是啊  你当时刚刚新婚...
Yeah, you'd been married...
才3个礼拜吧
three weeks?
我登上舰桥  与你并肩而立
I join you on the bridge,
看到你脸上洋溢着傻憨憨的笑容
and you got this big dumb smile plastered all over your face--
毫无艇长的威严
totally undignified.
杰弗里也在码头上
And Jeffrey's there on the pier.
那是他第一次从国外服役归来
He's home from his first tour.
他来目送自己的父亲出海
He's there to watch his old man pull out to sea.
长官  把手给我
Give me your dumb hand, sir.
你所承受的苦痛  是我无法想象的
I can't imagine what you're going through.
但我是你的朋友
But I am your friend.
我了解你
And I know who you are.
我相信你
And I trust you.
他们会找准你心中最深切的痛楚
They find what hurts you the most
想借此把你彻底打垮
and they try to break you with it.
但他们永远不会得逞
But that's where they miss.
因为最深的痛楚  正是激励我们的力量
What hurts us the most, that's our strength.
正是支撑我们抗争到底的勇气
That's what gets us through.
我特别激动
I'm excited.
你也是军人  一定理解我的心情
And I know you of all people, you get that.
等我到了那边  再跟你联系
I'll tell you stories on the other side.
我爱你  老爸
I love you, dad.
爸爸
Hi, dad.
我希望你永远不用看到这录像
I hope you never have to watch this.
真希望以前能让你有机会更好地了解我
I wish that I had let you know me better.
因为那样你就能懂得我现在有多么恐惧
If I had, then you would know how scared I am.
但你也知道我绝不会就此退缩
But you would also know that I'm not gonna run from this.
我不是那种人
That's not who I am.
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, dad.
你的意思是
You've indicated that
你不会向你的妻子倾诉这些
you're not going to tell your wife about this.
这是为什么
Why is that?
因为在那些黑暗的日子里
The whole time I was there,
克里斯蒂是支撑我活下去的唯一动力
Christine's what kept me alive.
你想知道我为何不把那些事告诉她
You want to know why I'm not gonna tell my wife?
因为在我的世界里  她是唯一的美好
'Cause she's the one good thing I got left in this world.
也许正是因为这样  我就得继续保密
Maybe this way, I get to keep that.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：笨熊猫  Silmar  十九罗汉  我不是青椒  hammer_tank  小黎  君莫舞
时间轴：贝壳  爱你科  小仓鼠Eli    校对：宁馨儿  米苏  插线
后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
《破釜沉舟》前情提要
自己人居然想击沉我们
Our own people tried to sink us?
违抗军令  你说还会是什么下场
What do you think happens when you ignore orders?
这不是违抗军令  只是请求解释
We didn't ignore anything. We questioned.
老海军中流行这么一句话
Old navy saying--
"愚人必自食恶果"
"Stupid will be punished."
我们接管了圣玛丽娜岛上的
we have commandeered the N.A.T.O.
北约预警监测站
early warning station on the island of Sainte Marina.
这个监测站和外面停靠的那艘潜艇
This station, and that sub parked outside--
现在起都归我管
they all belong to me now.
另有20余艘战舰正在逼近
We're reading some 20 other warships closing in
200英里无人区边界
on the 200 mile line.
大部分将于48小时内到达
Most should arrive within the next 48 hours.
谢帕德上将  你我心知肚明
Admiral Shepard, we both know
潜艇根本不是巴基斯坦人击沉的
the Pakistanis didn't sink her.
-爸  是我  -我以为你死了
- Dad, it's me. - I thought I'd lost you.
你们到底干了些什么
What the hell did you just do?
塔妮  你以为我是为和平而战吗
You think I made the peace, Tani?
我只不过是好久没杀人了
I just ran out of people to kill.
这是我的岛
This is my island.
想让我同意你们留下
If I allow your presence,
可是有条件的
it comes with certain terms and conditions.
科泰兹和布兰伦仍未归队
Cortez and Brannan are still missing and assumed awol.
科泰兹是第三次出海了  她不会擅离职守
Cortez is third tour. She's not awol.
我们得开始搜寻他们了
We gotta start looking for 'em.
马库斯  告诉他们
Marcus, tell them
你的儿子两周前在阿富汗
that your son got killed by friendly fire
被友军误杀
two weeks ago in Afghanistan.
因为最深的痛楚  正是激励我们的力量
What hurts us the most-- that's our strength.
正是支撑我们抗争到底的勇气
That's what gets us through.
退后
Back away!
说你呢  放手  退后  都退后
Hey, got off! Back away! Back away!
-他偷我们东西  -什么
- He stole from us! - What?!
就是他  他偷我们东西
Right there-- he stole from us!
谁偷你东西  帕克
Who stole from you? Parker!
-就是根破香蕉罢了  -你居然偷他们东西
- It was a banana, for god sake! - You stole from these people?!
-就是根香蕉  -马上给他一美元
- It was a banana. - Give him a dollar right now.
下不为例  听明白了吗
This will not happen again! Do you understand me?
我饿了  我想要香蕉我就拿
I'm hungry! If I want a banana, I'll take it!
关你4个小时禁闭给我好好反省
What you'll take is two rotations of E.M.I.
去潜艇上报道  剩下的人
Report to the boat. The rest of you
继续寻找失踪的人
continue searching for our missing people!
我们根本就不应该在这
We shouldn't even be here!
去潜艇上报道  这是命令  必须服从
Report to the boat. I gave you an order. Follow it.
那把我关禁闭吧  没了我们他们就撑不下去了
So throw me in the brig. They can't do this without us.
问问水手长  没有我们他们就得投降
Ask the C.O.B. without us, they have to surrender,
我们就能回家了
and we all go home.
给
Here.
军装给你  拿好
Here's your uniform. Take it.
是要给我们跳钢管舞吗  帕克
You gonna give us a pole dance now, Parker?
不错
Very nice.
把他关禁闭
Put him in the brig.
霍夫曼  把他关禁闭
Hoffman, put him in the brig.
立刻
Right now.
别碰我
Get off me!
怎么着
What?
最后一次有人看见雷德曼是昨天中午
Last anyone saw Redman was mid-rats yesterday.
整个岛都搜遍了
And we've scoured the island--
依然没有科泰兹和布兰伦的踪影
Still no sign of Cortez or Brannan, either.
这不像是擅离职守
This doesn't feel like an AWOL. situation.
本来就不是
That's because it's not.
我是科罗拉多号的马库斯艇长
This is Captain Marcus Chaplin of the U.S.S. Colorado.
我在跟谁对话
To whom am I speaking?
白宫高级顾问阿曼达・斯昭
White House Senior Adviser Amanda Straugh.
我被任命为对你们的谈判专员
I've been named as your negotiator.
祝贺你  斯昭女士
Congratulations, Miss Straugh.
我很钦佩你在科索沃的作为
I admired your work in Kosovo.
查普林先生  傍晚你们就将被完全封锁
Mr. Chaplin, the blockade is set to close by nightfall.
我想你对随之而来的后果心知肚明
I think you understand the ramifications of this,
你的艇员也应该清楚
as does your crew.
除非无条件投降
Unless you surrender unconditionally,
否则你们将失去与外界的一切联系
you will be effectively cut off from the world.
你上司打算杀了我艇上的所有人
Your boss tried to kill every man and woman on my boat,
现在你又要求我无条件投降
and now you expect unconditional surrender.
有点过分了吧
That's a bit of a reach, isn't it,
想想仍在我手上的17枚三叉戟核弹
considering the 17 tridents still in my control?
想想你儿子杰弗里
Think of your son Jeffrey.
我儿子已经死了
My son is dead.
海军希望能给他举办正式的葬礼
And the marines hoped to give him a proper funeral.
查普林先生  你一日不降
Mr. Chaplin, there will be no burial for your son
你儿子就一日不会有葬礼
until you surrender.
他的尸体将无限期地
His remains will rest in a Navy morgue
停放在海军停尸房
until that time-- indefinitely.
为了你的艇员  为了你的儿子
For your crew, for your son,
请做出正确的决定
do what's right.
副艇长  有什么事吗
What's on your mind, X.O.?
我们的艇员出了点问题
We got a problem with the crew.
别告诉我你俩也被关起来了
Don't tell me you're both under arrest, too.
地方有点不够用了
We're getting full up here.
听说布兰伦和科泰兹的事了吧
Heard about Brannan and Cortez?
还有雷德曼
And Redman.
都失踪了
All missing.
艇员们以为他们擅离职守了
Crew thinks they're AWOL.
他们不是擅离职守
They're not AWOL.
我们终于有意见一致的时候了  小子
For once, you and me agree, junior.
你想加入寻找他们的队伍吗
You want to be a part of the effort to find them?
你以为我不知道出了什么事吗
You don't think I know what's going on?
你正渐渐失势
You're losing control.
我在这儿关着更有影响力
I'm more powerful in here than out.
没错  这笼子成了你的造反司令部了
Yeah, I see you've found yourself a bully pulpit.
这岛也成了你威胁祖国
And you found a way to spite your country
以泄丧子之愤的泄愤之地
for Jeffrey's death.
你我愿望相同  送我上军事法庭
You and I want the same thing-- me in front of a court-martial,
在那里我们之中一人将被证明是正确的
where one of us will be proven right.
你可以就这么作壁上观
Meanwhile, here you sit, watching,
不顾手下三名士兵失踪
while three of your own go missing
其余人也渐渐军心涣散
and your men slowly start to unravel.
我从未想到你会把艇员放在第二位
I never thought I'd see you put anything
乔  尤其是放在首位的竟是你的自尊
ahead of your people, Joe-- least of all, pride.
向我保证  如果我释放你
So give me your word that if I release you,
你不会从中作梗
you will not undermine me,
绝不暗中迫害我的人和破坏我的潜艇
you will not sabotage my people or my boat.
你要助我回国上军事法庭
You will help me get back home to a court-martial,
到时候你就是控方的关键证人
where you can be the star witness for the prosecution.
你还相信我的话吗
My word still good enough for you?
相信
Yes.
那我想你保证
You have my word.
给水手长开锁
Unlock the C.O.B.!
我可不信
It ain't good enough for me.
我会盯着你的  水手长
I'll be watching you, C.O.B.
穿好上衣  帕克
Get your blouse on, Parker.
今天可不是便装星期五
It's not casual Friday around here.
遵命  长官
Sir.
你到底去不去
Are you coming or not?
离晚饭还六个小时呢
Dinner's in six hours.
你以为有公交坐吗  我们得赶快
You think there's a bus? We have to hurry.
酒吧打烊了  大家起身吧
Bar's closed, you guys. Raise.
一百块
A hundred.
你从哪儿弄到的
Where'd you get this?
别说我没帮过你们
Don't say I never did anything for you.
这是科泰兹的
This belongs to Cortez.
对  从一个为塞拉特卖命的家伙手里得来的
Yeah. Got it from a guy who works for a guy named Serrat.
法国妞的朋友
Friend of the French lady.
你不来信  也不打电话
You didn't write, you didn't call.
你也没用鞋带上吊
You didn't hang yourself with your shoelaces.
我们都让彼此失望了
We all have our disappointments to muster.
你挡住我的路了  水手长
You're blocking my way, C.O.B.
是吗
Am I?
走开
Stop.
多谢赏光共舞  长官
Thanks for the dance, ma'am.
我不认为朱利安・塞拉特有朋友
I don't think Julian Serrat has friends.
小心  玛丽亚  太重你拿不动
我们只是想知道对手是谁
Look, we just want to know who we're dealing with here.
她说不知道  你该走了
She said no. It's time for you to leave now.
听着  现在我们的人
Listen. Right now my people
不知道被谁囚禁在什么地方
are being held in some room somewhere.
不知道等待他们的会是什么
They have no say in anything that's happening to them.
他们很害怕  只想回家
They are scared. They just want to go home.
我想保证他们能回家
I want to see that they do.
我会跟朱利安谈  跟你们艇长一起
I'll talk to Julian. With your captain.
-就你们两个  -是的
- Just you and my captain? - Yes.
不能带别人  必须这样
No one else. That's how it must be.
我不能保证你的安全
I can't promise you'll be safe.
你需要担心的不是我
I'm not the one you have to worry about.
他...  怎么说来着
He's... how do you put it?
他对我非常好
He's sweet on me.
我要去
索菲  我们得在军舰合围之前离开这里
今晚之前来得及
他是在利用你
没人能利用我
我们六点海滩见
如果你六点没到  我不会等的
If you're not here by 6:00, I won't wait for you.
你们艇长是个什么样的人
What kind of man is your captain?
他要么愚蠢要么无礼  要么二者兼备
He's either a stupid man or a very disrespectful man or both.
他怎么不来见我  还要我抓多少人
Why won't he come to me? How many must I take?
十个  二十个
10? 20?
你们知道答案吗
Can you figure it out?
你叫什么名字
What is your name?
瑞德
Red.
这岛上的每一个人都知道
Everyone on this island knows--
遇到麻烦  就来找朱利安・塞拉特
If you have a problem, you come to Julian Serrat.
比方说  就在今天
For instance, just today
他们带来一个男孩  才15岁
a boy was brought to me, only 15--
颈部中弹
shot in the neck.
死在你们交火的那片丛林里
He died in the jungle during a battle your people were in.
我们不朝孩子开枪
We don't shoot kids.
可他还是中弹了
Nevertheless, he was shot.
必须有人付出代价
Someone has to pay now.
等一下
Hey! Listen.
我能跟你谈谈吗  私下
Can I talk to you? Privately?
我会让你不虚此行的
I'll make it worth your while.
巴基斯坦制造了数个便携式核装置
Pakistan had developed several portable nuclear devices.
国防部副部长科利主张打击巴基斯坦
核打击是唯一选择
我方情报已确认
Our intelligence determined...
巴基斯坦政府工作人员
that Pakistani government operatives
已将这些装置交给了恐怖分子
had placed those devices in the hands of terrorists,
并且即将用于恐怖活动
and that they were about to be taken.
出什么事了
What's going on?
先发制人的核战争成了我们的新政策
Proactive nuclear war is our new official policy.
就是这事
That's what's happening.
遥控器呢
Where's the remote?
-声音放小点  -喂
- Turn it down! - Hello?
十分果决
... and decisively.
核打击回应是保证美国安全的唯一手段
A nuclear response was the only one that guaranteed American safe--
是的  我在看  太可怕了
Yes. I'm watching. It's terrifying.
为什么
Why?
是的  我知道
Yes. I know it.
好的
Okay.
我得去见一个人
I have to meet someone.
现在吗
Now?
你这么担心这块硬盘
If you're so worried about that hard drive,
不如放进银行保险箱
you should put it in a safe deposit box.
罗伯特  这里面有科罗拉多号样机的所有技术
Robert, all of the tech for the prototype on the "Colorado" is on here.
唯一一份原理图
The only schematic.
你觉得我会把它托付给银行吗
You think I'd entrust that to a bank?
你疑心病太重
That is completely paranoid.
我知道
I know.
别让任何人进来
Don't let anyone in.
我可不会等你回来
I'm not waiting up for you.
不  你会的
Sure, you will.
谢帕德上将
Admiral Shepard?
有人吗
Knock, knock.
马库斯・查普林宣称  科罗拉多号收到的
Marcus Chaplin claims that the nuke order
核弹发射命令来自南极紧急通讯网
sent to the "Colorado" came through the antarctic network,
而非主通讯网
not the main network.
这不可能  因为我们并未遭受攻击
Which is impossible, because we weren't under attack.
而且有谁会相信一个好战的疯子呢
And who believes a trigger-happy madman anyway?
至少你相信  所以你来了
Well, you do. That's why you came.
我需要知道命令是谁下的
I need to know who sent that order.
让我去问问海军情报部的朋友莱纳斯吧
Let me just ask my friend Linus in Naval Intelligence.
哦  不对  他还在医院昏迷着呢
Oh, wait. He's lying comatose in a hospital
因为他对贝类过敏
because of a shellfish allergy.
顺便说一句  我对什么都不过敏
I'm allergic to nothing, by the way,
所以我若也遭受不测  拜托你露个面好吗
so if that happens, throw a flag on the play, will you?
你的朋友莱纳斯是个无名小卒  你可不是
Your friend Linus was nobody, but you're not.
你老爸和总统一起打高尔夫球
Your father golfs with the president,
而且我好像读到过  在华府
and I read somewhere where you're one of D.C.'s
你是最受欢迎的单身女性之一
most eligible bachelorettes.
是吗  不小心被发现了
Hmm. Well, look where that's got me.
在这件事中  你有得天独厚的条件
You're uniquely qualified to do something about this.
得天独厚的条件  就是拿我自己的人头冒险
Uniquely qualified to risk my own ass
去救你的宝贝女儿是吧
to help you save your daughter?
你以为我是谁啊
Who do you think I am?
你是战争中的寄生虫
You're a parasite who traffics in war
从来不用承担任何风险
without ever getting her hands dirty,
而这个国家付钱购买你们家族的武器
and this country has made you rich
让你赚得盆满钵满
buying your family's weapons.
你不该做出点回报吗
Aren't you ready to do something in return?
这是那条命令的文件号
It's the file number of the order.
这样够爱国了吧
Patriotic enough for you?
你还是在乎的  这个能帮上我
You do care. This will help me.
也能帮上其他和我一样相信此事的人
And it will help the people that believe as I do.
但你依然需要出面提出一些我不能提的问题
But you still need to ask the questions that I can't.
闹出些动静吧  辛克莱小姐
Make some noise, Miss Sinclair.
你跟他说什么了
What did you say to him?
不是她说了什么
It's not what she said.
而是她做了什么
It's what she did.
谢谢你  科泰兹
Thank you, Cortez.
[土语]
朱利安
Julian.
这位是马库斯・查普林艇长
This is Captain Marcus Chaplin.
他的几名手下失踪了
He's lost a few of his men,
我告诉他你能帮上忙
and I told him you could help.
欢迎
Welcome.
我还想艇长大人什么时候才会
I was wondering when I could expect a visit
大驾光临呢
from the great Captain.
您和您的潜艇给我们这个小小的世外桃源
You and your submarine have caused a commotion
闹得有点鸡犬不宁啊
in our little paradise.
我们很庆幸能在这里找到一个港湾
We're grateful to find a harbor here.
我们很愿意招待你们短暂停留
We are glad to temporarily accommodate you.
我艇上的三名艇员失踪了
I'm missing three crew members.
那你怎么不早来找我
You should have come to me sooner!
不过你现在来了  这才是最重要的
But you are here now. That is what is important.
-我想我是找对人了  -没错
- I see I've come to the right man. - Yes, you have.
我就是你该找的人
I'm the right man.
那边那些人
Those people there--
由于你们的到来  他们的儿子被杀了
Their son was killed because of your interference here.
你们为这个岛带来了暴力
You brought violence to this island.
现在那孩子死去了  这个女人沉浸在悲痛中
Now this child is dead, and this woman is in mourning.
我们也是
As are we all.
我要包办他们儿子葬礼的费用
I'm paying for their son's funeral.
我知道我们的到来给这里带来了不少麻烦
I understand our presence here has been a burden,
但我们之间不需要再起争端
but there's no need for us to quarrel,
因为如果真的要争  你输定了
because if we do, you'll lose.
被千刀万剐
A death by a thousand cuts.
这就是和我斗的下场
That would be war with me.
[土语]
这座岛处于封锁中
A blockade surrounds this island.
我有一艘满载贵重货物的船
I have a boat with very valuable cargo.
现在我满脑子想的都是这艘船
And I'm so concerned about this boat,
根本没工夫考虑你失踪的手下
I can't think about your missing crewmen.
我们有办法拿到你想要的东西
We have the means to get what you want
如果你有办法找到我的手下
if you have the means to return my crewmen.
好吧
Okay.
今晚他们会为死者守夜
They will stay with the body all night.
明天一早  我们会准备把男孩下葬
At dawn, we will prepare the boy for burial.
你欠这些人的债  我帮你还了
You have a debt to these people that I have paid.
但在天亮之前  你要还上欠我的债
But before dawn, you must bring me what you owe me.
你给的时间太短
That's not much time.
是的  我知道
Yes, I know.
你要是早点来就好了
I wish you had come to me sooner.
塞拉特给你的时间很少
Serrat didn't give you much time.
你们能办到吗
Will you be able to do it?
我们别无选择
We have to.
祝你好运
Good luck with everything.
再见
Uh, good-bye.
Good-bye.
我醒着呢
I'm awake.
我们快到了
We're almost there.
你没告诉我要走这么久
You didn't tell me it'd take this long.
我又不知道你这么娇气
I had no idea you were so fragile.
真不敢相信你住在这里
I can't believe this is where you live.
我妈妈以前经常来这儿
My mother came here a lot.
是吗  她也像你这么难缠吗
Yeah? Is she as much of a ball-buster as you?
不再是了  她去世了
Not anymore. She died.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我也是
Me, too.
你的父母呢  他们还健在吗
What about your parents? Are they still alive?
对
Yep.
就一个 对  字
That's it? Just "Yep"?
对
Yep.
艇员们状态不错
Crew looks good.
他们都明白形势
They know what's at stake.
我可不喜欢给毒枭当中间人
Can't say I like the idea of being a bagman for a drug lord.
而我不想两面受敌
And I don't like the idea of a war on two fronts.
我好像没有允许过你随便说话  水手长
I don't recall giving you permission to speak freely, C.O.B.
抱歉  长官  我犯糊涂了
Sorry, sir. I'm a little rusty.
全体艇员  我是副艇长
Crew, this is the X.O.
我们都清楚接下来要干什么
We all know what we're about to do,
原因也心知肚明
and we know why we're doing it.
布兰伦  科泰兹和瑞德曼都在指望着我们
Brannan, Cortez, and Redman are all counting on us.
为救战友而战  副艇长讲话完毕
Let's go get our people back. X.O. Out.
长官  潜艇正在接近封锁区内的战舰
You're approaching the ships in the blockade, sir.
工程舱  准备好珀尔修斯样机
Engineering, ready the Perseus prototype.
副艇长  启动需要时间
X.O., it'll take a moment to power up.
珀尔修斯启动程序
启动珀尔修斯系统
珀尔修斯准备完毕
美海军科罗拉多号
长官  潜艇消失了  屏幕上信号消失
You're gone, sir. Screens are clear.
科罗拉多号已隐身
The "Colorado's" Disappeared.
舵手  航向060  全速前进
Helm, 0-6-0, ahead full.
凯姆伦  开始计时  还有九小时天亮
Cameron, set a clock. We have nine hours to sunrise.
我需要你帮个忙
Hey. I need a favor.
让你的参议员调出
I need your senator to requisition
998命令的时间戳
a time stamp on order 998.
时间戳  经过加密而形成的凭证文档
此命令由南极通讯网下达给科罗拉多号
Came through the antarctic network to the "Colorado."
你是说查普林在电视上提到的那个
You mean the thing Chaplin talked about on TV?
那个通讯网是冷战遗物  只有在华府
It's a cold war relic. It's only supposed to be used
遭到核弹攻击才会加以使用
if someone hit D.C. with the big one.
拜托了
Please?
拜托啦  拜托嘛
Please, please, please?
我  我试试吧
I-I'll, uh... I'll work on it.
谢谢
Thank you.
不过  罗伯特  记着让参议员动手
Hey, Robert, make sure it goes through the senator.
别自己去
Don't do it yourself.
正在接近封锁线  长官
Approaching the blockade, sir.
艇长  发现两艘驱逐舰
Captain, I hold 2 destroyers.
两侧各5000码处
5,000 yards on each side.
计划航线
科罗拉多号
副艇长  我们得从中间穿过去
X.O., we're gonna have to pass in between them.
珀尔修斯系统已停止工作
Perseus is offline.
长官  声纳可以探测到你的潜艇
Sir, I have a sonar location on you.
他们听得到你们
They can hear you.
美海军科罗拉多号
重复  隐身已失效
I repeat--you are not masked.
工程舱  马上重启珀尔修斯系统
Engineering, conn. Get the Perseus back online now.
是  长官
Aye, sir.
珀尔修斯系统停止运行
指挥台  这里是工程舱
Conn, engineering, sir.
珀尔修斯系统已恢复  长官
All systems back online, sir.
潜艇再次隐身
You're off the screens again.
驱逐舰有什么动静吗
Any movement on the destroyers?
原位不动
Holding position.
看来我们很幸运
Looks like we got lucky.
舵手  超速前进
Helm, ahead flank.
潜水官  调整至深度600英尺
Diving officer, make your depth 600 feet.
任务按原计划继续
Proceed with the mission.
把货物运进来
Let's get that cargo on board.
小心点  给你
Watch yourself. Here you go.
货物按计划装载完毕
Cargo on board right on schedule.
船员下舱完毕  舱口安全
Last man down. Hatch secured.
把这些锁进供给箱  别打开
Lock them up in supply. Don't open them.
是  副艇长  里面是什么
Aye, X.O. What's in 'em?
三条人命
Three lives.
你就这样离开了文明社会  没回过头
So you just left civilization and never looked back?
对
Yeah.
一开始我以为这里只是我的遗产
At first I thought this place was just my heritage,
没想到竟然是我的救星
but it turned out to be my salvation.
别人都没有他幸运
Others of us weren't so lucky.
很多人没有这样的勇气
Most people don't have the courage to do that.
他们只是口头说说  过脱离世界的生活
They talk about it-- just live off the grid
或是重新开始什么的
or have a clean start or whatever.
而你是身体力行了
You actually did it.
-下周艾图就成年了  -是啊
- And next week, Aitu becomes a man. - Right.
还要  还要举行个仪式
There's a-- there's this ritual.
很赞  之后我就可以当学徒了
It's awesome. And after that, I can apprentice.
什么
What?
马努同意指导他了
Manu agreed to take him on.
我们之前不是这么定的
That wasn't the plan.
-以后再说  -不  现在说
- We'll talk about it later. - No, we'll talk about it now!
你跟他说了什么
What did you say to him?
他应该好好过日子
He deserves to have a life.
-这样挺好的  -你懂什么
- I like my life. - You don't know the difference!
塔妮  他改变主意了
Tani, he changed his mind.
不  是你逼他的
No, you changed his mind!
你就是不罢休  是吧
You won't stop, will you?
你还要毁掉这个家里  多少人的生活
How many lives in this family do you plan on ruining?
我女儿发脾气和太阳升起一样正常
My daughter storms off, the sun comes up.
预料之中的  不用追
It's expected. Stay.
谢谢你的招待
Thank you for your hospitality,
但是我得去陪带我来的伙伴
but I'm gonna dance with the one that brung me.
晚安  先生
Good night, sir.
警告
主动力系统失稳
辅助动力启动
工程舱  这里是指挥台
Engineering, conn.
珀尔修斯系统停了我的电
The Perseus is draining my power.
长官  它正在烧毁电路
Sir, it's starting to burn through circuits.
如果现在不关掉它
We don't shut it down,
我们有断电风险
it's gonna shut us down.
给老子关了这破玩意
Turn the damn thing off.
潜水官  下潜至1000英尺
Diving officer, make your depth 1,000 feet.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
我们得用老办法行动了
We're gonna have to do this the old-fashioned way.
副艇长  下令进入静默潜航状态
X.O., rig for silent. Rig ship for silent running.
停止所有风扇运行  进入静默潜航状态
Secure all fans. Rig ship for silent running.
艇长  四个点火控制系统已停止
Captain, four stop on fire control.
-皮特森搞什么名堂  -水手长  待在这
- What the hell, Peterson? - C.O.B., stay here.
-摩尔  回到轮机舱  -我能搞定
- Moore, get back to the engine room. - I got it.
海军有句老话
Old navy saying--
"别让水手长毁了潜艇"
"Don't let the C.O.B. sabotage the sub."
普罗赛  给我把火压着
Prosser, keep a lid on it. Keep a lid on it.
先生们  内部矛盾先放一边
Gentlemen, stow this problem,
不然我们在一分钟后就会玩完
or we're all gonna be dead in about one minute.
明白了吗
Am I clear?
明白  长官
Clear, sir.
-正接近封锁线  -明白
- Approaching the blockade. - Noted.
驱逐舰正转向我方位置
Destroyer turning on our position.
-打破了搜索队形  - 舵手  停车
- Breaking the perimeter. - Helm, all stop.
是  长官  停车
Yes, sir, all stop.
潜水官  再下潜300英尺
Diving officer, take us down another 300.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
慢慢下潜
But do it gently.
长官  两艘驱逐舰正向你的方位驶来
Sir, you've got two destroyers headed your way.
长官
Sir?
听得到吗
他们一定警告了封锁舰队
They'll have alerted the blockade.
先生们  我们正与整个舰队交手
Gentlemen, we have the entire fleet to contend with.
-报告深度  -1300英尺
- Depth? - 1,300.
你听见了吗
You hear that?
她在1300英尺处总会呻吟一会
She always moans a little at 1,300 feet.
那是她的敏感区
That's her g-spot.
驱逐舰正从艇艉方向靠近
Destroyer still approaching aft.
-再下潜  -明白  长官
- Deeper. - Yes, sir.
艇长  你这是要破纪录吗
You going for the record, captain?
她会挺住的
Oh, she'll take it.
是啊  她能行
Yes, she will.
1800英尺
1,800.
驱逐舰正从我们上方驶过
She's passing directly above us.
发现深水炸弹
Depth charges in the water!
舵手  准备好一爆炸就超速前进
Helm, ready ahead flank on the pop.
航向设为1-8-5度
Make your course 1-8-5.
第二艘驱逐舰从艇艉靠近  发现更多炸弹
Second destroyer approaching aft. More charges!
等待爆炸
Wait for the pop.
超速前进  右满舵
All ahead flank, right full rudder!
稳住  航向1-8-5度  我们掉头
Steady! 1-8-5! Get us around now!
目标方位1-4-4度  航速20节
Contact bearing 1-4-4. 20 knots.
宙斯盾巡洋舰
Aegis cruiser.
舵手  超速前进
Helm, all ahead flank.
潜水官  升降舵上转20度
Diving officer, 20 degree up-angle.
发现目标  她还有同伴
Contact! She has friends.
多艘舰船  行驶方向相同
Multiple, on the same heading.
是三艘驱逐舰  不  是四艘
Destroyers. Three. No, four.
发现深水炸弹
Depth charge in the water.
升降舵向上满舵
Full rise on the planes.
我们爬升  水柜排干
Get us up. Maximum bubble.
停车
All stop.
副艇长  停止一切运行
Dead in the water, X.O.
确认命令  停车
Confirm that order. All stop.
明白  艇长  停车
All stop. Aye, captain.
他们在我们正上方
They're right on us.
大家都别动
Nobody moves.
目标正在穿过
Contact's passing.
这是个典型的3深弹反潜程序
That's a standard 3-charge pattern.
仔细听  一  二  三
You'll hear it-- one, two, three.
他们没有再回来  长官
They're not coming back, sir.
副艇长  返航海滩
X.O., take us back to the beach.
声纳系统发现我们了
Sonar's acquired us.
驱逐舰以航向3-3-9度向我们驶来
Destroyer coming about on our position heading 3-3-9!
30分钟后潮汐就来了  我们得走了
舵手  航向3-2-0度
Helm, steer course 3-2-0.
山脊距离约2000码  我们正高速接近
Ridge at a range of 2,000 yards, closing fast.
那就是面墙  长官  延伸至海平面
That's a wall, sir. Right up to the surface.
不  那是一个峡谷  他们不敢追到那
No, it's a canyon. They'd be crazy to come after us.
你对间隙距离有把握吗
You sure about the clearance?
即使我们能驶入  也不能永远藏在里面
Even if we fit, we can't hide in there forever.
我们不用躲  我们要穿过峡谷
We're not gonna hide. We're going through.
长官  他们已经搜索到并锁定了我们
Sir, they have us acquired and ranged.
-正迅速接近准备再次攻击  -这次会很近
- Closing on us for another pass. - This is gonna be tight.
潜艇准备承受声波冲击  关闭警报
Rig the boat for sound collision, no alarms!
稳定航行
Steady as she goes.
塔妮
Tani!
你要睡在这里吗
You gonna sleep here or what?
也许吧
Maybe.
抱歉你父亲没对我大发雷霆
Sorry your dad didn't hate me more.
计划就是这样  对吗
That was the idea, right?
把入侵者带去吃晚饭
Bring the invader to dinner?
是啊
Yes...
计划就是这样
That was the idea.
我高中时  姑娘都会带我回家
You know, in high school I was the go-to guy
去气她们的父亲
for girls looking to piss off their fathers.
-他看上去没那么坏  -闭嘴
- He doesn't seem that bad. - Oh, shut up.
我只想说  不知道你想让你弟弟如何生活
I'm just saying, I don't know what you worked out
但他看上去在这里过得很开心
with your brother, but he seems pretty happy here.
这不管你的事
You know, it's really none of your business.
是啊  该我管的事远在九千英里之外
No. My business is about 9,000 miles away.
这是什么地方
So what is this place?
她被葬在这儿
She's buried here.
我给她带了一些姜糖
I brought her some ginger candy.
这是种  怎么说
It's kind of... I don't know,
一种问候她的方式吧
A way of saying hi, I guess.
我的父亲  他不是个好人
You know, he's not a good man, my father.
当我母亲生病时  他说服她
When my mother got sick, he convinced her
应该在岛上治疗
she should be treated here.
你懂的
You know.
用传统草药和那些荒谬的方法
Traditional medicine and all that nonsense.
却不愿把她带回澳大利亚
Didn't want to take her back to Australia...
她便同意了
So she went along.
她总是对他让步
Always appeasing him.
临死前  她非常痛苦
She was in a lot of pain at the end.
我等着艾图长大
I was waiting for Aitu to be old enough
把他带离这里
to get him away from here.
听着  塔妮
Look... Tani,
他留下并不等于你也必须留下
Just 'cause he's staying doesn't mean you have to.
你好  罗伯特
Hello, Robert.
知道我是谁吗
Do you know who I am?
-当然知道  -很好
- Y-yes, of course. - Well, good.
那就省事了
Then this won't take long.
罗伯特
Robert?
罗伯特  你在吗
Robert, are you here?
为什么女孩们总喜欢带你回家
Why were you the one the girls would bring home?
估计她们都以为能改变我
I guess they thought they could fix me.
她们成功了吗
Did they?
只有一个差点成功了
Only one came close.
-她叫什么名字  -美国海军
- What was her name? - U.S. Navy.
但我们正在经历一段困难时期
But we're going through a bit of a rough patch at the moment.
她让你认识了整个世界
She showed you the world.
一个并不那么美好的世界
World ain't all it's cracked up to be.
你听到那声音了吗
Do you hear that?
那是艾图将举行成人仪式的地方
That's where Aitu will come for his ritual.
他需要做什么
What does he have to do?
祝贺你  你是个男人了
Congratulations. You're a man.
是吗  那你跳下来算怎样
Yeah? What does that make you, then?
妈妈曾带我来过这里
My mom used to bring me here.
这是我们的小秘密
It was our little secret.
本来只有男孩能来
It's only supposed to be for the boys...
就像这里很多事情一样
like most things around here.
这地方就是这样
That's the thing about this place.
美好的事情却总是那么短暂
The best things never last for long.
我们得走了  回去要走很长的路
We should go. It's a long walk back.
情况汇报  水手长
Sit-rep, Master Chief?
样机烧坏了右舷配电板
Prototype fried the starboard switchboards.
反应堆供能为三分之一
Reactor's at one-third.
各主系统功能正由辅助系统运行
Vital systems are on auxiliary.
系统导航是没指望了
And you can forget about any nav.
我们在尽力重新启动  但是
We're trying to reboot, but...
山姆  尝试呼叫格蕾丝  让她帮我们定位
Sam, if you can raise Grace, get our position.
如果打不通的话
If we can't get through,
就只能干等着了
we're gonna have to wait this one out.
谢帕德上尉  谢帕德上尉  请回话
Lieutenant Shepard, Lieutenant Shepard, come in.
-我在  副艇长  -能够定位我们吗
- I'm here, X.O. - Can you get a fix on us?
并不准确  长官  干扰信号太多
Not accurately, sir. There's too much interference.
我们失去导航能力了  谢帕德上尉
We're blind down here, Lieutenant Shepard.
谢帕德上尉  还在吗  完毕
Lieutenant Shepard, are you there? Over.
失去联系了
We lost her.
山姆  我是索菲  我知道你们在哪
Sam, it's Sophie. I know where you are.
我有那个区域的海图
Uh, I've got that area charted.
那是什么
What is that?
你只需要知道怎么看图
You just need to know how to read it.
我想我能把你们带出去  听仔细
I think I can get you out. Listen carefully.
-深度多少  -175英尺
- What's your depth? - 175 feet.
-速度  -9节
- Speed? - 9 knots.
主动声呐能否正常使用
Do you still have active sonar?
可以  但会非常危险
Yeah, we do, but it's very dangerous.
我知道  但还是得用一下
I know, but do it anyway.
凯姆伦  启用一次回声测深仪
Cameron, one ping on the fathometer.
下潜50英尺
Down 50.
-潜至225英尺  -是  长官
- Dive to 225. - Yes, sir.
好的
Okay.
目前深度225英尺
We're at 225.
-速度  -10节
- Speed? - 10 knots.
很快将转弯  我会告诉你
You'll turn soon. I'll tell you.
转向那边
Which side?
右舷  快了
Starboard. Soon.
好的
Okay.
我觉得  可以开始缓慢转舵了
I think... you may scrape.
-哪边  右舷吗  -是的
- Which side? Starboard side? - Yes.
开始计时  现在就转舵
Mark. Turn now--
-十度  -向右舵十度
- 10 degrees. - Turn 10 degrees starboard side.
没错  就是这个动静
Yeah, that's what that sounds like.
很快就到了
Almost there.
潜至300英尺
Dive to 300 feet.
有只小船离开岛屿了
There's a small craft leaving the island.
没关系  我知道是谁
It's okay. I know who it is.
好的  当前深度300英尺
Okay, we're at-- we're at 300 feet.
水平航行  保持深度90米
Level off. Stay at 90 meters.
我是说  英尺
I mean, uh, feet.
300英尺  抱歉
Uh, 300 feet, sorry.
没关系  没问题
No, that's okay. That's fine.
用声呐再探测一次
Another ping.
再来一次  你说过"就一次"
Another ping? You said "once."
我从没说过"就一次"
I never said "once."
向左转20度
Turn port 20 degrees.
空间非常有限
Okay, there's not much room.
这艘潜艇转弯半径不够小
Yeah, this sub doesn't really corner all that well.
那我们就得小心点
Then we'll have to be careful.
好的
Okay.
差不多快到了
You're almost there.
升至120英尺
Rise to 120 feet.
然后就可以了  只需等待
And nothing else. Just, uh... waiting.
没关系  我等惯了
That's okay. I'm used to it.
我也是
Me, too.
我们安全了
We're clear.
成功抵达另一边
We're on the other side.
-好了  上浮吧  -是  长官
- All right, bring us up. - Aye, sir.
舵手  超速前进
Helm, all ahead flank.
航向191度  驶回海滩
Make your course 1-9-1. We're headed back to the beach.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
你们艇长违背了我们的约定
Your captain reneged on our deal.
你们中的一个必须付出代价
One of you must pay for his failure.
我让你来选一个
I will let you choose who.
-再等一下  -好吧  那你来选
- Now hold on a second-- - Okay, then you choose!
别这么做  我们是有交易的
Don't do this! We had a deal!
-你做了交易  -我和你们的艇长做了交易
- You made a deal? - I had a deal with your captain.
快点  别等我失去耐心
Quickly, before I lose patience!
别这样对待我们  别玩游戏
Don't put this on us. Don't play games.
我们好好谈谈
Let's talk about this!
好吧  这就是我们的谈判方式
Okay. Then this is how we will talk!
好吧  选他
Okay, him!
把他带去吧
Take him.
-什么  不要啊  -我很抱歉  瑞德
- What? Please! - I'm s-sorry, Red.
-我很抱歉  -不不不
- I'm sorry. - No! No, no, no!
-我很抱歉  瑞德  -求你了  约什  科泰兹
- I'm sorry, Red. - Please! Josh! Cortez!
瑞德  对不起
Red, I'm sorry!
求你了  不要这样
Please! Don't do this!
科泰兹
Cortez.
约什
Josh.
我现在就可以杀了你
I could kill you right now.
你想引发战争吗
Do you want a war?
还有一个
There's one more!
不  没有了
No, there is not.
你迟到了
You were late.
我们走
Let's go.
你有消息了吗
Have you heard anything?
不  还没有  他们...
Uh, no, not yet. They're--
他们现在去交易了
They're doing the switch right now.
你没赶上船
You missed your ride.
我总是挑错人
I always pick the wrong ones.
新年的时候  我下定决心
This new year's, I made a resolution
不再找坏男人  不再抽烟
to give up bad men and cigarettes,
一周后我却躺在刚特曼身边抽烟
And a week later I was smoking in bed next to Guttman.
通常这时我会趁机笑话
This is normally where I'd make a joke
和法国男人约会的下场
about dating French men,
但是
but...
我还是算了吧
I'll let it go.
我们会另想办法让你离开这里的
We'll find a way to get you out of here.
你不必为每个人负责的  知道吗
You don't have to be responsible for everyone, you know?
我就是这样一个人
It's kind of what I do.
你为什么要选择当兵
Why did you become a soldier?
我们不是士兵  我们是水手
Well, we're not soldiers. We're sailors.
但我年轻的时候有些迷失
But, uh, I was a bit lost early in life.
是大海给我指明了新方向
The water was more forgiving.
你妻子  她也喜欢出海的生活吗
Does your wife--she also likes being on the water?
不
No.
听着
uh, look.
我只是想过来感谢你
I just wanted to come by and thank you
感谢你的帮助
for what you did.
似乎我每次见你  都要为不同的事感谢你
It seems like every time I see you I'm thanking you for something,
我知道你原本是有机会离开的  所以
But I know you had a chance to leave, so...
谢谢你
Thank you.
何足挂齿
De rien.
-意思就是"不必客气"  -好吧
- That means "You're welcome." - Okay.
说白了就是没什么
Well, literally it means "It's nothing."
没这么简单
It wasn't.
跟我走
Giddyup.
他杀了瑞德吗
He killed Red?
是的
Yes.
行了
Okay then.
你打算去干什么  山姆
What are you going to do, Sam?
一边抵挡整个美国海军
Hold off the entire U.S. Navy on one side
另一边和暴民作战吗
and fight an insurgency on the other?
别犯和其他人一样的错误
Do not make the mistake so many others have.
丛林中埋伏着枪手  车下都埋着炸弹
Gunmen in the bushes. A bomb under every vehicle.
我们会伤亡惨重的
We'd bleed out in a fight.
反正我们也是死路一条了
We're bleeding anyway.
你觉得如果让他们知道
What do you think's gonna happen when they know
我们让一个岛上暴徒处决了我们的战友会怎样
we let some island thug execute one of our own, huh?
-到时候会怎样  -他给我们下了最后期限
- What happens then? - He gave us a deadline
是我们没能达到
which we did not meet.
我们不能总让他们忍下去
We can't keep asking more of them.
我们在这里最宝贵的精神
The one thing we have out here--
最宝贵的精神  就是对彼此的忠诚
The one thing we have out here-- is our loyalty to each other.
就是那样
That's it!
现在我们得告诉他们  连这个也没有了吗
Now we have to tell them they don't even have that?
被国抛弃  无家可归  现在甚至觉得
No country, no home, and now not even the faith
他们的死也毫无意义吗
that their death would mean something?
我们就眼睁睁看着他们被杀害吗
That we'll just allow them to be murdered?
我儿子的尸体被晾在海军冰库里  不能下葬
My son is lying unburied in a navy freezer
作为我不肯投降的代价
as the price for not capitulating,
所以你没有资格跟我说什么信念和复仇
so please don't tell me about faith and vengeance!
我们必报此仇
We will respond to this affront
只是眼下时候未到
at the time and place of my choosing.
我们不能被困在这儿  马库斯
We can't just get stuck here, Marcus.
我做不到
Can't do it.
现在的情况跟以前不同了  山姆
This is not like before, Sam.
我们在这儿并非是孤立无助
We're not helpless here.
等我选定合适的  时机
The time and place...of my choosing.
爸
Dad.
谢天谢地你来了
Thank god you're here.
他们拿走了  他们全拿走了
They took it. They took it all.
好了  没事了  没事了
Okay. It's okay. It's okay.
在那里发生了什么
What happened in there?
最后期限过了
Deadline passed.
塞拉特将瑞德拖出去  杀了他
Serrat hauled Red out and shot him.
瑞德之前顶撞过他
Red had been giving him lip earlier,
所以我猜是想拿他开刀
so I guess he was an easy target.
我很抱歉让你受这样的苦
I'm sorry you had to go through that.
我们尽了最大努力
We did the best we could.
长官  发生那样的事  没人会责怪你的
Forgive me, sir, but no one blames you for what happened.
或许你也该好好喝一杯
Maybe you should have one of those.
我们会回家的  我们会好好安葬杰弗里的
We'll get home, we'll bury Jeffrey right.
在阿灵顿公墓鸣枪21响
21 guns at Arlington.
我们会给他应有的待遇
We'll do it right.
"海军部已准备下达32号文件
"The Department of the Navy article 32 has been scheduled
"致美海军潜艇科罗拉多号艇员
"To the crew of the U.S.S. 'Colorado,'
《破釜沉舟》前情提要
福吉谷:华盛顿训练军队重振旗鼓的地方
留下               离开
留下             离开
玛丽・安托瓦内特(法王路易十六的王后): 法国革命时期所说
潜艇失事时  可注入高压气体排出主压载水舱内的水  使潜艇浮出水面
艇长仓
翻译：allen0314  圈圈  小黎  我不是青椒    校对：Ethan-泽生  米苏  宁馨儿
翻译：不悛熊  Silmar  萌Su  十九罗汉  Ethan-泽生  hammer_tank
后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
时间轴：贝壳  GGwhywhy  萌  cherry
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
217美元
$217.
911事件后美国人众志成城
Americans volunteered after 9/11,
-安德斯  你严重越界了  -我得回家  长官
- You're way out of line here, Anders. - I need to go home, sir.
把它关了
Turn that off.
把这事管到底
and see this thing through.
白宫律师声称  这一法律手段为剥夺
White House lawyers say the legal move paves the way
半个小时后  伊利诺斯号
tried to blow us out of the water
保持忙碌是个好方法
It's good to keep busy.
保持这一深度  解决堵漏问题
Maintain order depth. Secure the flooding.
保持左满舵  航向3-2-9度
Left full rudder steady, 3-2-9.
爆炸离艇身很近  在左舷
Explosion close aboard-- port side!
被袭前的位置
before the attack.
-被袭时的位置  -不是这样
- when it was attacked.  - No, that's not it.
比尔  我是马库斯
This is Marcus, Bill.
比你的艇长还高吗
Higher than your captain?
比你想的重要得多
worth more than you can ever imagine.
必要时可采取致命手段
using lethal force if necessary,
避开鱼雷  部署紧急防御措施
Torpedo evasion. Deploy countermeasures.
-别  -我很想让他安全离开那里
- Don't-- - Hey, I want to get him out of there as safe as I can,
别费事了  结的疤会比较好看
I know. Don't bother. It's gonna scar up nice.
别关  请开着门
No, leave it open, please.
别急  约什  就快连上了
Stay with me, Josh. We're almost there.
别靠近我  我发誓
Don't come near me! I swear to god!
别起来了
Don't get up.
别让她靠近霍普
Keep her away from him.
别往前走了
Don't take another step.
别这么做  我们是有交易的
Don't do this! We had a deal!
别这样  约什
Don't go there,  Josh.
并占领或凿沉美国潜艇科罗拉多号
and seize or scuttle the U.S.S. "Colorado."
不  不  不
No! No, no, no, no!
不  不是
No, it wasn't.
不  但他希望别人这么认为
No, but he wants them to think that he is.
不  副艇长  你不能这么做  他情绪混乱
No, X.O., you can't do this. He's messed up.
不  霍普现在还不能跋涉  不行
No, Hopper can't travel yet. No way.
不  没有了  你迟到了
No, there is not. You were late.
不  你把事情都搞混了
No. You...you're twisting everything up.
不  你发过誓要维护和保卫
No, you swore to support and defend
不  我得回去  我得...
No, I got to get back. I got to...
不
No.
不管你们想不想要它
Whether you want it or not.
不管你现在怎么想
Whatever's going through your mind right now,
不管怎样  都会有人说我是个英雄
Either way, somebody's gonna call me a hero.
不行
No. You won't.
不然我就在这里与它玉石俱焚
or I will die on the bottom with it.
不是发射命令  长官
It's not a firing order, sir.
不适宜继续指挥  副艇长也一样
unfit for command, as has his X.O.
不受国内外敌人的侵犯
against all enemies, foreign and domestic.
不为世界所知
wasn't noticed by the world.
不要
No. No!
不要浮上海面
We're not going anywhere.
不用的
You didn't.
不知道你注意到没有
Look, I'm not sure if you noticed,
不止一个人有这样的想法
He's not the only one.
布兰伦   请确认我的命令
Mr. Brannan, I want you to confirm that you have heard your orders.
布兰伦  别动  拿好手雷
Brannan, hold out the grenade and do not move!
布兰伦士官  离开指挥室
Petty Officer Brannan, step off the conn.
才能让人们去追寻事实真相
is forcing hard questions to be asked back home.
查普林测试样机的时候
But when Chaplin tested it,
查普林和肯德尔的
for Chaplin and Kendal to be stripped of
场面会失控  我们必死无疑
we lose the controls, we're all dead.
出现发射故障  长官
We have a firing malfunction, ma'am.
出现在"离开"的名单里
right up there with the others.
出现在潜艇频道内的信息
the boat's channels the last few days.
出于道德责任我们挺身而出  挑战权威
when it acts against the best interests of our nation.
此传统能够一直回溯到福吉谷
all the way back to Valley Forge.
从我这里偷走珀尔修斯硬盘
to steal the Perseus drive from me.
打架的话给我滚出去
Take this outside my bar!
打开扬声器
Put it on the speakers.
大到先进的武器系统
to advanced weapons systems,
大家处境都很艰难
This is hard on all of us,
大家都只想回家
Everybody just wants to go home.
大约还需30秒
30 seconds, maybe.
担心其他艇员会怎么想他
What the crew would think of him.
但巴基斯坦已成废墟
But Pakistan is in ruins,
但对我总还抱有信心吧
but you damn well will have faith in me.
但副艇长是对的
but the X.O. Is correct.
但还好有切萨皮克港
But there was always the Chesapeake.
但你不能像这样让我措手不及
But you shouldn't have put me on my heels like that.
但你得学着
but you're gonna have to learn
但你男友  那个地质学家
But your boyfriend, the geologist,
但你要做出决定  约什
but you need to decide, Josh.
但是不管你怎么想...
But whatever's going through your mind--
但是核潜艇副艇长之妻克里斯蒂・肯德尔
But Christine Kendal, wife of nuclear submarine X.O.,
但是游戏升级了
But the game has grown.
但他没给我这个机会
but he has taken it out of my hands.
但他们当时要杀我们  约什
They tried to kill us, Josh.
但我们必须做出抉择
but we do need to decide.
但我需要你的帮助
But I need your help.
但我已拉开手雷保险销
but my grenade is live.
但现在不再是了
but not anymore.
但休息舱会有冰淇淋
but there will be ice cream on the mess decks.
但这里不是阿灵顿
It ain't Arlington, though.
但这是我唯一的选择
But it's the only choice I had.
但这些都是可矫正的
Those things are curable.
但这也许是很长一段时间内
But it might be the last message
但这一决定是正确的  干得漂亮
but the right one. Well done.
当国家的最大利益受到威胁时
under the moral obligation to stand up to authority
当然  都听你的
Of course. Whatever you like.
当我对他说
When I ran the theory past him
当我看见海军的宣传时
I...I just wanted to be in the navy
倒计时三  二...
Impact in three, two...
到封锁区需要四小时
You're four hours out from the blockade.
得到妥当安排
can be arranged."
第二次是加入潜艇任务
and again by signing up for submariner duty.
第一次是加入海军
once when they joined the navy,
懂了
Understood.
赌注已经超出你的能力范围
The stakes are out of your league.
对  不能
No, you're not.
对哦  顽强的男人
Right. Tough guy.
-舵手留在原位  -是  长官
- Helm remain stationed. - Yes, sir.
而你却在某处享受汉普顿斯宝座
with you sitting on a Hamptons throne somewhere
而且她没钱  所以来不了
she has no money, so she can't just come,
而且我要亲手把你  肯德尔和查普林艇长
Besides, I'm gonna paddle you, Kendal, and Captain Chaplin
而是变得完美
We drill to be perfect.
而是一种誓言
It's a declaration.
而现在数据就在那个硬盘上
which is now also on that drive.
发现新目标  方位0-9-7度
New contact bearing 0-9-7.
发现鱼雷  方位0-2-7度
Torpedo in the water bearing 0-2-7.
放下枪
Lower your weapon.
费舍  我们走
Fish, let's roll.
浮上海面的潜艇在战斗中毫无作用  长官
In combat, a ship on the surface is a dead ship, sir.
副艇长  连线
X.O., open the channel.
副艇长  请和我们的轮机长谈谈
X.O., please speak with our engineer.
副艇长大人
Anyway, X.O., huh?
副艇长接管指挥台
X.O. On the conn.
赋予我一切
Gave me everything I have,
搞什么
What the...
告诉你那亲爱的水手  他的话会被转达
Tell your sweet sailor his message will be delivered.
格蕾丝  你得学着辨别
Grace, you're gonna want to learn to recognize
根本不存在  都被销毁了
It doesn't exist. It's wiped clean.
估计好久你都看不厌
Don't think you'll tire of that too soon.
滚出我家
Get off my property!
还好
Yeah.
还没到开香槟庆祝的时候
It's not time to pop champagne,
还能信任他们去做什么呢
what can we trust them to do?
还有...
There's--
还有我们和瑞德一起的经历
What we went through with Red.
还有一个
There's one more!
海军生涯让我更了解自己
The navy saw more in me than I saw in myself.
海面被照得粉亮
it lights up the water all pink.
-海员  返航  -是  长官
- Nav, take us home. - Aye, sir.
行动
Let's go.
好
Okay.
Yeah.
好吧  但我希望全体艇员
Fine. But I expect the crew
好吧  选他  把他带去吧
Okay, him. Take him.
好吧
Okay.
好的
好好保护这个岛
to care for it.
何时艇长是打定主意不会改的了
when the captain's made up his mind.
和副艇长山姆・肯德尔所犯罪行
and executive officer Samuel Kendal,
嗨  宝贝
Hi, babe.
很多医务工作者都离开了这座岛
A lot of hospital workers got off this island.
很好
Good.
很神奇
It's magical.
华府向我们下达了发射命令吗
D.C.'s giving us a firing order?
华莱士  冷静点
Hey, cool it, Wallace!
回屋里吧
Come back inside.
或留下听我指挥
"whether to remain under my command
或荣誉遣散
"or to be honorably dismissed.
或许吧
Yeah. Maybe.
或许我们该让他们回家
So maybe we let them.
或许我们可以给他们选择
Maybe we give them the choice.
霍普  躺好别动  兄弟
Hop. Hang in there, buddy.
霍普  挺住啊
Hopper, stay with me!
霍普  兄弟
Hopper, buddy.
霍普
Hop.
吉尔
Gil!
即核武器的优先购买权
the preemptive use of nuclear force.
即将达成的《博尔顿声明》
for what is coming to be called "The Bolton Doctrine,"
几小时之后美国就发动了核轰炸
and a few hours later the U.S. is nuking the joint?
计时开始
The clock starts now.
坚持住  兄弟
Okay, buddy.
见鬼  我现在身处通往世界末日的特快列车
Hell, I got front-row seats to the end of the world.
建议上浮海面进行艇体维修
The recommendation is surface to repair.
鉴于我们当前的处境
"given our circumstances, it is only right
将产生数十亿美元的利润
yielding hundreds of billions of dollars in profits."
将艇载18枚三叉戟核弹之一
fired one of its 18 trident missiles,
接受他人的援助之手
how to accept help when it's offered.
接下来的事情是我们指挥官的错
what was about to happen was our commander's fault.
结束演习
Drill concluded.
截止时间一过  他就说
And once the deadline passed, he said that
截止时间越来越近
As the deadline approached,
今日遭到海军部正式起诉
have been officially indicted today by the department of the navy.
今天按原计划  集合演习
assembled and ready to drill-- today, as scheduled.
今天就和布兰伦和科泰兹谈
Sitting down with Brannan and Cortez today.
今晚在她马里兰州的家门口前
lashed out at reporters tonight
进行安全轮班了
to safely man a shift.
进来
Come in.
就必须知道事情的真相
I need to know what this is really about.
就不那么理想了
is another story.
就跟设计的一模一样
just like it was supposed to,
就开始追踪数据
the minute the "Colorado" left port.
就全完了  别那么做
this thing is over. Don't do it.
就是对彼此的忠诚  就是那样
is our loyalty to each other. That's it!
就要击沉我们的舰艇吗
30 minutes after we picked you up?
就在5天之前  科罗拉多号潜艇
It's been just five days since the "Colorado"
据预测在未来几年中将无限膨胀
is predicted to explode in the coming years,
距离  4000码
Range--4,000 yards.
距离太远  不可能把手雷拿那么久
It's too far. You'll never hold them off that long.
开会
at the Pentagon tomorrow.
开启鱼雷发射程序
Firing point procedures,
开始考虑留下来吗
the boys think twice about turning tail?
看看这个岛
Look at it.
看来我哪都不用去了
Guess I'm not going anywhere.
看起来像是背叛了我的兄弟
It's like I've betrayed my brother.
科利那群人想此事就此了结
Curry and the others want this whole mess to just go away.
可如果他不选的话  我们三个都得死
If he hadn't, it would have been all three of us.
可是他带走了瑞德
but he took Red away,
可是艇员的表现...
But our crew...
克里斯蒂  我是保罗
Christine, it's me-- Paul.
克里斯蒂
Christine!
肯德尔女士  看这里  看这里
Mrs. Kendal, over here! Over here!
肯德尔女士  怎么不说说你的看法
Mrs. Kendal, why won't you make a statement?
肯德尔女士
Mrs. Kendal, what do you think
快点  我们走  加快速度
Come on, let's go, let's go, let's go, let's go!
快滚开
Get off now!
来
Come on.
来对付他们  那么制作样机的人
against them, who better to figure out
离我的人远点儿  尤其是霍普
Stay away from my guys, especially Hopper.
离我远点
Leave me alone!
立刻清舱
I want this deck cleared now!
立正
Ten-hut!
连线怎么样了  山姆
How we doing on that call, Sam?
另外五名队员  包括华莱士
Five other crewmen, including Wallace,
马库斯・查普林艇长"
"Captain Marcus Chaplin."
马库斯・查普林已被认定为
Marcus Chaplin has been deemed
马库斯现在自诩为华盛顿再世了吗
Marcus thinks he's George Washington now?
马上连上了
It's coming online now.
没错  你太重要了  我们不能让你走
You were right. You're too important to let go, Anders.
没人那么想  孩子
No one thinks that, son.
没人能帮上我
there's no one.
没人想  这不是我一个人的想法  长官
None of us did. And I'm not the only one, sir.
没有  长官
No, sir.
没有
No.
没有财产  也不重要
No wealth, no importance.
没有我们他们就得投降  我们就能回家了
Without us, they have to surrender, and we all go home.
每个会极大影响艇员情绪的决定
that will radically affect the disposition of my crew.
每个人都觉得我是个懦夫
Everyone thinks I'm a coward.
每每我朝港口看都能看见船只
And I'd look out there and I'd see those ships.
每名艇员皆应享有选择权利
"that you should each have the choice
每一名艇员都要做出决定
Everyone on this crew needs to decide.
美国公民资格埋下伏笔
their rights as American citizens,
美利坚合众国宪法
the Constitution of the United States
明白
Okay.
命令变了
Orders change.
目前华府局势十分紧张
where tensions remain high.
拿着
Take it.
那边有一半艇员都要放弃了
Half their crew's about to bug out.
那好  我们带上吉尔然后消失
Fine. We'll grab Gil and be out of your way.
那就是我的出路
That was my way out.
那可是国防部长  我不知道该做什么
It's the secretary of defense. I-I didn't know what to do.
那能帮得了你什么
And that helps you how?
那时我就知道
And I knew...
那是不可能的  我已经
Well, that's not possible. I've--
那是我们的钱
That is our money.
那条命令  998
The order. 998.
-那未来是...  -不  我保护了我们家族的未来
- a future that-- - No, I protected our family's future.
那知情不报呢
Well, what about not reporting it?
难道美国采取军事管制
The U.S. under martial law,
难道你没想过为什么你们获救
You ever ask yourself why the "Illinois"
脑子不清楚  我们不能这样杀了他
He's not thinking straight. We can't just kill him.
能让精力集中  我懂的
Keeps the mind focused. I get it.
你爱他  对不对
You loved him, didn't you?
你把我们家族的未来拱手让出
You just handed over our family's future,
你并不孤单
You're not alone.
你不懂
You don't get it.
你不想呆在这儿  不是有去留板吗
You don't like your situation here, there's a "Stay/Go" list.
你不需要担心我
You don't have to worry about me.
你不用选择
You didn't have to choose that.
你承诺要把它发送出去  而不是留下欣赏
You promised to send that, not watch it.
你打算去干什么  山姆
What are you gonna do, Sam?
你打算怎么处理放在我冷藏库的尸体
What are you planning on doing with the body in my refrigerator?
你当然明白  他那些话不是对你说的
You realize, of course, that he's not talking to you.
你当时别无选择
You had no choice.
你到底站在哪边
What do you really stand for?
你的弟兄怎么样了
How's your man?
你的科学技术  化学药品
Your science, your chemicals.
你对你丈夫的行为怎么看
about your husband's actions?
你对珀尔修斯付出了很多
You worked very hard on Perseus.
你个愚蠢的狗娘养的乡巴佬...
you stupid hillbilly son of a--
你还不明白  对吧
You don't get it, do you?
你很快就会觉得好受一些的
It's gonna feel better real soon.
你很快就会看到一些艇员回家了
You're gonna see some of the crew coming home soon.
你将会被严密监视
You're gonna be under a microscope.
你觉得你丈夫是个恐怖分子吗
Do you consider your husband to be a terrorist?
你觉得他会让三等士官来掌管核反应堆吗
You think he's gonna trust some PO3 to run his reactor?
你觉得他是个叛徒吗
Do you feel he's a traitor?!
你觉得我会错过吗
You think I'm missing that?
你今天赢回很多人心  先生
You won back a lot of hearts and minds today, sir.
你就像我刚来的时候
You're like me when I first arrived.
你看见去留板了吗
You saw the "Stay/Go" List?
你看上去很帅
You look good.
你可以解散了  上尉
You're dismissed, Lieutenant.
你可以在检阅前先到达潜艇
You can be on board before the muster--
你肯定可以找到人帮忙的  爸
There must be someone you can talk to, dad.
你肯定已经听说过有人
I'm sure you've heard about the attempt
你来做什么
What are you doing here?
你们必须为我继续履行自己的职责
You will execute your duties for the chief of boat.
你们带着一名伤兵从巴基斯坦匆忙撤离
You guys bug out of Pakistan with a wounded man,
你们的任务是终止他们的统治
Your orders are to terminate command,
你们的政府现在已将他们视作敌对势力
Your government now considers them enemy combatants.
你们都死定了
You guys are all dead.
你们可能不信任艇长
You may not have faith in your captain,
-你们两个跟我来  -是  长官
- You two, come with me. - Yes, sir.
你们俩都穿戴的很整齐啊
Well, look at you two all dressed up.
你们艇长违背了我们的约定
Your captain reneged on our deal.
你们为什么不报道他们
Why aren't you reporting about them, huh?!
你们为什么监视我
Why are you watching me?!
你们为什么要监视我
你们现在是这岛上的主宰力量
You are the power on this island now.
你们在任何时间因为任何原因被分开过吗
Were you ever separated at any time for any reason?
你们中的一个必须付出代价
One of you must pay for his failure.
你那边现在是何情况
What's your current situation?
你男朋友说你需要的一切
Everything your boyfriend said you needed.
你能把这个带出岛吗
You gonna be able to get this off the island?
你确定要这样做吗
Are you sure you wanna do that?
你认为还有其他的原因吗
You think that might have something to do with it?
-你认为我们还能坚持多久  -坐好
- How long you think this is gonna last... - Sit.
你是否单独行动  是否有反抗
Are you acting alone? Is there resistance?
你是个硬汉  霍普
You're a hard man, Hop.
你是说瑞德吗
You talking about Red?
你睡着了
You fell asleep.
你说的每一句话  做的每一件事
Everything you say, everything you do--
你说什么呢  遇到什么不测
What are you talking about? What's gonna happen to you?
你偷了一艘核潜艇  还向我们的国家开火
You stole a nuclear submarine a-and fired on our country!
你为总统做过那么多事
Well, after everything you have done for this president,
你违抗了一个直接命令
You disobeyed a direct order.
你想找队里的人谈话  就找我吧
You wanna talk to someone on my team, you talk to me.
你要坚强起来
You're gonna be unbreakable.
你要这样说的话  听着确实很恶劣
I guess it sounds pretty bad when you put it like that.
-你也是  -你是做了决定
- as were yours. - You've made your decision,
你一切都具备
There you have it.
你以为会怎样  我会蜷缩成一团泣不成声吗
What'd you think, I was just gonna roll up in a ball and cry?
你应该埋在阿灵顿
You deserve Arlington.
你有什么事要告诉我吗  凯希尔
Something you want to tell me, Cahill?
你有什么消息给我
Now what news do you have for me?
你在珀尔修斯系统研发中表现得很出色
You did a wonderful job on Perseus.
你在与权威抗衡
You're standing up to authority.
你在这件事里加入了太多私人感情
You're taking this too personally.
你怎么看待这两件事间的联系
How do you connect the dots?
你这次务必要信任我
You just have to trust me this time.
你真觉得你能打破这份信仰吗
You really think you can break that kind of devotion?
你真幸运  没打碎什么东西
You're lucky you didn't break anything.
你只能照做
you do it.
你只是太固执  尚未认清那一点
You're just too stubborn to see that yet.
你只想要志愿兵吗
You're looking for volunteers?
你知道我怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
你准备好就开拍
Whenever you're ready.
你自尊心强  这很好
Okay, you're proud, that's good,
你做得很好
You did good.
怒斥记者
in front of her Maryland home.
-其实是假的  是吧  -抱歉  你什么意思
- It's a load of crap, right? - Sorry. How do you mean?
牵涉叛国以及针对美国的恐怖行为"
"relating to acts of treason and terrorism against the United States."
签下名字离开不就行了
Why don't you just sign up and leave?
前一秒还好好的
One day everything's normal,
潜艇现已安全
Ship is secure.
欠债就得还
And debts are paid.
情况不是很好
He's not doing so good, man.
请进
Enter.
请问是谁
Who am I speaking with?
请指示
I request instructions.
去床上睡吧
Get yourself to bed.
去或留
Stay, go--
去哪里都比在这里强
Better odds than staying here, man.
去死
Hell with it.
全球强烈谴责
This universal condemnation
全体注意  我是你们的艇长
Attention all hands, this is your Captain.
劝服我花了那么多钱进行测试
when he persuaded me to spend so much of my money to run tests.
却让农民吃蛋糕吗
letting the peasants eat cake?
确实如此
It does.
然而  总统却私下会见了我父亲
Instead, the President personally called my father,
然后他就拿枪指着约什
Then he put his gun on Josh.
然后他就跑了
And then he ran away.
然后我们听到四声枪响
and... we heard four gunshots.
让他们都去死吧
Screw 'em, right?
任何在过去几天内
anything that might have come through
如果没人再朝他开枪  就算他走运了
He'll be lucky if someone doesn't take another shot at him.
如果你对我有所隐瞒  会让我很难办
I can't do my job if you keep me in the dark.
如果你想回家  约什  那件事之后
If you wanted to go home, Josh, after what happened...
如果你要跟我谈话
If you need to speak to me,
如果你愿意  我可以让艇上的医务兵
If you want, I could have one of the corpsman
如果你在"离开"那栏签了名
If you put your name on that "Go" List,
如果他们担心查普林会用我的样机
If they're worried Chaplin is gonna use my prototype
如果他问艇员们是不是想回家
Well, if he asks the men if they want to go home,
如果我们不能信任他们会留下来
And if we can't trust them to stay,
如果我们没发射那颗核弹
And if we hadn't fired that nuke,
如果我要说服他们留下来
And if I'm gonna convince them to stay,
如果我遇到不测
If, uh, something were to happen to me--
如果这是真格的
If this were the real deal,
如果真的有矿产  这个会是绿色
If the minerals were there, this test would be green.
如果真那样  我们就没有足够的人手
If that happens, we're not gonna have enough
如何最好地坚守我们立下的誓言
How do we best uphold the oath we took?
塞拉让我们自己选谁去死
Serrat made us choose who would die.
塞拉特频繁地过来
Serrat would check in more often,
山姆・肯德尔  美军潜艇科罗拉多号副艇长
And Sam Kendal, executive officer of the U.S.S. "Colorado"
山姆被海军停薪了
Navy's cut off Sam's pay.
山姆的父母也帮不上什么忙
and Sam's parents are no help.
上岸给他做个检查
come up from the boat and have a look at him.
上百年来  这个小岛都不为
For centuries, this island wasn't--
上尉  读一下
Read it, Lieutenant.
上尉  干得不错
Well done, Lieutenant.
-上尉  护送他出去  -是  长官
- Lieutenant, escort the chief out. - Yes, sir.
上尉  让潜艇继续航行是个大胆的命令
Keeping this boat moving was a gutsy call, Lieutenant,
稍等
Wait a second.
稍息
At ease.
设定航线驶往封锁区
Set a course for the blockade,
射向我国首都以东200英里海域
detonating it 200 miles off the coast of our nation's capital,
什么会
What for?
甚至考虑到二人为艇上指挥官...
and even allows for the two men in charge of the U.S.S...
士官布兰伦要和国防部长通话
Petty Officer Brannan would like to speak to the secretary of defense.
士官约什・布兰伦在我身边
I'm here with Petty Officer Josh Brannan,
似乎戳到了他的软肋
seemed like it rang his bell.
-试图谋害艇长了吧  -是的  他没事吧
- on the Captain's life. - Yeah. Is he okay?
-是  水手长  -是  水手长
- Aye, C.O.B. - Aye, C.O.B.
是  水手长
Aye, C.O.B.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
是啊
Huh. Yeah.
Yeah.
是单独行动
I'm alone.
是的  长官  明白  炸掉潜艇
Yes, sir, I heard you. Sink the boat.
是个绝对"美好的早晨"
It's a damn fine "good morning."
是海豹突击队害我们遇袭的
that his S.E.A.L. guys got us shot at,
是会这样的
Yeah. That was always coming.
是吗  考虑什么
Oh, yeah? Which is what?
是吗  你现在在干什么
Really? What are you doing right now?
是吗  你知道回去等待我们的是什么吗
Yeah? 'cause you know what's waiting for us back home?
是你们艇长违抗了直接命令
Well, your captain disobeyed a direct order.
是他们不想任何人知道科罗拉多号
They don't want anyone to know where the "Colorado" was
是我的错
It's my fault.
是新任国防部秘书长科利召开的
it's a meeting with the new secretary of Defense--Curry.
是诸多高科技产品的关键  小到手机
key components in everything from cell phones
收到紧急行动指令  长官
Emergency action message, sir.
收到了同样的信息
received the same message.
收到一条信息算不上什么罪行
It's not a crime to receive a message.
恕我直言  它已经放在那里一星期了
I'm sorry. It's just-- it's been there for a week.
谁  是谁更改了命令
Who? Who changed the orders?
-谁的命令  -头衔高于你们的上级
- From who? - A higher authority than you.
谁给你下的命令  华莱士
Who were your orders from, huh, Wallace?
谁知道我们回去会遭遇什么
Who knows how safe things are gonna be for us back there?
说  谁下的命令
Huh? Who were they from?
送上叛国罪的被告席
right to your treason trial.
算了吧
Let it go.
所以才能保留它的美丽
So it was allowed to remain beautiful.
所以你们有责任
So you have the responsibility
所以你说得太对了  我是加入了私人感情
So you're damn right I am taking this personally.
所以你为他奋斗
That's why you fought for him.
所以你暂时和我们在一起
So for now, you're stuck with us.
所以如果我能让女兵们
So I get you the whole female compliment
所以他跟我在一起
He stays with me.
所以我所做的这些决定
So what I've done, the choice I've made--
所有人离开指挥室
Everyone off this conn.
索菲  拜托
Sophie, please...
他不是我的艇长
He's not my captain!
他搞军事演习到底是想干什么
What the hell's he got us drilling for, anyway?
他和你一样  是我的敌人
He's the enemy, just like you.
他很好  我得确保他的安全
He's fine. I want to keep it that way.
他很忠诚
He's a true blue, this one.
他控制了潜艇
who has taken control of the boat.
他拉了保险销
The pin's out!
他们不肯说  但是我知道是
Well, they won't say, but it's a--
他们不停地更改命令
They change all the time.
他们不想让你知道科罗拉多号
They didn't want you to know where the "Colorado" was
他们对科罗拉多号上发生的事满口谎言
They are lying about what happened to the "Colorado"!
They're lying about what happened to the "Colorado"!
他们会再次挺身而出吗
will they raise their hands again?
他们叫我们叛徒
They're calling us traitors.
他们就成功了
they would have succeeded.
他们去打捞牡蛎
They dive for oysters.
他们为什么要偷走我们为他们设计的武器系统
why would they steal the very thing we built for them?
他们想把此事淹没在海底
They want to bury it at the bottom of the ocean.
他们想拿它干什么  他为什么要拿走它
What do they want with it? Why would he take it?
他杀了瑞德吗
He killed Red?
他是对的  长官
He is right about that, sir.
他是我弟弟
He was my brother.
-他是我们的一员  -一旦那颗手榴弹在指挥室引爆
- He's one of us. - That grenade goes off on the conn,
他是因为我才死的
And he's dead because of me.
他无论如何都不会让我回家的
He's not gonna let me go home no matter what.
他先问的我  可我没有选
He asked me first, and I wouldn't do it.
他也在威胁我的潜艇  还有我的弟兄
He's threatening my boat, too. And my men on it.
他已经问过他那些爱将
He's consulted with the military gods he adores so much,
他以为自己刀枪不入
He thinks he's bulletproof.
他早就算计过了
He's done the calculations.
他之前对这一切充满激情
he was so enthusiastic about all of this
他知道那些人留不住了
and he knows he's lost 'em.
它被卡住了
It's jammed.
它从科罗拉多号离港
It began tracking data
它现在是你们的了
And it's yours now.
她有信念  坠入了爱河
Well, she's got faith. She's in love.
太多私人感情
Too personally?
太阳落山时
And when the sun gets low,
提醒我们时间不多了
reminding us that our time was getting short.
提议启动应急吹排水系统
Recommend emergency blow.
天啊
oh, god.
听我说  我跟前面四个人都说过
Okay, look, like I've told the last four people,
听我说
Hey. Listen to me.
听着  很抱歉  但是我不想留在这
Listen, I'm sorry, but I don't want to be here.
听着  科泰兹  你在全艇很有影响力
Listen, Cortez, you hold a lot of sway,
听着  我的战友们就要离开了
Hey, I'm about to lose my crew.
听着  要不是确定我们的选择是对的
Listen, if I didn't know we were doing the right thing,
听着
Listen to me.
Listen.
停止前进
Full stop.
艇上军心动摇
We got a serious morale problem.
艇上每位成员都志愿加入过两次
Every member of this crew has already volunteered twice--
艇员们  立正
Crew, atten-hut!
艇员正在用排水泵进行排水
lined up to de-water with drain pump.
艇长的那个名单
Uh, the captain's list--
艇长和我都很感激你的贡献
The captain and I both appreciate your service.
-退后  别逼我  -后退  后退
- Just get back, damn it! - Stand down! Stand down!
退后
Back away!
陀螺定位系统
built into the prototype.
为什么到这来找我
Why are you here?
为什么要污蔑我的丈夫  你们这群懦夫
Why are you lying about my husband, you cowards?!
为什么又改变主意了
Why the change of heart?
为他的政府贡献那么多
for his administration,
唯一一份价值数十亿美元的系统说明
to steal the only specs of a multibillion-dollar system.
问询是应该的  但不要拘留任何人
Well, they'll be questioned, but no one's getting detained.
我帮不了你了  谢帕德上将  抱歉
I can't help you anymore, Admiral Shepard. I'm sorry.
我保证你的想法是错的
'cause I sure as hell don't.
我本来可能错过很多乐趣啊
Just think the fun I would have missed.
我必须回家  长官
I gotta go home, sir.
我不行了  詹姆斯  救救我
It's bad, James. I need help.
我不会就这么善罢甘休的
I'm not gonna let it go.
我不会扔下任何人
I'm not leaving anyone behind.
我不会是其中之一
I'm not gonna be one of them.
我不觉得我们
You know, I don't think you and I
我不能问怎么运  对不对
I'm not gonna ask how, am I?
我带着敬意  坚决要求你事先知会我
and I respectfully insist that you inform me of any decision
我得跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you for a minute.
我得跟你谈谈约什的事
I have to talk to you about Josh.
我得回家
I got to get home.
我得考虑长远些
I'm taking the long view.
我得找个地方把我朋友放下
I need a place to keep my friend
我的车没油了  食物也吃光了
There's no gas in my car, no groceries.
我的错
I did it.
我的姐姐  她得抚养孩子  所以...
My sister-- she's got the kids, so...
我的名字被挪地方了
My name's been moved.
我的名字会和其他人一样
my name would be on that "Go" List,
我的母亲  身体不是很好
My mom--she's not well, and...
我的人就守在附近
My men are nearby.
我都有按时付款
all of my payments are current.
我发过誓要保卫我的国家
I swore to defend my nation!
我关机了
Yeah, I turned my phone off.
我还有
I got...
我和吉尔一起出过三次任务
I did three tours with Gil.
-我很抱歉  瑞德  -约什  科泰兹
- Red, I'm sorry! - Josh! Cortez!
我会保证其执行
and l'll see that it's carried out.
我会陪你走过每一步  好吗
And I'm gonna be there every step of the way. Okay?
我会找人治好你的  万珀  照顾好他
I'm gonna get you fixed up. Viper, stay with him.
我几乎就要发了
And I almost did.
我将像往常一样登艇  和全艇成员一起
and I'll board the way I always have--with my crew.
我觉得他们以吗啡抵价获取离岛的船票
I think they paid you in morphine for their tickets out.
我就想当海军
I saw in the damn commercials, you know?
我就站在这
I'm standing right here.
我看上去还行吗
Do I look okay?
我没事
I'm fine!
我没想参与这件事
I didn't sign up for this.
我们16点整开始检阅
We muster at 1600,
我们被关在同一间屋子里  双手绑在背后
We were all held in the same room with our hands behind our backs.
我们彼此承诺过
We made each other promises.
我们不能总让他们忍下去
We can't keep asking more of them.
我们查了家庭电报
We've been through the familygrams.
我们打算拘留他们  进行问询
We'll detain them all for questioning.
我们得马上撤出去
We gotta leave right now!
我们的存在
Our mere presence
我们的国家是在抗争中建立的
Our country was founded in protest,
我们的政府遭到盟国的谴责
our government condemned by our allies.
我们改变了一些事  是吗
I guess we changed things a bit, didn't we?
我们根本就不应该在这
We shouldn't even be here!
我们还是失去了很多好艇员
Still, we're losing a lot of good people.
我们很有可能顺利逃生
there's every likelihood we'd all still be alive.
我们会损失3/4甚至更多的人
We're gonna lose three-quarters or more.
我们将再次操练鱼雷攻击方案
We will commence torpedo attack scenario once again.
我们绝不能引火上身
so we are going to sit this one out.
我们祈求
We begged,
我们提前10秒完成了演习任务
We shaved ten seconds off our time.
我们为什么杀了那家伙
Why did we kill that guy?
我们无法保证你的安全
We can't guarantee your safety.
我们先护送你上船吧
Let us get you a ride to the boat.
我们相当敌对  长官
We couldn't be farther apart, sir.
我们需要你的帮助
We could use your help.
我们也许得在这待一阵子
We may be here a while.
我们一起出生入死
We went through buds together.
我们一起离开这里
and get the hell out of dodge.
我们已经掌握了详情
We've put together a detail.
我们有船  所以带上吉尔的尸体和霍普
We have a boat. Let's grab Gil's body and Hopper,
我们在这里最宝贵的精神
The one thing we have out here
我们之前说的不对
It wasn't like we said.
我们只能这样
And that's just what we're gonna do.
我能拿几个箱子"
and how many bags can I take?"
我取了很多样本
I took many samples.
我确定
I know it.
我让你来选一个
I will let you choose who.
我让他们怎么做呢
And what would I ask them?
我认为你高估了愿意留下的人数  长官
I think you overestimate how many of them will stay, sir.
我是本舰上有权接触核武器的高级长官
I'm the senior nuke-rated chief on this boat.
我是队长吉尔・兰斯顿  谢谢你们的支援
Gil Langston, Captain. Thank you for the pickup.
我是国防部长科利
This is secretary of defense Curry.
我是一名美国公民  我不会保持缄默
I am a U.S. citizen, and I will not be silenced!
我受够你了  乔纳西
I'm sick of you, Jonesy!
我说到做到
Count on it.
我为那项工程累得半死不活
I worked my ass off on that project.
我为你骄傲
I'm very proud of you.
我喜欢你不代表我懦弱
Don't mistake my affection for you for weakness.
我现在不能做这个
I can't do this now.
我相信他们会的
I believe they will.
我想让你看看这个  这样你会明白
I wanted you to see this so you would understand.
我需要掌握任何信息
I need to know about any messages--
我要跟你说句话
I need a word.
我要和国防部长通话
I want to talk to the secretary of defense.
我要和科利通话
I want to speak to Curry.
我要接管这艘潜艇  长官
I'm taking control of this boat, sir.
我要拿回这艘潜艇  还给我的国家
I'm taking back this boat and returning it to my country,
-我要你约见... -已经安排好了  长官
- I want you to set up interviews with-- - Already done, sir.
我要寻求真相  你们也当如此
I want the truth, and you should, too!
我也不对贝类过敏
I'm not allergic to shellfish, either.
我一直都信任你
Always.
我一直清楚这点
I've always known that.
我一直在给你打电话
I've been trying to call you.
我以为我已经明确地表过态了
I thought my feelings on this subject were pretty clear,
我有话跟艇长说
I need to talk to the captain.
我有家事急需处理
I have family issues I need to attend to.
我原本服役3年期满光荣退伍
I'm supposed to be on the downhill run of a 3-year enlistment,
我在想办法让真相大白
I am trying to bring the truth out into light.
我在指挥台  拿着手雷
I'm on the conn. I have a grenade.
我真幸运  我是不可或缺的
Lucky me. I'm indispensable.
我只会扳弯东西  不会打碎东西
I bend, I don't break.
我只能通过这种方式和你联络了
This is the only way I could get you a message.
我只是  真心觉得我得留在这
I just--I feel it in my heart that I have to stay
我只是担心他
I was worried about him--
我只是在执行命令
I was acting on orders.
我只想当一名海军
That's all I ever wanted.
我只想让你知道
Just so you know,
我只想再检查一下索具
I'm just double-checking the riggings.
我知道
I know.
Oui, je sais.
我知道我很爱国
I know, I know. I get patriotic.
我知道这很难  但你的朋友应该被安葬
I know it must be hard, but your friend deserves better.
我最后一次和你说话  所以...
I-I can get to you for a while, so there's...
我昨天收到的
I received it yesterday.
无线电信号  加密信息
radio signals, coded communications,
无疑是帮助他们反击的最佳人选
how to help them defeat it than the people who made it?
稀土矿物类的全球市场上
"...Global markets in rare earth minerals,
洗耳恭听
I'm listening.
系统把数据都传输回来了
it transmitted all that data back home
下次再需正当防卫时
Given a just cause,
下一秒却甚至连吃的都没了
and then the next you can't even eat.
现在  我向你保证
Now, I grant you,
现在华盛顿很多大人物都如坐针毡
There are a lot of nervous powerful people in Washington right now,
现在你们欠我的债  索菲
Now there is a debt, Sophie.
现在却闹成这样
and now all of this?
现在我有个朋友比你更需要那玩意儿
Now I got a friend that needs that joy juice more than you do.
想要击沉我们的就是自己人
Our own people just tried to kill us,
想坐就坐下吧
It's okay if you want to sit down.
向前进
Forward march.
向右转
Right face.
小时候我家搬到了一个环境很差的城市
When I was a kid, we moved to a pretty rough town.
小心枪
Gun!
小子  你再说一句  就跟我干一架吧
One more, and you're gonna have to throw with me, son.
谢帕德上尉  你接管指挥台
Lieutenant Shepard, you have the conn.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
谢谢
Thanks.
信用卡被注销了  我没有任何积蓄
Credit cards were canceled. I have no savings.
兄弟  现在你要帮我理清这堆乱麻
Now, buddy, I need your help figuring out this mess.
需继续履行当前职责
will be required to continue executing their duties
需要送往医院
Needs a hospital.
需要我怎么做  长官
What do you want me to do... Sir?
选择离开者
"Those choosing to leave
演习的目的不是变得优秀
We don't drill to be good.
演习结束
Drill concluded.
样机上面装有
There's a gyroscopic positioning system
要求他支使我男朋友
had him get my boyfriend
也许艇长知道一些你不知道的情况
Maybe the captain is aware of something that you're not.
也许我的演讲该更好
Maybe if I'd made a better speech.
也要通过正常的行政管理流程
you will do so through the proper chain of command.
一个不落
All of you.
一个小时前就修理完毕了
Had this fixed an hour ago.
一号和二号鱼雷发射管  准备发射
tubes one and two, prepare to fire.
医院的工作人员都已经跑了
but most of the hospital staff have abandoned ship.
医院里没有吗啡了
Hospital's out of morphine.
已经和艇员们沟通过了
So we've talked it through the crew.
因此我才把名单张贴在 休息舱的舱面上
That's why there's a list... up on the mess decks.
因为如果总统要你去做某件事
Because when the president asks you to do something,
因为是我让他那样做的
Because I told him to.
因为我要执行命令
Because those were my orders.
赢得了最高呼声
across the country today.
尤其是在女兵们中间
especially with the female enlisted.
有本事当面说我是叛徒  你们这些骗子
Come out here and call me a traitor to my face, you liars!
有多人持武器与我对峙
There's an armed party on the conn,
有人收买了跟我上床的男人指使他偷走
Someone got the man that I was sleeping with
有人通知我明天在五角大楼
I've been asked to attend a meeting
有人洗劫了药品供给库
Someone raided the supply cabinet.
有什么事吗  布兰伦先生
Can I help you, Mr. Brannan?
有什么损失你们赔偿
You're paying for the damage.
有手榴弹
Grenade!
有谁单独和塞拉特相处过吗
So neither of you spent any time alone with Serrat?
有些事你必须知道
something you need to know.
有意思  继续关注他
That's interesting. Stay on him.
佑护你们行动成功
and bless this endeavor.
于是你就让一颗暴躁的定时炸弹在艇上
So you let a time bomb fester on my boat.
鱼雷舱  请报告进度
Torpedo room report.
鱼雷舱的堵漏问题已解决
Flooding in torpedo room is secure.
鱼雷舱的水位已控制到安全标准
Flooding in the torpedo room is secured.
鱼雷舱进水了
Flooding in the torpedo room.
鱼雷多久后接触我艇
Time to impact?
鱼雷将于五秒后撞击
Torpedo five seconds to impact.
与此同时
Meanwhile,
愿上帝让你们心中充满爱国热忱
May god fill you with patriot zeal,
约什  到底怎么了  告诉我
Josh, what's going on, man? Talk to me.
约什  放轻松  孩子
Josh, take it easy, son.
约什  我明白
Look, Josh, I get it.
约什  我知道你被俘的经历有如炼狱
Josh, I know you went through hell when you were captured.
约什  现在潜艇上有120条命
Josh, there are 120 souls on this boat right now.
约什选了瑞德
He picked Red.
再也不会了
Not again.
在"留下"那栏签名  男士们就能瞬间
up on your "Stay" list, all of a sudden
在那儿向海军当局投降
where you will surrender to naval authorities.
在全国范围内
...Met by mostly cheers
在早晨  当地的女孩们会下山来
In the morning, the local girls come down.
在知道他们的立场之前  不能让他们上艇
We can't have them on the boat until we know where they stand.
责任和忠诚让我们何去何从
What do duty and honor dictate we do?
怎么会这样
How does this happen?
-炸掉潜艇  -放下枪
- Blow it. Sink the boat. - Lower your weapons.
詹姆斯  霍普醒了
James. Hop's waking up.
战斗准备
Battle stations.
长官  请指示
Sir, what are my orders?
长官  是斯特恩・瑞德曼
It's Seaman Redman, sir.
长官  我要将潜艇带到封锁区
Sir, I'm taking the boat out to the blockade.
长官
Sir...
-找到水手长  -是 长官
- Find the C.O.B. - Aye, sir.
这不是正确选择
this is not the answer.
这才叫保卫你的国家
That is how you defend your nation.
这才是我的乖女儿
That's my girl.
这岛大得很  给我继续找
It's a big island. Keep looking!
这地方曾是流亡之地
This place was exile,
这个过程残酷无情
It's gonna be relentless and vicious.
这件事很难说谁对谁错
it's pretty damn hard to fathom what's right or wrong here,
这可不是我说的
You didn't hear it from me.
这里确实很有意思  但也是时候离开了
Hey, it's been fun, man, but it's time to go.
这里位置很好
It's a nice spot.
这里有些事情
There are things here
这里真的应该缝一针
This could really use a stitch.
这么敌对  真的
are that far apart, really.
这事你本可以在电话里跟我讲的
Look, you could have told me this on the phone.
这是给他妻子的  不是供你娱乐的
It's meant for his wife, not for your amusement.
这是什么时候发来的
When did this come through?
这无关乎去与留
It's not stay or go.
这些问题我已经回答了
Now I've answered those questions for myself,
针对艇长马库斯・查普林
in regards to criminal charges against captain Marcus Chaplin
真的  很美
Ah, it's just... spectacular.
-真是大胆之举啊  -是啊
- Pretty ballsy move. - Yes, it was.
整个事件你能接受了吗
You feeling better about all this?
政府拘押了我
The government detained me!
只会得到一个回答  "船在哪儿
the only answer he's gonna get is, "Where's the boat
直到安全返美途径
"until such a time as safe transit back to the United States
直到能带他回家
until I can get him home.
直到枪响瑞德一直尖叫
Red was screaming right up until the gunshots.
直接开口要就行了啊
They could have asked.
指挥台  我是副艇长  无法堵漏
Conn, X.O. cannot secure flooding.
指挥台  鱼雷舱的堵漏问题已解决
Conn, torpedo room flooding has stopped,
至少不能让他们继续执勤了
A-at least let me take them off the duty roster.
中国在台湾海岸进行了海军演习
China conducted naval drills off the coast of Taiwan, which--
铸就了现在的我
made me into the man I am today.
准备迎接爆炸震荡
Prepare for impact.
准备应战
Get ready to fight.
自从诉讼提起后  来电从未间断
It's been ringing nonstop since the indictment.
棕色肌肤  比基尼上衣
Brown skin, bikini tops.
作为副艇长
I'm the X.O. Of this boat,
做好准备向他妈自己人开战吗
Firing against our own damn people.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译：圈圈  Silmar  不悛熊  Ethan  我不是青椒  萌Su
翻译：allen0314  狂舞之鹤    校对：米苏  宁馨儿  Ethan
时间轴：贝壳   GGwhywhy   Cherry   米苏
后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
《破釜沉舟》前情回顾
-山姆  山姆  是你吗  -是我  我没事
- Sam! Sam, is that you?  - It's me. I'm okay.
不管你听说了什么
Listen to me. I don't know what you've heard,
我都可以解释
but I can explain it all.
我得先安全回家
I just need to get home first.
马库斯・查普林已被认定为
Marcus Chaplin has been deemed
不适宜继续指挥  副艇长也一样
unfit for command, as has his X.O.
你们的政府现在已将他们视作敌对势力
Your government now considers them enemy combatants.
你们带着一名伤兵从巴基斯坦匆忙撤离
You guys bug out of Pakistan with a wounded man.
几小时之后美国就发动了核轰炸
And a few hours later the U.S. is nuking the joint?
你怎么看待这两件事间的联系
How do you connect the dots?
马库斯・查普林宣称  科罗拉多号收到的
Marcus Chaplin claims that the nuke order
核弹发射命令来自南极紧急通讯网
sent to the "Colorado" came through the Antarctic Network.
在这件事中  你有得天独厚的条件
You're uniquely qualified to do something about this.
得天独厚的条件  就是拿我自己的人头冒险
Uniquely qualified to risk my own ass
去救你的宝贝女儿是吧
to help you save your daughter?
你真觉得你能打破这份信仰吗
Really think you can break that kind of devotion?
她有信念  坠入了爱河
Well, she's got faith. She's in love.
但这些都是可矫正的
Those things are curable.
政府拘押了我
The government detained me!
特大新闻
海军叛徒之妻克里斯汀娜袭击媒体记者
他们对科罗拉多号上发生的事满口谎言
They are lying about what happened to the "Colorado"!
我是一名美国公民  我不会保持缄默
I am a U.S. citizen, and I will not be silenced!
煽动叛乱  叛国  恐怖主义
Sedition, treason, terrorism.
更别提你还偷了一艘美国战舰
Not to mention you stole a U.S. warship
向华府发射了一枚核弹
and fired a nuclear weapon to Washington D.C.
我是为了保护我的艇员
To prevent American b-1 bombers
不受美国B-1轰炸机袭击
from annihilating my crew,
-保护成千上万无辜的平民  -你现在是
- and thousands of innocent civilians! - You are currently
强制扣押141名艇员
holding 141 U.S. sailors against their will,
其中还有71名正式签名要求
71 of whom signed a list formally requesting
在此岛解除他们的职务
that they be relieved of their duties on this island.
科利不知道这件事
Curry doesn't know that.
他们都有家庭  有妻子
These men have families, sir. They have wives.
还有孩子
They have children.
军人家庭都明白...
Military families who knew precisely--
他们没想要参与这样的事
They didn't sign up for this!
现在我们还是在角色扮演吗
Are we still role-playing here?
模拟辩论是你的主意  如果不管用的话
The mock debate was your idea. If it's not useful...
很管用  好好想想
It is useful. Ask yourself,
为什么他们突然愿意谈判了
why the sudden willingness to negotiate?
中国大陆正对台湾剑拔弩张
China's rattling her sabers over Taiwan.
美国政府可不想因为我们
And our little distraction is the last thing
这边的事分心伤神
that this administration needs.
我们只有这一次机会扭转局势
We have one shot to get this right.
两小时后  你就要面对面
In two hours, you'll be face-to-face
和国防部长威廉・科利谈判
with Secretary of Defense William Curry,
此人非常奸诈狡猾
who happens to be an extremely cunning son of a bitch.
控制好你的情绪
Control your feelings,
否则科利会借此对付你
or I guarantee Curry will control them for you.
我的咖啡豆只够维持两周了
I only have beans for two more weeks.
所以你想跳楼的话
So if you're going to jump,
拜托请等我喝完那些咖啡
please wait until I finish my cafe.
不了  我不喝
No, I'm okay.
我明白  不用说了
I know. Don't say it.
我看起来像个卖冰淇淋的小商贩
I, uh, I look like an ice cream man.
我本来是想说
I was going to say
或许别人对制服男的看法是对的
perhaps it's true what they say about a man in uniform.
有人要来造访了
Well, company's coming.
艇长想演场戏  所以...
Captain wants to put on a show, so...
我觉得这挺好的  双方以和谈的形式
I think this can only be good. You'll talk, they'll talk.
他们想要回潜艇  你们想回家
They want their submarine, you want to go home.
事情没那么简单
It's not that simple.
打扰  长官
Excuse me, sir.
女士  我想你应该下来看看
Ma'am, I think you should come down here.
你在这儿真是太好了
I'm glad you're here.
貌似我们有大麻烦了
We seem to have a bit of a catastrophic problem.
你不是说我们的咖啡喝完了吗
I thought you said we're out of coffee.
什么事
What is it?
31阵列出问题了
Array 31 pegged out
北部边界一半瘫痪
and took down half the northern perimeter.
什么意思  他在说什么
What does that mean? What's he talking about?
看到绿点组成的弧线了吗
You see that string of green lights?
那是我们的声纳阵列
That's our sonar array line.
主要防止潜艇偷袭
It keeps submarines from sneaking up and killing you.
-看到断掉的那段了吗  -看到了
- Now, you see that part that's off?  - Yeah.
也就是说那部分  关闭了
That means that part is, uh, you know, off.
我是副艇长
This is the X.O.
紧急集合  准备战斗
Man battle stations. Man battle stations.
26英里处42射击点可能有敌人入侵
Possible enemy contact 26 miles from range point 42--
那不是袭击
It's not an attack.
稍等  待命
Hold that order. Stand by.
你说什么
Excuse me?
上个月阵列就该换电池了
The array was supposed to have its battery serviced last month.
是因为没电了  你在开玩笑吗
I-it's a dead battery? Are you kidding me?
你们需要多久能换好
How long will it take for you to fix?
阵列在水下300英尺处
The array's 300 feet below the surface, man.
不归我们换
We don't fix it.
那是谁换
Who fixes it?
美国海军
The United States navy.
需要我给你电话号码吗
Should I get you the number?
我要和艇长去谈判
I'm gonna be with the captain in negotiations.
你来接管科罗拉多号
So you're gonna take the "Colorado"
还有一个分遣队
and a small detachment.
需要潜水员  工程师
Diver, engineering,
-声纳  无线电  -是  长官
- sonar, weps--  - Yes, sir.
我们完全有理由认为
Listen, we have every reason to believe
只是电池没电了
that this is just a dead battery.
但是刚巧是和科利一行前来的同一天
But the same day that Curry and his entourage arrive,
所以我们不排除其他可能
we can't rule anything out.
准备好第一次指挥了吗
So, you ready for your first command?
准备好了  不会让你失望的  长官
Aye, aye. Won't let you down, sir.
我知道  解散
I know you won't. Dismissed.
终于让你自己真枪实战了
Daddy finally let you take the car out of the driveway?
别担心  长官
Don't worry, sir.
我会帮忙看着她的
I'll keep her out of trouble.
-他在哪里  -詹姆斯吗
- So where is he?  - James?
我又不是他的保姆
I'm not his keeper.
帮我给金士官带个话
Well, maybe you could get Petty Officer King a message for me.
一个边界水下声纳阵列出故障了
A critical underwater sonar array has failed.
我的任务是带领人去维修
And I'm tasked with leading the repair operation.
所以我需要一名优秀的潜水员
So I need a diver-- a good one.
要接受过水肺潜水训练的
One who's trained in trimix--
你需要记下来吗
Do you want to write this down?
好吧  他队内两名海豹突击队员
Fine. Two of the S.E.A.L.S in his unit,
费舍和沃格勒都有深水独潜资格
Fisher and Vogler, are certified deep solo.
我需要詹姆斯告诉我谁更优秀
I need James to tell me which one's best.
-你开玩笑吧  -看  找到他了
- You are joking, right? - Oh, look, I found him.
沃格勒都没下过250英尺
Vogler's never been below 250.
那么就是费舍
So Fisher it is, then.
-你没必要这么做  -非做不可
- You don't have to do this. - But I do.
如果美国海军知道声纳阵列出了问题
If the U.S. Navy finds out the array line's down,
会派50个你这样的家伙
They'll drop 50 guys just like you
趁我们熟睡时敲破我们的脑壳
to double-tap our skulls while we sleep, so--
你需要潜水员
You need a diver.
-我就是  -你自告奋勇
- I'm a diver. - You volunteering?
我以为你不管他们的事了  詹姆斯
I thought you were done with these people, James.
8点整出发  带好装备
We leave 0800. Get your gear.
知道吗  海豹突击队的人就是这样
You know, that's the thing with these S.E.A.L. boys.
为了刺激什么都敢做
They'll do just about anything for a thrill.
正是科利
That's Curry, all right.
12名带M4的宪兵
Looks like we got 12 M.P.s with M4s.
长官  你一定不敢相信
Sir, you're not gonna believe this.
白宫顾问阿曼达・斯昭
White House adviser Amanda Straugh.
很好  看来我们得到了总统的高度关注
Good. It seems we have the president's full attention.
不  看左边
No. Pan left.
格蕾丝的父亲跟来搞什么名堂
What the hell is Grace's father doing here?
他们以为我是钟楼里的持枪歹徒
Oh, they think they're dealing with a gunman in a bell tower.
带位老友来劝降
They brought an old friend to talk me down.
你们大家都忧心忡忡  挂念家人
There's not a man among you who's not worried about his family,
不知事件如何收场
and how this is all gonna end.
我对你们的命令很简单
My orders to you are simple.
不要
Don't.
不要让这些人看到你们的疑虑
Don't show these people your doubt.
惟有团结一心  我们才有力量
We are only as strong as we are unified,
惟有不露声色  才能一致对外
and only as unified as we appear to be.
让他们看到我们的决心
Show these people our resolve,
今天我们大家就有回家的机会
and there's a chance for all of us to go home today.
你们都听到了  列队
You heard the man! Fall in!
我带来你们总统的口信
I bring a message from your president.
任何不愿继续参与
Any person who no longer wishes to be a party
这场叛国行径者
to this treasonous act,
现在出列
step forward now.
我们会保护你
We will protect you.
很好
Very well!
是你们自取灭亡
So shall you hang.
上将
Admiral.
马库斯在哪儿
Where's Marcus?
他正等着你们
He's waiting.
格蕾丝很好  长官
Grace is fine, sir.
抱歉  我们没想到你会来
I'm sorry. We didn't expect you to be here.
她正在潜艇上
She's currently embarked on the sub.
谁负责指挥
Who's in command?
情况汇报  水手长
Sit-rep, Master Chief.
我有疑问  长官
Interrogative, ma'am.
我的潜艇上为什么会有法国妞
Why is there a French girl on my boat?
她对此次任务至关重要
She's vital to the mission.
莫非我们打算撤退
Are we planning a retreat?
-有没有情况汇报  -有  长官
- Do you have a report or not? - Yes, ma'am.
水手长报告  他从前划独木舟上也比这人手多
C.O.B. reports that he's crewed canoes with more men than this.
现在是通讯官在负责导航
We've got our communications officer piloting the boat.
6个非专业人员兼顾武器和机械
We have six non-quals spread in between weapons and engineering.
或许能够勉强航行  或者作战
Maybe we can run, maybe we can fight,
但是想要边跑边打  却比登天还难
but we sure as shinola cannot run and fight.
谢谢  水手长  没事了
Thank you, Master Chief. That'll be all.
希望你们有带浮圈
Hope you folks brought your water wings.
没别的事了 水手长
That will be all, C.O.B.
格蕾丝  就算你在指挥台上站到审判日
Grace, you can stand on that conn till the rapture comes.
你仍旧不会是我的艇长
Still don't make you my captain.
凯希尔先生  深度310英尺
Mr. Cahill, make your depth 3-1-0 feet,
俯角10度  注意空泡
10 degree down angle. And watch your cavitation.
栅栏倒了  可能有不速之客
The fence is down. We may have uninvited guests.
俯角10度  收到
10 degree down angle, aye.
正在通过海沟  长官
Passing the trench now, sir.
我是说  女长官
I mean, ma'am.
都可以的  凯希尔先生
Either will do, Mr. Cahill.
你认为你们能坚持多久  马库斯
How long do you expect to hold out here, Marcus?
一个月  两个月  四个月
A month? Two? Four?
当然  你的队伍正在减员
Of course, you're losing people left and right.
多久之后  余下的下伙子们会不再听你指挥
How long before the rest of these boys turn on you,
反戈哗变
break out the piano wire?
他们会的  等雨季一来
Because they will. After the monsoons.
遍地洪水  闹起饥荒
Fields flood, starvation starts.
你到底是不是带着解决方案来和谈的
Did you come with an offer or not?
和谈  我是来处理麻烦的
An offer? I came to clean up a mess.
你们朝自己祖国的首都发射一枚核弹
You launched a nuclear missile at your own country.
你们未经宣战就向巴基斯坦发射了两枚
You detonated two in Pakistan without a declaration of war.
你们把战斧导弹射向己方...
You fired a Tomahawk missile at your own--
违抗直接命令的叛变潜艇  没错
At a rogue submarine in contravention of direct orders, yes.
非法  未经确认的直接命令
Direct, unlawful, unconfirmed orders.
我确认过
I confirmed them!
我说的是权威人物的确认
I meant by somebody with authority.
别跟我谈你古怪的是非观
Do not talk to me about your quaint ideas of right and wrong.
我们来这里不是因为你们的原则  小子
We are not here because of your principles, son.
我们来  是因为你们的渎职
We are here because of your failure--
你们未能履行职责  执行命令
to do your duty, to follow orders,
没做到转动钥匙按下按钮这样简单的事
to simply turn a key and press a button.
天呐  找对黑猩猩都比你们俩更能胜任
My God, a pair of chimpanzees could do what you conot.
你要我的解决方案
You want my offer?
我的解决方案就是
My offer is this--
叛国罪
treason.
山姆・肯德尔  马库斯・查普林
Sam Kendal, Marcus Chaplin,
格蕾丝・谢帕德
Grace Shepard,
及当日指挥台上所有军官
and all officers present on the conn that day
将接受军事法庭审判
will appear before a military tribunal.
我的艇员呢
What about my crew?
联邦监狱服刑7年
Seven years each in a federal penitentiary.
不得假释
No parole.
我们愿意放弃死刑制裁
Now, we are willing to forego the death penalty
因为考虑到
in light of the circumstance
查普林艇长之子杰弗里不幸阵亡
regarding the unfortunate death of captain Chaplin's son Jeffrey.
你想要我死  想封住我的嘴
You want me dead, you want to silence me,
想杀光我的船员
you want to kill my crew?
你有过机会  王八蛋  你错过了
You had your shot, you son of a bitch! You missed!
你看清楚了  我不是政客
Look closely. I am not a politician.
你敢再提我儿的名字
If you say my son's name again,
我发誓  我就把你的眼珠子打出来
I swear I will crush the jelly from your eyes.
好了  冷静  冷静
Okay. Easy, easy, easy.
冷静点
Easy!
别激动
Easy.
把枪放下  没事了
Get them down. We're okay.
没事了  没事了
We're okay. We're okay.
没事了
We're okay.
他的情绪不对  山姆
He's not well, Sam.
你还有很多值得珍惜的东西
You still have something to live for.
别把希望都寄托在一无所有的人身上
Don't tie it all to a man with nothing to lose.
你不是说应该"不动声色"吗
What the hell happened to "Show no emotion"?
你打破了自己制定的规则  我想...
You're breaking your own rules, sir. I'd like--
长官
Sir!
他惹怒我了
He pissed me off.
他惹怒你了
He pissed you off?
可现在他是唯一一位
That is the one man right now
有权力送我们回家的人
who has the power to send us all back home!
是送我们进监狱
To send us to prison.
这是在谈判
It's a negotiation!
双方各退一步  达成妥协
We give a little, they give a little.
-我知道怎么谈判  -真的吗
- I know how it works. - Really?
因为你刚才的表现  实在是太...
'Cause the man I saw in there seemed completely--
继续说  说出来
Go on. Say it.
长官  服五年  六年徒刑  我都能接受
I could do five years, sir. I could do six.
-闭嘴  -只要能让我们回家
- Stop it! - If it gets us back home,
只要不再有人员伤亡  我就愿意服刑
and no more people die, I could do it!
那就是你想要的结局吗
Is that how you want this to end?
不是想要  是除此之外别无他法
It's not what I want, it's what I can get.
谁曾经那样教过我
Who taught me that?
我还教过你  荣誉高于一切
And what did I teach you about honor?
你知道只要你开口  我定会至死忠随
You know I will follow you all the way down if you ask.
可是长官  你别指望他们向你道歉
But the apology you want is not coming, sir.
他们是代表美国政府来交涉的
That is the United States of America in there!
而美国政府从不道歉
And they do not apologize!
一定要时刻注意你的氧气剩余量
Pay close attention to your air reserves.
注意好绳索
And watch the tether.
那是我们唯一的纽带
It's our only communication.
如果绳索被切断  一定要保持深度
If you lose the tether, maintain your depth.
因为如果任凭水流带你上浮得过快...
If the current drags you up too quickly--
我就会被压扁  关节会炸开
I get bent. My joints explode.
脑子里全是血栓  我见过那种惨状
My brain embolizes. I've seen it.
我又不是第一次参加牛仔竞技了
This isn't my first rodeo, okay?
孩子  她恐怕不知道牛仔竞技为何物吧
She don't know what a rodeo is, kid.
-法国也会举办牛仔竞技啊  -不可能
- Oh, we have rodeo in France. - Nah.
真的  牛马满场奔腾  牛仔精彩献艺
Oui. Horses, cows, cowboys.
法国根本没有牛仔  女士
There's no such thing as a French cowboy, lady.
法国人就是牛仔的反义词
French is the opposite of cowboy.
牛仔是像威尔・罗杰斯
Cowboy is like Will Rogers,
约翰・韦恩和克林特・伊斯特伍德那样的真汉子
John Wayne, Clint Eastwood.
三人均为美国演员  以饰演牛仔而闻名
罗伯特・杜瓦尔也算吧
Robert Duvall?
美国演员  以饰演牛仔而闻名
你终于明白我的意思了
Now you're getting it.
杜瓦尔是法国人
Duvall is French.
收回你刚才的话
You take that back.
我们要到达声呐阵列处了
We're coming up on the array now.
每个人都要保持警觉  坚守岗...
I want everyone sharp, at their stat--
你不是要用这把电钻吧
Tell me that's not the drill you're using.
是啊
Yes.
那可是把手提钻
It looks like a jackhammer.
电池外壳上的螺栓足有10英寸长
The bolts in the battery casing are 10 inches long.
不行  给他找把扳手来  水手长
No. Get him a wrench, C.O.B.
要是用扳手  没等我拧下第一枚螺钉
A wrench? I'll suck down my first tank
我的第一瓶氧气就该耗光了
before I pull the first screw.
你只要在海里启动电钻  10英里内的潜艇
You rev that thing out there, and any sub within 10 miles
就会向我艇发射MK48鱼雷
is gonna put a Mark-48 torpedo in our ear hole,
造成艇毁人亡的后果
and we'll all be dead.
为什么没有事先请示我
Why wasn't I told about this?
查验执行任务所需的装备是艇长的工作
It's the job of the captain to review all the mission assets.
我在半小时前刚接任了代理艇长一职
I was assigned this mission half an hour ago.
好吧  就用电钻  但动作要快
Fine. Use the drill, but make it quick.
什么
What?
你得好好考虑清楚  上尉
You need to think this through, Lieutenant.
你这么刚愎自用
You let your ego drive the boat,
会把我们害死的
people will get dead.
你之前答应过我格蕾丝不会
You said Grace wouldn't be charged
与马库斯和山姆一起遭到起诉
along with Marcus and Sam.
我们会为你女儿减刑
And we'll reduce the charges against your daughter
前提是你说服艇长接受我们的条件
when you convince the captain to accept our terms.
我与马库斯相识已有30年之久了
I've known Marcus for 30 years.
他是个坚持原则的人
He will stand on principle.
无论我说什么  都无法改变那一点
Nothing I can say is going to change that.
伊利诺斯号的巴特勒艇长向我报告说
I have a message from Captain Butler of the "Illinois".
他发现对方的的声纳阵列有个缺口
He believes he's found a gap in their sonar array line.
他还需多久就能定位并击沉科罗拉多号呢
How long before he finds the "Colorado" and sinks her?
那艘潜艇上可都是美国的水手
Those are American sailors on that submarine.
有人则认为他们是一群罪犯
Some say they're criminals.
虽然我并不愿意下达发射命令
Now I won't enjoy giving the fire order,
但若到了紧要关头  我不得不发
but when the time comes, I will give it,
换成你  也会这样做
just as you would.
好好劝劝你的朋友  让他妥协吧
So convince your friend to settle.
我到达声纳阵列了
All right, I'm on the array.
很好  系好绳索
Good. Secure the tether.
我要开始计时了
I'm starting the clock.
预计空气余量
能见度100英尺  看不到艇体
Vis 100 feet. Can't see the boat.
我们就在你的正下方  詹姆斯
We're right below you, James.
开始修理吧
Proceed with repair.
先取出电池外壳上的螺栓
First remove the bolts from the battery casing.
该死  谁听见了
Damn it. Who heard that?
谁都能听见  长官
Who didn't, ma'am?
噪音已传遍
We have noise propagation
温跃层上下15英里的区域
above and below the thermal for 15 miles.
全体注意  好戏开场了  我们成了活靶子
All right, people, it's a party, and we just became the pinata.
金士官  请用你最快的速度完成
Petty Officer King, as fast as you can, please.
-是  长官  -你是想害死我们吗
- Aye, ma'ma. - Are you trying to get us killed?
难以置信
Unbelievable.
肯德尔先生说你们有条件要提
Mr. Kendal says you have an offer?
我和我手下的军官要上法庭
I want a trial for me and my officers.
你们肯定会被送上军事法庭秘密审理的
Secret court-martial can certainly be arranged.
你误会了
You misunderstand.
我要求在民事法庭公开审理
I demand a public trial in a civilian court
全程录像  陪审员列席
cameras, jury,
并且赦免我手下的全体艇员
amnesty for my enlisted men.
我看你真的是疯了
You really have lost your mind.
你还说他是认真的  肯德尔
Y-you said he was serious, Kendal.
除非你们先答应这些条件
And only after you've agreed to those terms
我们才愿意商谈在巴基斯坦海岸
will we discuss the six
搭载那六名海豹突击队员的事
navy S.E.A.L.S I picked up off the coast of Pakistan.
一定是这海边空气的原因
Must be all this ocean air.
让我感觉非常饿
I'm famished.
我们先暂停去吃个午饭吧
Shall we break for lunch?
疯子以为这是场游戏
Lunatic thinks this is a game.
伊利诺斯号已经穿越了边界
The "Illinois" is through the perimeter.
两艘688i潜艇归航
Two 688i's inbound.
追捕到它
Hunt her down.
你一找到那艘潜艇  就立刻通知我
I want to know the moment you find that sub.
詹姆斯  检查一下水压
James, check your pressure.
收到  再拆一个螺栓
Copy that. One more bolt.
詹姆斯  你得加快速度了
James, you need to hurry.
或许他们没听到
Maybe they didn't hear it.
或许他们在另一片区域
Maybe they're in another sector
没有...
and they didn't--
发现新目标  2艘688潜艇
New contact--2 688-class subs
方位0-7-1度
bearing 0-7-1,
距离16000码
range 16,000 yards.
16000码  还很远
16k? They're too far away.
运气好一点
With a little luck,
我们很快就可以撤退...
we'll be outhere before they fi--
发现新目标  弗吉尼亚级
New contact-- Virginia Class.
我们的挡音区声纳有反应  长官
Much have come out of our baffles, ma'am.
是伊利诺斯号  已经很近了
It's the "Illinois." She's close.
你必须命令下潜了  上尉
You gotta dive the boat, lieutenant.
不  他还在外面呢
No! He's still outside!
探测到主动声纳  它在搜寻我们
Active sonar. She's looking for us.
立刻下潜
Dive the boat now.
安静  我知道自己在干什么
Quiet! I know what I'm doing.
如果我们下潜  他必死无疑
He's dead if we dive!
目标正在靠近  航向1-4-9度
Contact coming about. Heading 1-4-9.
格蕾丝
Grace.
舵手  左满舵  紧急下潜
Helm, left full rudder! Emergency deep!
下潜吧  凯希尔先生
Take us down, Mr. Cahill.
詹姆斯  切断绳索  詹姆斯
James, cut the tether. James?
收到请回复  切断绳索
Do you copy? Cut the tether.
什么  不  没有绳索我就完了
What? No. I'm screwed without the tether.
别那么做
Don't do it!
不要
No!
超过测试深度
Passing test depth.
等等  他切断绳子了吗
Wait. Did he cut loose?
我们目前在1400英尺海下  索菲
We're at 1,400 feet, Sophie.
如果他还连着  就必死无疑  安静点
If he's attached, he's dead. Now be quiet.
凯希尔先生  在1500英尺深度停下
Mr. Cahill, all stop 1500 feet.
让潜艇悬游待命
Hover the ship.
我们在水中制造出一个空洞吧
Let's make like a hole in the water.
长官  我侦测到两个  是三个目标
Ma'am, I'm tracking two-- make that three contacts
在交错深度频繁发射脉冲
pinging actively at staggered depth.
搜寻模式  他们已覆盖我们所在范围了
Search pattern. They got us covered.
现在我们若移动  只有死路一条
We move now, we die.
半个中东都在进行武装斗争
Half the Middle East is up in arms.
在巴林  阿曼  阿联酋都出现暴乱
Riots in Bahrain, Oman, U.A.E.
中国海军在台湾岛附近聚集
China's navy is amassing around Taiwan.
而我的语音信箱里全是那些议员们
And my voicemail is full of congressmen
在抱怨8美元的气价
bitching about $8 gas.
或许下次你们再用核武器攻击别国前
Maybe next time you guys nuke a country,
该三思一下
you'll think it through.
木已成舟
Well, it happened.
现在重任压在你我这样的人身上
And now it's up to people like you and me--
负责任的人
responsible people.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
马库斯・查普林的妻子死于癌症
Marcus Chaplin's wife died of cancer.
一个儿子在阿富汗阵亡
One son K.I.A. in Afghanistan,
另一个儿子跑去拯救鲸鱼了
the other son ran off to save the whales.
已经多年没跟马库斯说过话了
Hasn't talked to Marcus in years.
当一个男人失去一切  剩下的就只有目标了
When a man loses everything, all he has left is his cause.
你自问一下
So ask yourself--
他的目标  依然和你的一样吗
Is his cause still the same as yours?
里面再见了
I'll see you inside.
山姆  我是来达成协议的  那就是我的工作
Look, I make deals, Sam. That's all I do.
而我见到的那个男人  他根本不想合作
And the man I see-- I can tell you he doesn't want one.
他只想殉难
What he wants is martyrdom.
仔细观察他  你也会发现的
Watch him. You'll see.
我从没想过我们会用上那些武器
Oh, I-I never thought we'd use those weapons.
不会再用了
Not again.
现在已经用了  我却连原因都不清楚
Now that we have, I don't even know why.
两天前  有81个国家
Two days ago, 81 countries moved for
在联合国大会上对美国发起了正式谴责
a formal condemnation of the United States on the floor of the U.N.
在华盛顿  几乎有一半的前参谋长
In D.C., I have almost half of the former joint chiefs
打算强行让总统下台
ready to forcibly remove this president.
他们都指望着你  坚守住这个岛
And they're all counting on you to hold fast on this island
等待合适的时机
until the time is right.
成为他们所编故事中格格不入的一环
To be part of the story that doesn't fit--
活生生的谎言的象征
the living, breathing symbol of the lie.
我曾经想过成为各种人  亚瑟
I've wanted to be a lot of things, Arthur,
却从未想过成为一个象征
but a symbol was never one of them.
是吗  但命运使然
Oh, yeah? Well, we don't get to
我们也无能为力  不是吗
choose our fate, do we?
如果我今天有机会带着我的艇员们回家
If I have a chance to bring my people home today,
我可能会欣然接受
I may have to take it.
我也想要我的女儿回家  马库斯  真的
Yeah, well, I want my daughter home, Marcus. I do.
但我不知道我们的国家将会变成什么样
But I don't know what that home is becoming.
不  我不需要预约
No, I don't need a reservation.
那一直都是我的桌子  就那张
That's my table always, right there.
那张桌已经有人预约了
That table's reserved.
我知道有人预约了  就是留给我的
I know it's reserved. It's reserved for me.
我想跟罗格里奥谈谈
I would like to speak with Rogelio.
我在这儿等着
I'll wait.
失陪了
Excuse me.
你跟我上床
So you sleep with me,
然后趁我洗澡时  偷走了我的硬盘
and then you steal my hard drive while I'm in the shower.
那意味着你"搞"了我两次啊
That makes two times you screwed me,
我现在仍难以判断  哪个更让人失望
and I'm still not sure which was more disappointing.
-嗨  米米  -嗨  凯莉
- Hi, Mimi. - Kylie. Hi.
去补点粉吧
Catch a powder,
不然我让你永远无法出席全城各种社交活动
or I'll erase you off every guest list in the city.
米米・凡德霍特
Mimi Vanderholt?
那包挂在她身上都嫌掉价
The girl is an accessory to her own handbag.
你就是不知道什么时候该闭嘴  是吧
You just don't know when to stop, do you?
你让事情回到正轨我就罢休
I'll stop when you make this right.
帮我拿回我的数据
Help me get my data back.
你就不能跟其他人一样顺从合作吗
Why can't you just play along like everyone else?
因为其他人都是
Because it turns out everyone else
卑鄙的伪君子
is a backstabbing hypocrite.
你原先也一样卑鄙和虚伪
You were a backstabbing hypocrite.
我就喜欢你那一点
I liked that about you.
怎么变了
What happened?
太晚了  你已经出局
It's too late. You're out.
你已经变得和我们不一样了
You just went from being us to being them.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
不好意思
Excuse me?
把你的手拿开
Get your hands off me.
能跟我离开吗  女士
Could you come with me, ma'am?
现在就走
Now.
这边请
This way.
他们对科罗拉多号上发生的事满口谎言
They're lying about what happened to the "Colorado"!
我是一名美国公民  我不会保持缄默
I am a u.S. Citizen, and I will not be silenced!
我要寻求真相  你们也当如此
I want the truth, and you should, too!
潜艇军官夫人狂怒
怎么一直播这疯女人的视频
They ever gonna stop showing this nut job?
你们为什么不报道他们
Why aren't you reporting about them, huh?
政府拘押了我
The government detained me!
他们满口谎言...
They are lying about--
没完没了  对吧
It's never gonna stop, is it?
对
No.
这才是痛苦之处
That's what makes it so hard.
我理解你的感受  发现所爱之人
I know what it's like to find out the person we love
并不像你所想的那样
isn't who we thought they were.
这是什么
What is this?
这什么意思  "潜在买家"
What does this mean, "potential buyer"?
政府掌握了山姆和马库斯・查普林之间
The government has 32 e-mails that are encrypted
32封加密邮件往来
between Sam and Marcus Chaplin,
详述了他们向中国叛变
detailing their plan to defect to China
并卖掉科罗拉多号的计划
and sell the "Colorado."
不可能  山姆绝不会
That's insane. Sam would never do--
不知不觉中我们会失去很多人
We can lose somebody and never know.
他们离开  然后回来
They go away, they come back,
但内心有一部分却再也回不来
some part of them doesn't return.
他们会保守的一些秘密
Some part that they kept secret,
-绝口不言  直到...  -够了
- maybe even to themselves, until the moment-- - Stop.
够了  别说了
Please just... Just stop.
山姆之前从朝鲜回来后
Sam was different when he came home
就不一样了  不是吗
from North Korea, wasn't he?
小时候经常这么玩
Used to do this when I was a kid.
恐怖角  我爸爸脾气不好
Cape fear. My daddy was a crab man.
难以相信
I find that hard to believe.
哪一点  是说我出身平凡吗
What, that I come from humble folk?
是你曾是个孩子
That you were ever a child.
你不像你表现出来的那么讨厌我
You know, I think you like me more than you let on.
不是吗  我还挺喜欢你的
No? Well, I like you.
甚至我心里还有点敬佩
I think some part of me even admires
敬佩你想做的事
what you're trying to do here.
在世界上开辟出自己的一片领地
Carving out your own little piece of the world.
这是你想要的吗
Is that what you want?
因为我可以满足你
'Cause I could give that to you.
你知道我想要什么
You know what I want.
老天  你还真固执
God, you're a stubborn man.
你就想上法庭
You want your day in court.
你知道那边现在什么情况吗
Do you have any idea what's happening out there?
你开启了一场争夺  马库斯
You got the ball rolling, Marcus.
所有人都虎视眈眈
It's all up for grabs now--
同盟关系风云变幻  边界问题逐渐展现
Alliances shifting, frontiers opening up.
你们准备向台湾派遣第三支舰队
You're moving the third fleet towards Taiwan.
够用吗
Will it be enough?
你完全可以使用
Suddenly you could use
封锁这个岛的舰队
the ships you've got blockading my island.
你只需要给我一个机会
All you have to do is give me the chance
让我在公开法庭上说出真相
to tell the truth in open court.
我们都忙着重塑世界
We are reshaping the face of this planet,
你居然要求站在台上
and you want to stand on a soapbox
说什么真相
and plead for the truth?
你觉得这样你就是英雄了  做梦
You think that makes you a hero? It doesn't.
这让你看起来像个傻瓜
It makes you a fool.
因为最终
Because in the end,
真相由我们书写
the truth is gonna be whatever we say it is.
而这个地方  你  还有那些人
And this place, you, these people
只会成为小小的脚注
are gonna be a little footnote
存在于这个"一个分裂的国家如何
in a story about how a broken nation
在自由的指引下重新成为了
asserted itself in the cause of freedom
一个伟大的帝国"的故事里
and became a great empire once again.
你们对巴基斯坦所做的事
What you did to Pakistan...
有没有想过历史会如何评判
Do you ever wonder how history will judge you?
天呐  这里景色真美  不是吗
God... It's so beautiful here, isn't it?
长官  你确定要在这种时候打盹吗
Sir, are you honestly taking a nap right now?
科利知道拖延会让对方紧张
Well, Curry knows that delay heightens tension in one's opponent.
而紧张会导致不确定
Anxiety begets uncertainty.
山姆  你得试着呼吸
You really should breathe, Sam.
我在呼吸  我在呼吸
I'm breathing. I am breathing.
我还想继续呼吸下去
I'd like to keep it that way.
这给我们时间怀疑
It gives us time to doubt the possibility
期望目的达成的可能性
of our desired outcome.
一旦怀疑  就会退而求其次
We doubt, we settle for less.
那我们到底什么时候点头
And when exactly do we say yes?
我们的底线是什么
What's our bottom line?
你明知是什么
You know what it is.
我想听你亲口说出来
I want to hear you say it.
回家
To go home.
他们来了
They're coming.
什么事  亚瑟
What is it, Arthur?
出事了  无线电通信频繁
Something's up. There's a lot of radio chatter,
斯昭正在通卫星电话
and Straugh's on the sat phone.
我女儿还在海里
My daughter's out there.
你女儿已经成为一个能力卓越的军官  亚瑟
Your daughter has become a very capable officer, Arthur.
她处理得了
She can handle it.
抱歉  推迟了这么久
My apologies for the delay.
我带来了一份提议
I have with me here an offer.
很好
Very well.
总统先生宽宏大量
Your President was feeling generous.
他已授权
He has authorized...
别回应
Don't react.
操作员报告说  格蕾丝最后停留的位置
The E.W.S. reports three fast attack submarines
曾被三艘快攻潜艇包围
circling Grace's last known position.
如果他们发现她了
If they've found her--
如果他们发现她了  我们早就死了
If they had found her, we'd already be dead.
我们让您扫兴了吗  艇长
Are we boring you, captain?
是啊  但我在听
Yes. But I'm listening.
预计空气余量
空气余量只能维持九分钟了
He's got nine minutes of air left.
仍在探测主动声纳  长官
Still searching active sonar, ma'am.
一旦探测到我们的艇壳反射回波
They bounce a ping off our hull.
他们马上就会下来将我们彻底击沉
They're gonna come down here and punch our clock for good.
只是早晚的事
It's just a matter of time.
情况我了解了  水手长  谢谢
I know the score, C.O.B. Thank you.
詹姆斯还在上面
James is still up there.
他可能还活着
He could be alive.
如果我们现在转到詹姆斯方向
If we make a break for James now,
那些攻击潜艇很可能会发现我们
there's a good chance those attack subs hear us.
到时候就插翅难飞了
I can't outrun them.
我们要等他们撤退
We wait for them to bug out.
你认为你能掌控生死吗
You think you can decide who lives and who dies?
你又不是上帝
You're not God.
在这艘艇上  我就是
On this ship, I am.
如果还有谁不满意的话
And if anyone else has a problem with that,
欢迎站出来指正
you're more than welcome to step outside.
以前做过紧急排水  凯希尔
Ever blown the tanks on a boomer, Mr.Cahill?
没在这个深度试过  长官
Not from this depth, ma'am, no.
你能行的
You'll do fine.
密切监测水平仪
Just watch your bubble.
一会可能会有碎片
There'll be some debris.
长官  碎片
Debris, ma'am?
如果潜艇能上升到发射深度
If we can get this boat up to firing depth,
我们就要动点儿真格的  逼他们撤退
we show them our teeth, we force them to back off.
水手长  让你的手下准备好鱼雷管
Chief of the boat, you tell your men to ready torpedo tubes
四枚全部待发
one through four in all respects.
本舰无法与快速攻击型潜艇对战
You can't shoot it out with fast attack submarines.
需要我重复一遍命令吗
Do you need me to repeat the order?
不用  长官
No, ma'am.
很好
Good.
怎么了
What's happening?
艇长勇气倍增
Captain's got sand in her swimsuit,
正带领我们走去天堂
so we're all headed to the le gran rodeo in the sky.
预计空气余量
你们这帮抛弃我的混蛋可能听不见
You runaway bastards probably can't hear me,
但是电池组已安装完毕
the battery packs are going in now,
那么...不用谢
so... you know, you're welcome.
我会在这儿等人来接的
I'll just be here waiting for my ride.
真好吃
That is really good.
不用说违心话
You don't have to say that.
说真的呢  真的很好吃
No, I mean it. Really, that's really good.
谁教你做饭的
Who taught you to cook?
-我妻子  -你结婚了
- My wife. - You're married?
不是  只是没办法说出"前任"这个词
I'm not. I just can't bring myself to say the "ex" part yet.
-抱歉  -没关系
- Sorry. - That's all right.
两年前我离婚了  必须学着喂饱自己
Two years ago. Had to learn how to feed myself.
其实  得学着做很多事
Learn how to do a lot of things, actually.
没想到自己会那么依赖一个人
It's surprising how much you can come to rely on someone.
堂娜离开后
When Donna left,
我花了很多时间重拾自我
took me a long time to remember who I was.
很奇怪  你竟然能如此痴迷一个人
It's strange, you can fall so far into a person
连自我都丧失了
that you just sort of disappear.
你一直在围着他们打转
You kind of become the space around them,
他们离开后  你不禁要问
and when they leave it's like,
"她就那么走了
"Well, now that she's gone,
我到底算什么”  你懂的
do I even exist?" You know?
如果你想  我可以留下来陪你
I could stay the night if you want.
不是你想的那样  我是说住在客房..
N-not like that. I-I just meant in the guest room
-如果你...  -你不该问的
- If--if you...  - You can't ask that.
是啊  我知道  对不起
Yeah, I know, I... I'm sorry.
你一个人没问题吧
You'll be all right here?
那就好
Okay.
我已经尽力在帮你了
I've tried to help you here.
总统先生已经给了你们一条体面的出路
The president's given you an honorable way out.
这位总统先生根本没明白我的意思
This president doesn't know the meaning of the word.
你可要三思啊  长官  人命关天
Be careful, sir. You are dealing with people's lives.
事实上  我倒觉得我们的存在
In fact, I imagine our presence here
很碍他老人家的眼啊
has become rather inconvenient for him.
也碍你们的眼
For all of you.
我们的总统先生现在的支持率是68%
Our president currently enjoys a 68% approval rating, so--
可不是嘛
I'm sure he does.
老布什1991年2月28号
George Bush I won Desert Storm
获得沙漠风暴行动的胜利
on 28 February 1991.
21个月之后  他就下台了
21 months later, he was voted out of office.
所以别跟我说选票  我要公正的审判
So don't talk to me about polls. I want my trial.
你觉得会有人相信一个叛徒的话吗
And who do you think's going to believe a traitor?
我可握有整个阴谋的铁证啊
Oh, I have hard evidence of the whole sordid thing--
我的海豹突击队新朋友告诉我的
from my new navy S.E.A.L. pals.
撒谎  你根本没有
No, you don't.
你真应该把握时机杀了那些海报突击队员
You should have killed those S.E.A.L.s when you had the chance.
你的船员和初级军官可以免罪
Amnesty for your crew and junior officers.
你要归还我的潜艇和海豹突击队员
You return my submarine, my S.E.A.L.S.
你和副艇长就违反第92条军规进行认罪
You and the X.O. plead guilty to a violation of Article 92.
两年的保护性监禁
Two years protective custody.
不行
No.
-长官  我们能暂停商量一下吗  -不行
- Sir, can we take a break and discuss... - No.
18个月
18 months.
-艇长  -我要求公审  科利先生
- Captain... - I want a public trial, Mr. Curry.
那是不可能的
That's never gonna happen.
谈判结束了
So be it.
我会请来各大媒体  揭露你和
I'll invite the cameras here and try you
这位缺席总统的劣行
and the president in absentia.
你要来吗
You coming?
你到底想不想回家了
Did you ever give a damn about getting home?
山姆  如果你有意见
Sam, if you have objections--
也许你无家可归了  但我有
Maybe you have nowhere to go, but I do.
你的船员们也不是
And so does your crew.
难道为了你那该死的真相
And, what, you're just gonna let them all burn
就要他们都跟着陪葬吗
for the sake of your damn truth?
我的真相
My truth?
是我的真相吗
My truth?!
山姆  新条件  把潜艇还给我
Sam, new offer. Get my boat back,
我保证你和格蕾丝・谢帕德
and I promise you and Grace Shepard
将免受牢狱之灾
will never see the inside of a prison.
我还将保证你和你娇妻的安全
I will guarantee your safety in the country of your choice
无论你们定居在哪个国家
with your beautiful wife.
别让他把你拉下水  山姆
Don't let him drag you down with him, Sam.
这已经是最优厚的条件了
Doesn't get better than this.
成交
You got a deal.
你立字为据  我还你潜艇
You put that in writing, you got your sub back.
成交  走吧  快  我们走
Deal. Let's get out of here. Come on! Let's go!
我是艇长
This is the Captain.
我父亲曾告诉我
My father once told never never to bet
别拿自己输不起的事打赌
more than I was willing to lose.
现在  你们都知道我的想法了
By now, you all know my intentions.
就是与敌交战  这会使舰艇陷入困境
I mean to engage our enemy and put this vessel in harm's way.
艇上所有人也都会有危险
Every life on this boat will be at risk.
这样做我输不起
It's more than I'm willing to lose.
但我不是在拿这舰艇下注
But I'm not betting on this boat,
我把赌注压在你们身上  因为水手们
I am betting on you, because you sailors
我相信你们
are a sure thing.
继续
Carry on.
他们来了
Here they come.
距目标2800码
2,800 yards to target.
凯希尔  听我口令超速前进
Mr. Cahill, all ahead flank on my mark.
行动
Mark.
20节  21节
20 knots. 21.
-22节  -正形成空泡
- 22 knots. - We're cavitating.
这什么意思
What does that mean?
意味着我们要发动攻击
That means company's coming.
凯希尔  仰角30度
Mr. Cahill, up angle, 30 degrees.
发现目标  方位1-1-7度
Contact, bearing 1-1-7,
预计空气余量
距离5000码  正在靠近
range 5,000 yards. She's coming about.
-行动吧  凯希尔  -是 长官  23节
- On your horse, Mr. Cahill. - Aye, ma'am. 23 knots.
加油  宝贝
Come on, girl.
水手长  请到控制台
I need you up here, C.O.B.
发现新目标  距离4100码
New contact, 4,100 yards!
是伊利诺斯号  方位2-1-3度
It's the "Illinois." Bearing 2-1-3.
长官  它在搜索我们
Ma'am, she's acquiring.
你是故意激怒我的
You provoked me.
想要我反抗
You wanted me to react.
没错  为了有个好结果
Yes. To get the best deal.
让你和格蕾丝能够回家
To get you and Grace home.
我还以为我们相互信任呢
I was under the impression that we trust each other.
我相信你的直觉  山姆
I trust your instincts, Sam.
只有把我们搞分裂了  科利才会完全同意
Curry was never gonna go all the way unless he could split us.
谈判就是在演戏
Negotiation is theater.
我要确保你的情绪看起来是真的
I had to be certain your emotion would be read as real.
是真的
It was real.
我知道
I know.
第1349号总统密令
Secret executive order number 1349.
这肯定能让你满意的
I trust you'll find it to your liking.
我们不在乎你去哪
We do not care where you go.
不在乎你做什么
We do not care what you do.
但要是泄漏出一点点这几周的事情
But if you breathe a word about any of the events of the past week,
这项协议将作废
this agreement shall be void,
你也将被捕
and so shall you.
这些条件你接受吗
Can you abide by these terms?
我接受
I can.
你将立刻被遣回  羁押直至海军法庭审判
You shall be remanded immediately to our custody for court-martial.
我愿意
I'll go willingly.
我只有一个条件  允许我与我的艇员告别
I ask only that I be allowed to address my crew.
当然可以
Of course.
-你在做什么  -协议终止
- What are you doing? -This offer has expired.
-什么  -部长先生
- What?! - Mr. Secretary.
不好意思  你们要去哪  我们说好的
Excuse me, where are you going? We had a deal!
-到底怎发生了什么  -我也不知道
- What the hell just happened? - I don't know.
巴特勒艇长可以火力解决科罗拉多号
Captain Butler has a firing solution on the "Colorado."
他正在等你的命令
Awaiting your order.
杀了它  现在就杀了它
Kill her. Kill her now.
巴特勒艇长  我是阿曼达・斯昭
Captain Butler, Amanda Straugh.
认证口令0-1-2-2
Authentication 0-1-2-2--
别开枪  别开枪
Hold your fire! Hold your fire!
快  快
Come on. Come on!
伊利诺斯号正在待命
"Illinois" is standing by.
请确认开火命令
Awaiting confirmation of fire order.
我们现在可以发射  长官  长官
We have the shot now, ma'am. Ma'am?
伊利诺斯号正在靠近  距离3000码
"Illinois" Closing. 3,000 yards.
下潜  仰角30度  舵手  右满舵
Dive, 30 degrees up angle! Helm right full rudder!
给它点颜色看看
Shake that son of a bitch.
正向我们右舷船尾30度方向驶来
Coming about 30 degrees off our starboard quarter.
肯定会让我们没命的  长官
He's got us dead to rights, ma'am.
距离多少
Distance to target?
-1400码  长官  -躲不了了
- 1,400 yards, ma'am. - We're not gonna make it.
至少我们不会死在岸上
At least we won't die dry.
-距离目标1300码  -为什么他们还不开火
- 1,300 yards to target!  - Why haven't they fired?
-机械故障  -两艘同时吗
- Mechanical failure. - On both ships?
或许他们不想欺负小女孩
Well, maybe they don't want to hit a girl.
-你老婆怎么还愿意跟着你  -我会计划
- How did you ever stay married? - Stayed deployed.
保持1200码  两艘都在我方后部
Maintaining 1,200 yards. Both contacts still back there!
没人会这么走运  有人在给我们争取时间
Nobody's this lucky. Somebody bought us time.
别浪费这时间了  开一二三号鱼雷门
Let's not waste it. Open doors one, two, and three.
是  门已打开
Aye, aye. Doors open.
接近目标  长官  我们受到攻击了
Closing on target. Ma'am, we got a shot.
鱼雷准备  听我口令
Ready torpedoes. On my order.
给我无线电
Ahh! I need a radio!
Get me a radio!
巴特勒艇长  我是国防部长威廉・科利
Captain Butler, this is secretary of defense William Curry!
我命令你发射
I order you to fire!
发射
Fire!
鱼雷已发射  锁定目标
Torpedoes away. Target acquired.
长官  伊利诺斯号刚打开了鱼雷门
Ma'am, "Illinois" Just opened her doors.
它要发射了  伊利诺斯号鱼雷已发射
She's gonna shoot. "Illinois" Torpedo in the water!
-一发射就激活了  -我们的鱼雷到哪了
- Went active right out of the gate. - Where are my fish, C.O.B.?
还有7秒
Seven seconds to impact.
目标进入范围
5  4  3  2
Five... Four... Three... Two...
One.
左满舵  仰角20度
Left full rudder, up angle 20 degrees!
凯希尔  驶向爆炸点
Take me into the debris, Mr. Cahill!
左满舵  仰角20度  遵命
Left full, up 20, aye!
皮茨  鱼雷都在哪
Chief Pitts, where are those torpedoes?
正在扩大搜索  长官  我们摆脱了
Tracking wide, ma'am. It's lost us.
停舵  承压水舱全部急速排水
Helm all stop! Emergency blow all main ballast tanks!
600...
550...
450  注意排水  注意水平仪
450... Secure the blow! Mind your bubble!
300  200  到达发射深度
300... 200 feet. Approaching firing depth.
声纳探测目标  对方是否还在追踪
Sonar, contacts? Are they tracking?
没有  长官  安全了
Negative, ma'am. It worked.
他们在下面绕圈
We left them down there circling the plume.
艇体保持水平  打开导弹舱门
Level off. Open my missile doors.
准备极高频通信
Stand by for E.H.F. transmission.
圣玛丽娜区域内所有舰艇请注意
Attention to all forces in the area of Sainte Marina.
我是核动力弹道导弹潜艇科罗拉多号的艇长
This is the captain of the S.S.B.N. "Colorado."
你们在卫星上也能看到
As you can see on your satellites,
我舰武器舱门已开
our doors are open,
有四枚核弹已瞄准华府随时准备发射
and we have four nukes spun up and aimed at D.C.
请调走你们在200里无人区内的兵力
Kindly remove your forces from the 200-mile perimeter.
多谢合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
预计空气余量
我有枪
I have a gun.
抱歉突然闯进来
Sorry about the pop-in.
只有这样才能躲开前门的新闻采访车
Only way to dodge the news vans out front.
-你到底是谁  -凯莉・辛克莱
- Who the hell are you? - Kylie Sinclair.
我相信是政府设计
I believe the administration
陷害您丈夫的  肯德尔夫人
set your husband up, Mrs. Kendal.
只要你愿意帮我  我就能证明
And if you're willing to help me, I can prove it.
你喝咖啡吗
You want some coffee?
还有生命迹象吗
Any sign of life?
没有  长官
No, ma'am.
预计空气余量
我曾在苏比克[菲律宾城市]
I used to drink with this senior chief
和一个叫迪斯科的老水手长喝过酒
at Subic named Disco.
我们一定是喝遍了
We must have hit every
奥隆加坡[菲律宾城市]的烈酒
hooch hole in Olongapo,
直到有一天迪斯科在爆棚吧
till one night Disco fell in with this little honey-ko
偶遇他的小亲亲
from the boom boom bar.
我不是在说所谓的闪婚
And I'm not talking some 4-day marriage.
我说的是实实在在的爱情
I'm... I'm talking actual, factual love.
真动人  水手长
That's beautiful, C.O.B.
结束单身后  迪斯科破了产
End of liberty, Disco was flat broke,
他的亲亲想和他一刀两断
and honey-ko was gonna cut him off,
可我是个浪漫的人
but I'm a romantic.
所以我告诉迪斯科  只要他把头埋进
So I tell Disco I'll give him 10 bucks
锦鲤池里  每分钟我会给他十美金
for every minute he holds his head in the koi pond.
花了我五十块
Cost me 50.
这个故事的重点是什么
Is there a point to this story?
重点是  他曾是海军海豹突击队的
Point is, he was a navy S.E.A.L.
听  你们听到了吗
There! Did you hear that?
长官
Uh, ma'am...
我想也许是
I think maybe...
敲打声
Tapping?
很微弱  但是
Very faint, but...
没错
Yes!
是摩斯密码  50码深
That's morse code. 50 feet.
-左舷  20度  -按此方向
- Port side, 20 degrees. - On that heading!
停车  准备救援
All stop. Stand by to retrieve.
他在说什么
What's he saying?
你不会想知道的  长官
You don't want to know, ma'am.
你具体是做什么的
So what is it you do, exactly?
重要的是我做过的事
It's what I did that matters.
我在山姆的潜艇上安装了一个罕有的设备
I put a very unique piece of equipment on Sam's submarine,
并且我相信这个设备
and I believe this equipment recorded information
记录下的信息  是某些
that certain powerful people would like
权势之人想极力掩饰的
to keep very secret.
那这些信息在哪儿
So where is it?
被偷了  被某个帮政府
Stolen... by a secret cabal
掩盖事实的秘密组织偷了
as part of a government cover-up.
相信我  我很确切地知道
Trust me, I know exactly...
我信你
I believe you.
很好  因为我想让这些坏人
Good, because I intend to flush every one of these rats
全都无所遁形
into the light.
不过有个问题
But here's the thing.
我目前的权限有点受限
My, um, access is a bit limited at the moment.
所以我才需要你加入
So that's where you come in.
你想让我怎么做
What do you want me to do?
你希望你制造点新闻
I want you to make some noise.
我知道这一切对你来说有多可怕
I know how frightening this must all be for you.
没关系
All right.
我不会要求
I wouldn't ask--
我说过没关系  交给我
I said all right. I'll do it.
我也有条件  我的律师保罗・威尔斯
But I want something, too. My lawyer, Paul Wells--
他是山姆的知交  他还一直
He's an old friend of Sam's, and he's been...
尽其能地陪我度过难关
amazing helping me through all this.
-好啊  -不过他是政府
- Okay. - But he's a government agent
派来监视我策反我跟山姆敌对的特工
sent to spy on me and turn me against Sam.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
女人的第六感
Because the other woman always knows.
事实是  我婚姻中的每一天
The truth is, I've shared my husband
都在与人共享我丈夫
every single day of this marriage.
山姆・肯德尔深爱着自己的祖国
Sam Kendal is in love with his country,
无论顺境与逆境  无论疾病与健康
for better or worse, in sickness and in health,
他永远不会背叛她
and he would never betray her.
不为钱财  没有什么能改变他
Not for money. Not for anything.
甚至是我
Not even me.
科罗拉多号汇报任务已完成
"Colorado" reports mission accomplished.
潜艇及全体人员安然无恙
Ship and all hands in good condition.
准备下锚
Ready to anchor.
空气耗尽你还憋了六分钟
I clocked you at six minutes past reserves.
你怎么办到的
How did you do that?
我只是告诉自己的身体不拼就是死路一条
I just told my body you'd left it for dead.
当时那是个艰难的决定  金
It was a tough call, King.
真高兴你归队了
I'm glad you're back.
有多艰难
How tough?
立正
Ten-hut!
长官到
Officer on deck!
他们想沉了潜艇  长官
They tried to sink the sub, sir.
他们闯过了200英里无人区边界
They broke the 200-mile line.
是的  没错
Yes, they did.
我们该如何回应
So how are we gonna respond?
不回应
We're not.
一位高级内阁顾问今天
A senior white house adviser
在这里遇害了  长官
was killed here today, sir.
部长本人也挨了一颗枪子
The secretary himself took a bullet.
不  他没有  科利很清楚游戏规则
No, he didn't. Curry knows the game.
除非有万无一失的准备
Never admit to being attacked unless you're prepared
千万别承认受到了袭击
to pay the price for your response.
所以  这事从未发生
So... this never happened,
他们也从没来过
and they were never here.
你要怎么跟格蕾丝说她父亲的事
What are you gonna tell Grace about her father?
若是你  你希望我怎么说
How would you want to hear it?
直奔主题快速解决
Straight up and quick.
艇长接管指挥台
Captain on the conn.
除了我和谢帕德上尉  都请离开指挥台
Please give Lieutenant Shepard and me the conn.
格蕾丝  我要和你谈谈你父亲的事
Grace, this is about your father.
我们提前打烊了
We're closing early.
我就想你这么说
I was hoping you'd say that.
你走了好久  比我
You were gone longer than I...
能喝的时候就喝吧
Drink it while you can.
《破釜沉舟》前情提要
那条情报是错的
The intel is all wrong.
我们做了什么  我们杀错人了
What did we do? We killed the wrong people.
你们带着一名伤兵从巴基斯坦匆忙撤离
You guys bug out of Pakistan with a wounded man,
几小时之后美国就发动了核轰炸
and a few hours later, the U.S. is nuking the joint?
你怎么看待这两件事间的联系
How do you connect the dots?
你真应该把握时机
You should've killed those s.E.A.L.S
杀了那些海豹突击队员
when you had the chance.
这是我的岛
This is my island.
想让我同意你们留下
If I allow your presence,
可是有条件的
it comes with certain terms and conditions.
我现在就可以杀了你
I could kill you right now.
你想引发战争吗
Do you want a war?
我儿子已经死了
My son is dead.
你一日不降  你儿子就一日不会有葬礼
There will be no burial for your son until you surrender.
你是山姆的朋友
You're Sam's friend.
是的  大学朋友
Yes. From college.
肯德尔女士  你对你丈夫的行为怎么看
Mrs. Kendal... What do you think about your husband's actions?
他是政府派来监视我的特工
He's a government agent sent to spy on me
还要策反我跟山姆敌对
and turn me against Sam.
你到底想不想回家了
You ever give a damn about getting home?
山姆  如果你有意见
Sam, if you have objections--
也许你无家可归了  但我有
Maybe you have nowhere to go, but I do.
《破釜沉舟》第一季第六集
化学攻击3小时后
你不会回来了  是不是
You're never coming back, are you?
我总会回到你身边  不是吗
I always find my way back, don't I?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我很快就回来了
I'm gonna be home soon.
我保证
I promise.
皮茨
Pitts.
皮茨  醒醒
Pitts, wake up.
-发生了什么  -冷静  放轻松
- What the hell is going on? - Whoa! Hey, hey, take it easy.
你倒是轻松
You take it easy.
那边有几百人昏倒在地
There's a hundred people passed out back there.
听着  朋友  你在流血
Listen, my friend. You're bleeding, okay?
我帮你处理一下  我有
Let me help you. I brought--
我要你告诉我  那些人发生了什么
You're gonna tell me what happened to all those people back there.
你不记得了
You don't remember?
没关系的
Look, it's okay.
你现在身体不正常
You're not well.
你  还有那些人  都中了毒
You, those people back there, you've all been drugged.
你要躺下  等药效过去
You need to lie down. Wait for it to pass.
你鞋上有血迹
There's blood on your shoes.
-什么  -你鞋上为什么有血迹
- What? Look-- - Why is there blood on your shoes?
不  我只是帮忙...
No. I'm just helping--
告诉我到底发生了什么
Tell me what the hell is going on!
别伤害我  求你了
Don't hurt me, please.
我以我母亲发誓
I swear on my mother,
我到这的时候  你的朋友都已经死了
your friends were already dead when I got here.
好好歇着吧  我的朋友
Rest easy, ma puce.
很快事情就会了结
It will end soon enough.
也许你到时还会感谢我
You might even be grateful.
好事成双
One more for luck.
四小时前
化学攻击前20分钟
我还以为你死了
Thought you were dead.
好多年没睡过这么舒服的觉了
I haven't slept like that in years.
你还说梦话
You talk in your sleep.
我说了什么
What do I say?
那是你跟你梦中情人的秘密
That's between you and whoever comes in your dream.
非礼勿听
Wouldn't be polite to listen.
这位是一级士官巴里・霍普
Petty officer first class Barry Hopper,
这位是艇长马库斯・查普林
Captain Marcus Chaplin.
很高兴看到你恢复得很好
It's good to see you're getting your strength back.
感谢你们能来  不过他真的需要休息
We appreciate you guys coming, but he actually needs his rest.
我们只会占用一点时间
Only gonna take a minute.
你应该也知道  自从我们把你从水里救出来
As I'm sure you're now aware, the world's a bit different
世界就发生了一些变化
since we pulled you out of the water.
我知道  他们都告诉我了
Yeah, the guys have been filling me in.
不过有些东西他们也不知道
Well, they can't tell you what they don't know.
最新谈判结果表明
In recent negotiations,
国防部长对你们很有兴趣
the secretary of defense took a keen interest in all of you.
他似乎十分想要让你和你的队员
He seemed quite determined to have you and your team
重新回到他的掌控之中
back under his control again.
那样的高官居然会对你们感兴趣  不奇怪吗
It seem odd that someone that high up is so concerned with you?
我说过了  很感谢你们的到来
Like I said, we appreciate you stopping by and all--
别别  他们有话想说  听听看
No, no, no, they got a point. Let 'em get to it.
你们有话要说  对吧
You do have a point, don't you?
那听好了
Here it is--
如果巴基斯坦的那次任务中
If your mission in Pakistan--
你们获知的某些内情或者某些行动
something you know about it or something you did--
导致你们回家不安全的话
makes it unsafe for you to go back home,
欢迎留在这里
you're welcome here.
你开什么玩笑  你以为你是谁
Are you kidding me? Who do you think you are?
你往你的祖国扔核弹  你个...
You nuked your own country, you piece of--
你已经死了
you're dead already,
你个自大的杂种
you arrogant son of a bitch.
你只是蠢得不知道要倒下
You're just too stupid to fall down.
有没有那种长得像甜甜圈的  莲雾
The ones that look like round doughnuts, the wax apples.
没了  没了  就这些了
No more, no more. This is it.
你要是还想要  就放几艘船进来
You want more? Let in some boats.
-金和霍普...  -我说
- So King and Hopper-- - Hey.
你得再多给一点
You owe me more.
你走之后  他们密谈了一阵
After you leave, they have a little bedside chat.
然后金让另外两个大汉守在门口
Then King puts the other two gorillas on the door.
自己匆匆出去了
He bugs out.
我连这玩意怎么吃都不知道
I don't even know how to eat these things.
-长官  -水手长
- Sirs. - C.O.B.
艇员们怎么样  水手长
How's the crew, C.O.B.?
状态好得就像哈雷摩托
Firing like a one-kick harley.
正在换班
Just swapping out the crew now.
长官  这些毛球你打算吃吗
Sir, you gonna eat those hairy balls?
我都不知道它们是什么
I don't even know what they are.
红毛丹  跟荔枝差不多
Chom chom. It's like litchi.
没想到你还中意异域水果  水手长
Hadn't pegged you for an exotic fruit man, C.O.B.
你不问我不说
Don't ask, don't tell.
海豹突击队的人加强戒备了
So the S.E.A.L.S are starting to close ranks?
是的  他们一定有事瞒着我们
Yeah, they're definitely hiding something.
可我看不出跟他们耗下去会有什么结果
I don't see a shoving match getting us anywhere, though.
上次我提到这群小子
Secretary Curry nearly popped an eyeball
科利部长差点儿把眼珠瞪出来
last time I mentioned those boys.
这次我就说他们要见媒体
Let's see what happens
看看会怎么样
when I tell him they want to meet the press.
科罗拉多号副艇长之妻"夜询"律师
那是山姆的妻子
That's Sam's wife.
我知道  可和她在一起的帅哥又是谁
I know, but who's that handsome gentleman she's with?
吉拉尔女士
Ms. Girard.
关掉
Get rid of it.
我想跟国防部长科利通话
I want to talk to Secretary of Defense Curry.
-可以帮忙吗  -好  稍等几分钟
- Can you work your magic? - Yes. A few minutes.
需要视频记录
And I'm gonna need a video feed.
我想看到他对我的话的反应
I'd like to see his reaction to what I have to say.
我们有摄像机
We have cameras.
摄像机我们确实有
We do have, uh, cameras.
山姆
Hey, Sam.
瞧瞧这个
Have a look.
这他妈是什么东西
What the hell is that?
那家伙在温暖你的妻子
That's the guy keeping your wife warm.
抱歉  你觉得这很好笑吗
I'm sorry. You think that's funny?
实际上  我认为这很可悲
I think it's sad, actually.
你有种站起来跟我说
Well, you stand up if you're gonna talk to me like that, man.
副艇长  别激动  专注任务
Easy, X.O. Stay on target.
把它关掉  给我接视频信号  马上
Hey, you, get rid of that and get me my video feed. Now.
对不起  我不知道他今天怎么了
I'm sorry. I don't know what's wrong with him today.
没事  不要紧  不过是张照片
No, it's fine. It's fine. It's just a picture.
我以为你会高兴的
I thought you'd be pleased.
你说你不能回家是因为霍普重伤
You said you couldn't go home because Hopper was hurt,
现在他已经没事了
but now he's okay, so--
我就可以走了
So now I can go.
是啊
Yeah.
我欣喜若狂
I'm ecstatic.
那么
So...
你...
Are you...
要回家了吗
going home?
我还没决定
I haven't decided.
但是你想走
But you want to.
我怎么想并不重要
Doesn't matter what I want.
我有工作要做
I got a job to do,
海湾大桥可通不到这里
and the bay bridge doesn't reach this far.
我一直都想看看...
I've always wanted to see the...
天呐
Oh, my god.
那好像是我妈
That looks like my mom.
什么
What?
坚持住
Hold on!
我的头怎么这样疼
Why does my head hurt so much?
接通了吗
You getting through?
转接有问题  但是我想就快了
Trouble with the relay, but soon, I think.
要什么东西吗
You need anything?
不用  我没事
No, I'm okay.
我的视频记录呢
And what about my video feed?
我正在想办法
I'm working on it.
越快越好
Well, the sooner the better.
听着伙计  除非你懂我的活该怎么干
Look, mate, unless you know how to do my job,
否则不如出去凉快着让我安心干活
why don't you just chill out and let me do my job?
好
Okay.
镇上发生了严重情况
We got a serious issue in town.
稍等  水手长
One second, C.O.B.
-好了  可以连线了  -先别接通
- Okay, your line is open. - Yeah, hold the line.
奈杰尔  我需要视频记录
Nigel, I need the video feed.
闭"嘴"  姐妹
Cross your legs, sister.
我说了我正在想办法
I said I was working on it.
我不知道你有什么问题
I don't know what your problem is,
但是你给我解决它  现在就解决
but you sort it out, and you sort it out right now.
问题解决了
Problem sorted.
求求你们  别说话了
Please, everyone, just-- just stop talking.
求你们
Please.
声音太吵
Oh, it's so loud in here.
全镇都是这种情况
Same thing's happening all over town.
我以前见过类似的场面  绝对不是好事
I've seen this party before, and it's not good.
我们中毒了
We've been dosed.
是一种叫做BZ的药  很厉害
It's a pretty serious drug called B.Z.
军方发明的  绰号"脑轰鸣"
Military designed it, nickname "Buzz."
我做过实验对象
I was a guinea pig.
我和兄弟们曾去做过志愿
Me and some buddies volunteered
当年的音乐可没这么难听
back when music didn't suck.
有外块赚当然好
Extra cash was nice,
但即便是低剂量  也不是闹着玩的
but even at a low dose, it was no picnic.
有好消息吗
There any good news?
有  不会致死
Well, it doesn't kill you.
找到了
Found it.
"BZ是一种无味的军事失能剂
Um, "B.Z. is an odorless military incapacitating agent.
主要导致出现错觉  判断力下降
"The central effects include delusions, poor judgment,
短暂失忆  妄想  幻觉  幻想
"memory blackouts, paranoia, illusions, hallucinations.
最终  中毒者会丧失意识
"Ultimately, the victims will lose consciousness."
症状持续时间约八小时"
"Symptoms last about eight hours."
这是一次协同攻击
This is a coordinated attack.
对  但毒药是怎么进来的
Yeah, but how'd it get here?
实验时他们一般掺在柠檬水里
Well, in the experiment, they mixed it with lemonade.
这个岛上只有一个主要水源
Well, the island's only got one main water supply.
-往那里投毒  就搞定所有人了  -聪明
- They dose that, they knock out everyone. - Smart.
解毒方法呢
Countermeasures?
医生曾给我注射肾上腺素解毒
Well, the docs used adrenaline to snap me out of it.
"可使用多种肾上腺素和过敏疫苗"
"Can also use epinephrine, epipens, allergy shots."
科罗拉多号医务室里面有这些药
"Colorado" has those in the med locker.
本地的医院里应该也有
Hospital here would have some, too.
我们得抓紧行动
We gotta move fast.
好  水手长  上尉  你们跟我一起
All right, C.O.B., lieutenant, you're with me.
我们负责下潜隐藏潜艇
We're gonna dive and hide the sub.
用艇上的药度过危险
Ride it out with the meds we have on board.
副艇长  你负责岛上
X.O., you've got the island.
去医院拿肾上腺素
Get the epipens from the hospital,
给自己和必需人员注射
inject yourself and enough crewmen
修理维护好预警站
to repair and defend the E.W.S.
接下来的八小时内要保持清醒警惕
Stay awake and alive for the next eight hours,
暴风雨要来了
'cause something bad's coming.
刚刚进入深水区  长官
Just entering deep water, sir.
航向1-5-3度
Heading 1-5-3.
以全速的三分之二平稳前进
Ahead two-thirds. Steady as she goes.
上尉  你还好吗
You still with me, lieutenant?
很好  长官
All the way, sir.
水手长报告情况
Report, C.O.B.
按照这份药品清单
According to this drug inventory,
科泰兹应该能拿到20人份的肾上腺素
Cortez should be coming back with 20 epipens.
只有20人份
Only 20?
被蜂蛰要注射肾上腺素解毒
潜艇上可没有很多蜜蜂  长官
There's not a lot of bees on submarines, ma'am.
指挥台和轮机舱内的必要人员先注射
Essential personnel on the conn and engine room get shots first.
然后是各部门负责人
Department heads after that.
那样会有很多艇员
That's gonna leave a whole lot of the crew
无法解毒痛苦无比
crawling out of their skins.
那我们就照顾他们  自求多福吧
So we babysit and hope for the best.
看来今天也一如既往嘛
Why should today be any different?
长官  都没有了
Sir, they're gone.
肾上腺素注射剂没了  有人闯入了医务室
Sir, the epi shots-- medical locker was broken into.
-什么意思  -有人把药偷走了
- What are you talking about? - Someone stole 'em.
那我们一支也没有了
So we have nothing?
一些艇员已经慌了阵脚
And some of the crew's already freaking out,
行为举止奇怪
acting weird.
我们要怎么办  长官
What do we do, sir?
下潜
We dive.
你欠我钱  你得再给我一些
You owe me! You owe me more!
滚开
Hey, get off of me!
克里斯蒂  你在干什么
Christine, what are you doing?
你不会回来了  是不是
You're never coming home, are you?
什么
What?
抱歉  长官  我只是很渴
I'm sorry, sir. Just really thirsty.
皮茨  没事  跟我来  我们需要...
Pitts, it's okay. Come with me. We gotta--
我要喝水
I need water.
皮茨  皮茨  听我说
Hey, Pitts. Pitts, Pitts, Pitts, listen to me.
我们正遭遇攻击
We're under attack, okay?
我们被下毒了
We have been drugged.
我需要你的帮助  振作起来
I need your help. Come on.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
但是我得先去喝水
But I gotta get water!
药就下在水里  皮茨
It's in the water, Pitts!
化学攻击三小时后
你们可能会感到头昏眼花  昏昏欲睡
You may find also yourself feeling lightheaded or sleepy.
没有关系
That's fine.
如果出现这种情况
When that happens,
请离开工作岗位
I want you to step away from your position
到自己的铺位上去躺好
and secure yourself in your bunk.
我知道我们现在...
I realize we're running...
我知道我们现在就位艇员不足
I realize we're running a skeleton crew.
但是在安全的深度
But we will ride out this storm
我们一定能度过这次危机
hovering here at s-- a safe depth
然后安然无恙地返回港口
and return to port unharmed.
艇长讲话完毕
Captain out.
嘿  老兄
Hey, man.
你中毒了吗  看上去不太严重
You messed up? You don't seem too messed up.
你也还好
Neither do you.
军用药物  可令神经中枢长时间兴奋
吃了几片苯丙胺
Popped some "Go pills".
你拎着根牙签想干什么
Where you goin' with the toothpick?
和塞拉特有点账要算
Got some business with Serrat.
那我们俩算是一伙了
Guess that makes us partners.
她还在昏迷
Ah, she's still out of it.
被BZ毒的不轻
That B.Z. hit her hard.
八成是个素食主义者
Probably a vegetarian.
我觉得她挺喜欢我的
I think she likes me, though.
快  快给我醒过来
Come on, ake up, already!
给她注射这个
Here. Give her these.
-两支  -只要能弄醒她就行
- Two? - Whatever it takes to bring her back.
剂量太大了  会弄死她的
It's too much. You're going to stop her heart.
试试静脉注射
Try to hit a vein or something.
我要她15分钟内醒过来
I want that coma up in 15.
把她弄死了就什么都得不到了
You're not going to get anything fixed if you kill her.
她是法国人  心脏承受能力强
She's French. She's all heart.
会没事的
She'll be fine.
他们有交叉火力
They got cross-fire.
我们三步都前进不了
We won't get three steps.
来吧  亲爱的  快起来
Let's go, sweetheart. Up and at 'em.
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
你们是怎么回事  你们没必要...
What is wrong with you? There's no need for you to--
天啊  闭嘴
Oh, my god. Shut up.
听着  我没时间装绅士
Look, I don't have time to do it the nice way.
你我的协定很简单
We made a very simple arrangement.
里面可不包括这个
This was not a part of it.
也不包括杀你  但一切都可以变
Neither was killing you, but everything's negotiable.
我得告诉你
I gotta tell you,
你弄断我的手  让我很火大
I'm really kind of pissed you broke my arm.
他们抓住了霍普
They got Hopper.
你该多喝点牛奶
You should drink more milk.
刚做的体腔检查爽吗
Did you enjoy your cavity search, by the way?
你呢
Did you?
我们已经知道它不在哪里
Now that we know where it is not,
不如谈谈它到底在哪
let's talk about where it is.
我说了  我不知道
Told you, I don't know where it is.
你这态度  会莫名其妙害死很多人的
That attitude is gonna get a lot of people killed for no reason.
他们是什么人
Who are these guys?
他们要找的到底是什么
What the hell are they looking for?
化学攻击一小时后
我们正遭遇攻击
We're under attack, okay?
我们被下毒了
We have been drugged.
我需要你的帮助  振作起来
I need your help. Come on.
是  长官  但是我得先去喝水
Yes, sir. But I gotta get water!
药就下在水里  皮茨
It's in the water, Pitts!
你不会回来了  是不是
You're never coming back, are you?
天啊  你不是真的
Oh, god. You're not real.
我知道你不是真的
I know you're not real.
你不相信我吗
Don't you trust me?
你不相信你自己吗
Don't you trust yourself?
你是谁
Who are you?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
你是谁
Who are you?
副艇长  冷静  你认识我的
X.O., hang on. You know me.
我不认识你  你在这里干什么
I don't know you. What are you doing in here?
我的手臂断了  必须固定一下
My arm was broken. I had to--I had to set it.
外面那些人是你杀的吗
Did you kill those men out there?
不不不  是霍普  长官
No, no, no, no, no, it was--it was Hopper, sir.
他...他疯了一样  攻击我们
He went--he went... he went crazy, attacked us.
他打断了我的手
He broke my arm.
不  我不认识你  我不认识你
No. I don't know you. I don't know you.
是药捣的鬼  长官  它让你脑子不清楚
It's that drug, sir. It's messing with your mind.
我是吉姆・麦克卢尔  后勤的
I'm Jim Mcclure. I'm in supply.
不  不  不
No, no, no, no.
等等  你认识我的
Hang on. You know me.
你是海军少校山姆・肯德尔
You're lieutenant commander Sam Kendal.
科罗拉多号的副艇长
You're the X.O. on the "Colorado."
是药捣的鬼  长官
It's just the drugs, sir. It's--
它让你迷惑
It gets you confused.
那药让大家都发了疯
That drug is making everyone crazy.
让你看见幻象  看见一些...
It makes you see things, think things that aren't--
不真实的东西
aren't real.
你没事吧
Y-you okay?
我...
I...
你需要帮助吗  我可以帮你
You need help? I can help you.
我需要打一针肾腺素
I, uh, I need EPI shots.
就是肾上腺素  能帮助减轻...
Epinephrine, it--it helps counteract the...
我已经找过了
Already checked.
都没了
They're--they're gone.
他失去意识了
He's unconscious.
要我扶他回铺位  还是...
Did you want me to try and get him to a bunk or--
等水手长回来我们再移动他
We'll move him when the C.O.B. gets back.
长官  我感觉有点...
Sir, I'm feeling a lit-- I--
我需要你保持清醒  上尉
I need you here, lieutenant, with me.
坚持住
With me.
你能做到吗
Can you handle that?
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
我清醒着  长官
I'm here, sir.
警告
一号机舱出现火情
We got a fire in machinery one.
如果火势蔓延到储油罐...
If that fire gets to the air in the storage tanks--
我知道  关闭氧气阀  上尉
I'm aware. Shut down the oxygen header, lieutenant.
那我们还剩多少氧气
How much air does that leave us?
吸到多少算多少
Whatever you can smell.
一号机舱  我是指挥台  请回复
Machinery one, conn. Report.
请立刻报告火情
Report status on the fire.
他们可能早已经昏过去了
They could all be passed out down there.
水手长
C.O.B.!
水手长  你在哪儿
C.O.B., where are you?
谢帕德上尉  你来负责指挥台
Lieutenant Shepard, you have the conn.
长官
Sir.
如果没人去灭掉火  再恢复供氧
If someone doesn't get that fire out and the air back on,
我们都会睡过去  长眠不醒
we all go to sleep, never wake up.
保持潜艇稳定
Keep her steady.
我得和科罗拉多号取得联系
I need to get ahold of the "Colorado"
看他们是否需要帮助
to see if they need any help.
需要权限
Oh, there's power.
能帮我输入信号吗  副艇长
Can you key the signal for me, X.O.?
为什么我们没有孩子呢  山姆
How come we don't have kids, Sam?
是不是因为你总是不在家
Is it 'cause you're never home?
听着
Look...
我们得叫醒你的法国朋友
we gotta wake up your french friend.
能听到吗
You hear me?
我们得把那法国小姐弄起来
We gotta get that French senorita back on her feet.
只有这样才能挽救当前的乱局
Only way this thing's getting fixed.
索菲  醒醒
Hey. Sophie, wake up.
看着我
Hey, look at me.
听我说  睁开眼睛
Look, look-- hey, open your eyes.
你得集中注意听我说  听着
You need to focus on me. Here, look.
索菲  你得醒醒
Sophie, you gotta wake up.
我们必须把无线电修好
I need to get the radio fixed now.
他会杀了我们的...  为了钱
He will kill us... all for money.
副艇长
X.O...
你需要再输入一次信号
Need you to key the signal again.
本来不想这么做的  但是...
I was hoping to avoid this, but...
待会儿再杀你也不迟
I guess I can always kill you later.
爸爸
hi, daddy.
杰弗里
Jeffrey?
警告
你回来了
You came home!
真高兴你回家了  宝贝
I am so happy you're here, babe.
不坐下来吗
Aren't you gonna sit down?
你离开那么久
You were gone for so long,
我以为你永远不会回来了
I thought you were never coming home.
为什么你总让我独守空房 山姆
Why are you always leaving me alone, Sam?
我不想这样的  可我没有办法
I don't want to leave you alone. But I have to.
-抱歉  -你才不抱歉呢
- I'm sorry. - You're not sorry.
马库斯给你那份文职工作
When Marcus offered you that desk job,
你首先想到的居然是...
your first thought was...
老天  我希望克里斯蒂不要知道这件事
God, I hope Christine doesn't find out about that.
不是这样的
No, it wasn't.
不是吗
It wasn't?
我只是想自己决定  仅此而已
Look, I just want my own command. That's all.
那是不是又一件
Is that just another one of those things
你不希望克里斯蒂知道的事
that you hope Christine doesn't find out about?
你不了解情况
You don't know what it's like.
被拷问那件事呢
To be tortured?
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
我爱你
I love you.
-你不想让我爱你吗  -我当然想
- Don't you want me to love you? - Of course I do.
那为什么不信任我
Then why don't you trust me?
我当然信任你
I do trust you.
那是为什么
What is it then?
我不信任自己
I don't trust myself.
的确不该
Well, you shouldn't.
也不该相信他
And you shouldn't trust him.
能帮个忙吗
Help me out, would you?
我只有一只手
I only got one arm.
该死  好疼
Damn, that hurts.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
她会醒的  稍等一下
She'll come around. Just give her a minute.
你叫什么来着
Hey, remind me of your name.
麦克卢尔
Mcclure.
-后勤的麦克卢尔  -是的
- Mcclure in supply. - Yeah.
你的上级军官是...
And you report to Senior Watch...
-阿诺德军士长  -俄亥俄的比尔・阿诺德
- Chief Arnold. - Bill Arnold from Ohio.
是啊  俄亥俄
Right, Ohio.
是啊  抱歉
Right, right, right. Sorry.
但他上个月就晋升了
But he got promoted last month.
你是谁
Who are you?
你来这儿有什么目的
Huh?! Why are you here?
你在干什么  山姆
What are you doing, Sam?
纠正这一切  等着我  克里斯蒂
I'm gonna fix everything. You'll see, Christine.
我很快就回来了  我保证
I'm gonna be home soon. I promise.
我保证
I promise.
你是谁
Who are you?
说话
Tell me.
说啊
Tell me!
化学攻击四小时后
我不知道
I don't know.
猜猜嘛
Guess.
你
"U"?
你实在不擅长猜词
You're terrible at this.
顺便告诉你  是"吉普赛人"
By the way, it was "Gypsy."
那边情况怎么样了
How are we doing back there?
再等一秒
One second.
你一直说"等一秒"
Yeah, you keep saying that.
你知道一秒是多久吧
You do know how long one second is, right?
该用多久就用多久
It takes how long it takes.
像圣诞树一样神奇
Hey, hey! Like a Christmas tree.
圣诞快乐  我的朋友
Joyeux noel, huh, mon ami?
你不是我的朋友
You are not my friend.
真伤心  汇报一下工作进度吗
Devastating. So do we have a working comm or what?
我必须下楼  重启天线电源
I have to, um, reset power for the antenna downstairs.
跟着她
Go with her.
就快没你的事了  塞拉特先生
Almost out of your hair, Mr. Serrat.
我会想念你的
I'll miss you.
我把丑话说在前面
Yeah, well, I'm gonna bring this up now
免得你待会儿发脾气
'cause I don't want you pitching a fit later.
她做完活就得死
When she's done, she's dead.
什么
What?
不  绝对不行
No, no, this isn't--no!
很好  有话现在说
Good, get it out now
因为她知道的太多了
'cause, yeah, she's seen a lot of faces.
我可以替她担保
I will be responsible for her.
我保证...
I will make sure...
什么意思
What was that?
没有理由...
There's no reason to--
游戏还长着呢
It's a long game.
别第一天就自寻死路
Don't get yourself hanged on the first day.
准备转移霍普
Get Hopper ready to move.
这次绑结实点
And tie him up good this time
别让他再害别人受伤
so he doesn't screw anyone's health plan.
好了吗
That's it?
还有一个
One more.
放松  放松  你还好吗
Easy. Easy. Easy. You okay?
我会救你出去  但需要你协助
I'm gonna get you out of here, but we need your help.
我们回到楼上  假装一切正常
We're gonna go back upstairs like there's nothing wrong.
我就在你身后
I'm gonna be right behind you.
而我就在他身后
And I'll be right behind him.
你进去的时候  动作要快
When you go in, you go in fast.
上了指挥台就卧倒
You get to the conn, get down on the floor.
明白吗
You understand?
好  明白了
Yes, I understand.
好的
Okay.
我搞定形成交叉火力的两人
Hey. I got the cross-fire twins.
你搞定另一个人
You take the other one.
好  记住别杀断手的那个
Okay, remember, broken arm stays alive.
我不知道你为何而战  朋友
I don't know what you think you're fighting for, friend.
挥舞旗帜  敬礼  世界警察
Flag waving, saluting, world policing--
都不过是商业的一部分
it's all just part of the commercial.
-怎么样  -快了快了  马上
- Well? - Almost. Almost. I-I am very close.
还有一些最后的连接
A few final connections.
很好
Good.
你能帮我输入信号吗
Will you key the signal for me?
说个时间
Say when.
快了
Almost.
他们是什么人  谁派来的
Who are these people? Who sent them?
-我不知道  -你在干什么
- I don't know. - What are you doing?
他刚救了你一命
He just saved your life.
-他们想要什么  -他和他的朋友霍普
- What do they want?! - Him and his friend Hopper.
本来不该有伤亡
There was to be no harm.
他们告诉我  把药投入水里
They told me, put their drug in the water,
你们就会睡着
and you would go to sleep.
醒来之后你们就没理由留下了
When you woke, there would be no reason for you to stay.
他们答应让我夺回我的岛
They promised me my island back!
他们骗我
They lied.
我知道的就是这样  其余的你们都看到了
That is what I know. The rest is as you see.
出去
Get out of here.
请帮我把指挥台连上线
Please help me get the conn back online.
但愿我们的潜艇还在
Hopefully there's still a sub out there somewhere.
空气
Air.
你得重新开启制氧
You gotta turn the oxygen back on.
困了吗
You sleepy? Yeah?
警报  氧气含量过低  一氧化碳及二氧化碳含量过高
我也困了
Me too.
今晚想听什么故事
What story you want to do tonight?
孔雀的故事
The--the peacock.
挑得不错
That's a good one.
一只孔雀
A peacock...
展开他华丽的尾羽
spreading his gorgeous tail
嘲笑路过的一只鹤
made fun of a crane that was passing by.
这只孔雀
The peacock...
嘲笑鹤灰蒙蒙的羽毛  说道
laughed at the dusty color of the crane's feathers and said...
"我的衣裳就像国王
"I am robed like a king,
警报  氧气含量过低  一氧化碳及二氧化碳含量过高
你的翅膀却一点色彩都没有"
While you have not a bit of color on your wings."
"没错"鹤答道
"That's true," Replied the crane.
"但我能直上云霄
"but I soar to the heights of heaven.
而你只能在陆地上行走
"While you only walk below,
好似一只
"like a...
好似一只老鼠"
like a rat."
预警站呼叫科罗拉多号  收到请回答
E.W.S. to "Colorado." Come in, "Colorado."
你确定设备正常吗
Are you sure it's working?
是的  应该有用
Yes, it should be.
科罗拉多号请回答  我是副艇长
Come in, "Colorado." This is the X.O.
能不能请你  再检查一遍信号
Can you please, can you just recheck the signal?
信号没问题  我检查过了
The signal is good. I have checked.
也许他们遇到了麻烦
Um, perhaps they have a problem--
请你再检查一遍信号行吗  拜托了
Can you please just recheck the signal? Please.
别发火  好吗  我在尽力而为
Don't get angry, okay? I'm doing my best.
我不是发火  对不起  我很抱歉
I'm not. I'm not. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起  我没有  没有
I'm sorry. I'm not. I'm not.
现在大家都不容易
It is difficult in this place for everyone.
你好像应对得还不错
You seem to be handling it very well.
相信我  我并不好受
I promise you, I'm not.
道德是有底线的
There is a line of morals, okay?
一旦你越过了它  内心永无平静可言
When you cross this line, you never have peace.
你额头上有血迹
You--you have some blood on your forehead.
抱歉
Sorry.
预警站呼叫科罗拉多号  收到请回答
Uh, E.W.S. to "Colorado." Come in, "Colorado."
E.W.S. to "Colorado." Come in, "Colorado."
预警站呼叫科罗拉多号  收到请回答
收到  预警站
Roger, E.W.S.
我们大约在五英里外
We're about 5 miles out,
潜艇看起来一切正常
and it looks like the sub's all right.
我们会等到艇员醒来
We'll wait for the crew to wake up, and we'll
确认安全后立即返航
make our way back once we get an all clear.
岸上一切都好吗
How are things on the beach?
预警站已经安全  长官
E.W.S. is secure, sir.
但有人员伤亡
Not without a body count, though,
包括两名海豹突击队员
including two of the SEALs--
沃格勒和蒙克
Vogler and Monk.
收到  科罗拉多号完毕
Roger that. "Colorado" out.
他们为什么想抓我们
Why'd those guys want me and you?
你以为呢
What do you think?
你我进过巴基斯坦的那个房间
We were the two in the room in Pakistan.
只有我们俩个人知道交火的原因
We're the only ones who know why the bullets started flying.
我只知道  我们杀了本来要救的人
All I know is, we killed the guy we were sent in to save.
我还是不明白原因
I still don't know why.
任务指令由解救变为消灭
The mission directive got changed from extraction to elimination.
我没接到新指令
I wasn't given new orders.
我收到了
I was.
请进
Enter.
长官  换班艇员已登艇
Sir, relief crew is on board.
其他人已经上岸
Everyone else is already ashore.
我让一艘小艇在外候命
I've got a skiff waiting to take you back
等你准备完毕后送你上岸
if you're ready.
我得先刮胡子  上尉
I'm just gonna scrape off the fuzz, lieutenant.
当了30年海军
After 30 years of shaving in the navy,
在岸上刮胡子反而容易伤到自己
I have a tendency to cut myself on land.
明白
Understood.
估计我近期不会敢拿任何尖锐的东西了
Don't think I'll be holding anything sharp for a little while.
我马上就来
I'll be right up.
塞拉特显然是他们的内应
Serrat was obviously the man on the inside.
不知道他是从哪里弄来的BZ
I don't know how he got the B.Z.,
但是他把药投进了水里
but he got it in the water.
要是他们的头儿没被射杀
If their leader survives the gunshot,
或许能告诉我们答案
maybe we can ask him.
问题是那些人怎样联络塞拉特
It's interesting that someone was able to contact him
并策划攻击
and set up the attack.
也许他有电台或者卫星电话
Maybe he's got a radio or--or a sat phone?
或者艇员中有人帮助他
Or maybe someone on our crew helped him.
你觉得艇员中有人在为...
You think someone on our crew is working...
为谁工作
working for who?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我昏迷的时候
But when I was unconscious,
有人拿走了我的核弹发射钥匙
someone took my firing key.
我们现在失去了发射核武器的能力
We now have no nuclear launch capabilities.
如果他们的目标就是钥匙
If the plan was to steal the key,
我们怎么能活到现在
then how come we're still alive?
完全没有道理
That doesn't make any sense.
没了核弹发射钥匙  我们简直任人宰割
We are defenseless without our firing key.
也许他们只是想给我们施压
Maybe they want to make us sweat.
或者他们正在赶来
Maybe they're on the way here.
又或者他们想先让自己人安全撤离
Maybe their plan was to extract their men first.
无论如何  我们必须找到钥匙
Either way, we have to find the key.
处理一下伤口
You should get that taken care of.
我会的
I will.
看来你们打得很惨烈
Must have been a hell of a fight.
说实话  我不记得了
Honestly, I don't remember.
你会想起来的
It'll come back to you.
至少会想起大半
Most of it, at least.
化学攻击3小时后
你到底是谁
Who are you?
你来这里想干什么
What are you doing here?
说话
Tell me.
说啊
Tell me!
别这样
Stop it.
别再对我撒谎了  山姆
Stop lying to me, Sam.
什么
What?
山姆  好久不见啊
Hey, Sam. I haven't seen you for a while.
保罗
Paul?
你为什么在我家里
Why are you in my house?
你怎么和我妻子在一起
What are you doing with my wife?
你以为克里斯蒂会傻到
You think Christine's the kind of woman
一直遥遥无期地等下去吗
that's gonna wait forever for you to come home?
天呐  瞧瞧她
I mean, god, look at her.
怎么会遥遥无期
It's not forever.
他这话是什么意思  我对你说过...
Why is he saying forever? I told you...
你看她有多美
Look how beautiful she is.
老兄  你怎能把娇妻丢下不管
And you're gonna leave this unattended, buddy?
女人是有需求的
Women have needs.
要是你不来照顾她  我可求之不得
If you don't... I sure as hell will.
山姆  一切就要结束了
This is the beginning of the end, Sam.
你说什么呢  不是的
What are you talking about? No, it's not.
你看
Look.
看看你对他做了什么
Look what you did to him.
你差点把他打死
You almost killed him.
我会永远爱你
I'll always love you.
别离开我
Don't leave me.
我不能失去你  我不要失去你
I can't lose you. I'm not gonna lose you.
那就快回家
Then come home.
我必须坚持到底
I have to finish this.
否则我的艇员就会丧命
If I don't, my people will die.
我绝不会让这种事情发生
I'm not gonna let that happen.
那我们怎么办  山姆
What about us, Sam?
这一针下去
When you do that...
我就会消失
I'll be gone,
或许你再也不会见到我
and you may never see me again.
你为什么要这样
Why would you do that?
别走
Stay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你不会回来了  是吧
You're never coming back, are you?
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be different now.
别说了
Stop it.
无论我走多远  总会回到你身边
I always find my way back, don't I?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
我很快就回来了
I'm gonna be home soon.
我保证
I promise.
我只是来向你道声晚安
I just, uh, wanted to say good night
还有  再次为我今天的行为道歉
and, uh, to apologize again for anything I may have...
你当时无法控制自己
You weren't yourself, so...
是啊  我想是吧
No, I, um...I suppose not.
你在忙什么
Uh, what are you working on?
遇袭期间  监控一直在录像
The cameras were still recording during the attack.
太好了  能让我看看吗
Oh, brilliant. Can I--can I see?
明天吧
Oh, tomorrow?
今天大家都太累了
Um, it's been a long day, right?
一切都会好起来的  我保证
Everything's gonna be different now. I promise.
别说了
Stop it.
无论我走多远  总会回到你身边
I always find my way back, don't I?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
别这样
Stop it.
无论我走多远  总会回到你身边
I always find my way back, don't I?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
《破釜沉舟》下周五继续  敬请锁定人人影视
Last resort, all new next thursday at 8/7 central line on abc.
《破釜沉舟》上集回顾
我们正遭到攻击  我们被下毒了
We're under attack. We have been drugged.
他们告诉我  把药投入水里
They told me, put their drug in the water,
你们就会睡着
and you would go to sleep.
他们答应让我夺回我的岛
They promised me my island back.
外面那些人是你杀的吗
Did you kill those men out there?
我到这的时候  你的朋友都已经死了
Your friends were already dead when I got here.
我没时间装绅士
I don't have time to do it the nice way.
你我的协定很简单
We made a very simple arrangement.
一切都可以改变
Everything's negotiable.
你是谁
Who are you?
说话 说啊
Tell me. Tell me!
他是政府派来监视我的特工
He's a government agent sent to spy on me
并策反我跟山姆敌对
and turn me against Sam.
我会纠正这一切  等着我  克里斯蒂
I'm gonna fix everything. You'll see, Christine.
你在干什么  山姆
What are you doing, Sam?
巴特勒艇长可以火力解决科罗拉多号
Captain Butler has a firing solution on the "Colorado."
我现在就可以杀了你
I could kill you right now.
你想引发战争吗
Do you want a war?
当我昏迷的时候
When I was unconscious,
有人拿走了我的核弹发射钥匙
someone took my firing key.
我们现在失去了发射核武器的能力
We now have no nuclear launch capabilities.
谢帕德上尉  他还要这样干多久
Lieutenant Shepard, how much longer is he gonna take?
我们是按照命令行事
We do what we're told.
按照命令行事  才使我们落到如今的地步
'Cause that's worked out so well for us so far.
实在太过分了
It's outrageous.
副艇长  快检查完了吧
You almost done, X.O.?
我觉得有些人再过30秒
I think some of these guys are about 30 seconds
就会以下犯上  抗命不从
from coming over here and getting an article 90.
需要多久就该多久  上尉
Well, it's gonna take as long as it takes, Lieutenant.
那是我的包  长官
That's my bag, sir.
抱歉  没人能豁免
I'm sorry. No one's exempt.
我们不知道在BZ袭击中是谁在协助他们
We don't know who helped those men with the B.Z. attack.
我们知道是谁攻击了我们
We know who attacked us.
是塞拉特的协助下的秘密行动组
Black ops with help from Serrat.
那是谁偷了潜艇上的肾上腺素注射剂
Then who stole the EpiPens on the sub?
我们之中有内鬼  你我都清楚
There's somebody on the inside. You know it, and I know it.
为什么不让我帮你呢
Why don't you just let me help you?
非得要我把话说明白吗  上尉
Do I have to spell it out for you, lieutenant?
所以说我也是嫌疑人吗
So I'm a suspect?
你认为我背叛了大家吗
You think that I betrayed the crew?
我不知道
I don't know.
你可以走了
You're dismissed.
你在对我耍官威吗
You're pulling rank on me?
我不用耍官威  上尉  我有这权力
I don't pull rank, lieutenant. I have rank.
没找到钥匙
No sign of the key.
但如果我们一直这样对待他们
But if we keep treating them like this,
我们就会失去威信
we're gonna lose 'em.
钥匙被盗时  在艇上的只有艇员
The only people on board when the key was stolen were crew members,
副艇长
X.O.
他们中有一个是敌人
One of them is the enemy,
在我们把他揪出来之前
and until we find out who,
只有你我能知道钥匙被盗这件事
the only people who can know about the key are you and me.
但已经过了48小时了  长官
But it's been 48 hours, sir.
如果对方的目的是让我们失去防御力
If the goal was to render us defenseless,
那为什么我们还没死
then how come we're not already dead?
叛徒只是得手之后尚未汇报
Our judas hasn't reported their success yet.
但一旦他们这么做了
But once they do...
至少让我告诉格蕾丝
At least let me tell Grace.
格蕾丝的父亲正被军事羁押  山姆
Grace's father was hauled out of here in military custody, Sam.
难道她没有可能一时冲动吗
Is it impossible to imagine her doing something rash?
我完全信任谢帕德上尉  长官
I back lieutenant Shepard 100%, sir.
百分之百
100%.
在这件事结束之前  我们只以事实说话
Until this thing is over, we will be ruled by fact
而非情感
and not emotion,
事实是  我们被背叛了
and the fact is, we have been betrayed.
我们继续搜查全体艇员
We keep searching the crew.
我们若再这么下去  军心就会散掉
We keep this up, we're not gonna have a crew.
安静  我的铺位也被他们搜了
Quiet! They tossed my bunk, too.
我可没抱怨个不停
You don't see me bitchin' about somebody spittin' in my grits.
副艇长要你们打开柜锁
X.O. wants these coffin lockers open.
打开它们
Open 'em up.
列队出来
Now file out.
科瓦尔斯基
Kowalski.
手里拿的是什么
What do you got there?
是牙套  水手长
It's a night guard, C.O.B.,
防止我磨牙
for my overbite.
瘾不小啊
Hey, Kurt Cobain.
你哪来的这东西
Where'd you get this?
我
I...
你在吸毒  你竟然在吸毒
You been using? You've been using!
你想要这垃圾吗
You want this junk?
你想要这玩意吗
You want this? Huh?!
-不  -你哪弄来的
- No! - Where'd you get it?
唯一知道你还活着的
The only two people who know you're still alive
就是站在你面前的两个人
are the two you're looking at.
你应该庆幸
And that's lucky for you.
我知道有好几个海豹突击队员想向你"问好"
I know a couple of navy SEALs that would love to come say hi.
我艇上的叛徒是谁
Who's the traitor on my boat?
我以为你们会先问我的名字
Here I thought you were gonna start with my name.
我叫布斯
It's Booth.
布斯
Booth?
好的  布斯
Okay,Booth.
我们知道在袭击中有人协助你
We know you had assistance during the attack.
我们想知道你的同伙是谁
We want to know who you're working with.
得了吧  艇长
Come on, captain.
你一定听到过流言
You must have heard the rumors.
艇长中间一直有传言说
The word among sub captains for a while
中情局在每艘核潜艇上都安插了休眠者
has been that the CIA has a sleeper agent on every nuclear sub...
以防哪个艇长发疯生出糊涂念头
just in case some crazy captain gets the wrong idea.
不管是你艇员中的哪位
And whoever it is in your crew,
从你们问题的急迫程度判断
judging from the urgency of the question,
我猜他们得手了
I guess they pulled it off.
得手了什么
Pulled off what, exactly?
他们的任务
Their mission.
就是你脖子上的发射钥匙
The firing key from around your neck.
看来我说中了
I see I'm right.
那么你是中情局的人
So that's who you're with... CIA?
心里不好过吧
Hell of a feeling, isn't it?
享受午餐吧
Enjoy your lunch,
因为我会让你烂在这里
because I will keep you here
你除了自己的心跳呼吸什么都听不到
where you can hear your breath and your heartbeat and nothing else
直到你供出那个人
until you give me a name.
信息隔离  艇长
Compartmentalization, captain.
我怎么会知道
Why would I know?
你可以再来拷问我
You can torture me again,
可是我不知道他的名字
but I don't know a name,
不认得面孔
a face,
连声音都没听过
or even a voice.
或许他在撒谎
Well, maybe he's lying.
我很怀疑
I doubt it.
但是还有一个人可能知道
But there is one other person who may know.
你该多派些守卫
You should post more guards.
为什么  我又不怕什么
Why? I have nothing to fear.
你协助外来者使用军用药品
You aided foreigners in an attack on this island
攻击了这座岛
using a military drug.
水手长
C.O.B.
开始搬  东西全都装箱
Tear it apart. Load everything up in boxes.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
袭击中有人偷了我一件很重要的东西
Something I value greatly was taken from me during the attack.
如果你能告诉我它的下落
If you can tell me where to find it
或者是谁偷的  这事一笔勾销
or who took it, we're good.
否则  我艇上有28枚巡航导弹
If not, I do have 28 cruise missiles on my boat.
巡航导弹
Cruise missile?
我受过的威胁不少
I've been threatened with many things,
巡航导弹倒是头一回
but never a cruise missile.
装上卡车
Put 'em on the truck.
回头再开箱
We'll open 'em later.
搜他的身
Search him.
上次我在这里  任由他摆布
Last time I was here, he was the one in control.
我更喜欢这样
I like it this way better.
在看什么
What are you looking at?
你的后颈
The back of your neck.
我喜欢你把头发扎起来
I like your hair up.
披着头发拿的小费多
I make better tips with it down.
泡酒吧的男人喜欢认为给他倒酒的女人
Guys in bars like to think the girls pouring their drinks
入杯中烈酒般热情奔放
are free spirits.
那样的话  如果他们的甜言蜜语够动听
That way, if they say something interesting enough,
酒吧女就会跟他们上床
they'll hop into bed with them.
多么愚蠢  你能想象吗
Can you imagine such stupidity?
我可以帮你埋葬你的朋友
I can help you bury your friends.
我不介意
I don't mind.
只能我和霍普去
Gotta be just me and Hopper.
去埋了你的朋友  然后回来
Go bury your friends. Come back.
我关掉酒吧
I'll--I'll close down the bar.
我们喝个大醉  朝天开枪
We'll drink ourselves stupid and fire guns in the air,
你想怎样就怎样
whatever you like.
你真了解我
You're good for me.
那不好吗
That's a problem?
只是还不习惯
Just not used to it.
你到底是谁  你来这里想干什么
Who are you? What are you doing here?
说话
Tell me.
说啊
Tell me!
这是干什么
What is all this?
我们得把塞拉特的东西存起来
We had to store Serrat's stuff somewhere.
所有地方都要搜
Everything has to be searched,
包括你的办公室
including your office.
你在搜我的东西
You're looking through my things?
不想解释一下你去塞拉特家做什么
You want to tell me what you were doing at Serrat's?
我去听音乐  那也不可以吗
I went to listen to music. Is that allowed?
你连我的电脑也搜了
Did you search my computer as well?
好吧  如果你要搜我的东西  请便
Okay, if you want to search me, go ahead.
我阻止不了你
I can't stop you.
但你知道我并没有参与
But you know I was not involved.
我看不透你
I don't know what you are.
不敢确定
Not for sure.
那么我们的感觉一致了
Well, maybe that makes two of us.
我知道你卖毒品给我的人
I know you're selling to my guys.
以后不许
No more.
听着  老家伙
Listen, old man,
想要货  就直说
you need something, you just ask.
不许向海军贩毒
Don't deal to navy.
政府一再强调  对巴基斯坦实施核打击
The nuclear attack on Pakistan... was the terrorist threat
是为了应付恐怖威胁
the government used to justify it--
确有其事还是只是借口
Was it real or was it just an excuse?
野心家编出来的幌子
A false flag to validate the first shot of a man
因为他做了总统  还想当皇帝
who wants to be an emperor, not a president.
却要你的潜艇和巴基斯坦平民来买单
And your boat and the citizens of that nation paid the price.
心满意足吧  你们是好人
Yeah, enjoy it, man. You're the good guys.
但纠结之处在于
But here's the twist--
我们也是
So are we.
你们杀了两个海豹突击队员  还敢自称好人
You killed two navy SEALs. You're the good guys?
我们尽力避免伤亡
We tried to avoid that.
我的小队负责抓住霍普
My team was just supposed to grab Hopper
休眠者负责偷你们艇长的钥匙
while the sleeper took your captain's key.
为什么要偷发射钥匙
Why steal the firing key?
为什么不联系外界  形成联盟
Why not reach out? Why not form an alliance?
你可以认为他是精于谋略
You may think he's some kind of chess master,
可是没人知道查普林到底是在作势
but nobody knows if Chaplin is just bluffing
还是真的疯了
or if he's actually insane.
无论哪种情况
Either way, it's too dangerous
让他带着17枚核弹逍遥在外都过于危险
to let him stay parked out here with 17 nukes.
你有没有看过他的海军医疗调查心理档案
Have you seen his N.S.M.R.L. psych profile?
知不知道他有愤怒问题
Do you know he has rage issues
和边缘型自恋型人格特质
and borderline narcissistic personality traits?
你知道还有谁有这种性格特点吗
You know who else he shares those traits with?
谁
Who's that?
卡扎菲  斯大林
Gadhafi, Stalin,
吉姆・琼斯[邪教首领]
Jim Jones.
以及丘吉尔  麦克阿瑟和巴顿将军
Churchill, Macarther, Patton.
布斯  你到底能不能帮我们回家
Look, Booth, can you help get us home or not?
山姆  我们不想让你们回家
We don't want you to come home, Sam.
科罗拉多号必须是反抗的象征
The "Colorado" needs to be the symbol of resistance.
我们需要你们留下  继续你们正在做的事
We need you to stay here, keep doing what you're doing.
不过不能由查普林领导
But not with Chaplin in charge.
我们要你来领导
We want you.
你可以跟我们合作
You we can work with.
你跟人合作的方式真有意思  布斯
You got a funny way of working with people, Booth.
你们在这里对抗  总统的位子就坐不长了
The president's not gonna last, not with you here.
情形对他不利
Everything's turning against him.
只要六个月  可能一年
I'm talking six months, maybe a year...
-不不不  -然后你就能
- No, no, no. - Then you can--
我不要等那么久
I'm not waiting that long.
如果克里斯蒂也在呢  如果我们把她带来
What if Christine was here? What if we brought her to you?
我可以做到那个的  山姆
I can make that happen, Sam.
你不再是我的老板了
You know, you're not my boss anymore.
我现在是你哥哥手下的人
I work for your brother now.
那你总该认识钱吧
You still know what this is?
我们这款产品是为国家安全局
We developed it for N.S.A.
监视国内情况设计的
domestic surveillance.
插入车内的USB接口
Plug it into the U.S.B. Port of the car.
20秒的时间  程序就会启动联结
Give it 20 seconds for the program to migrate.
之后  只要司机
After that, every time the driver
用车内免提打电话
makes a call through the hands-free,
电话就会被转接到这里
You get the call on this.
要进车里面的时候
Now as for getting into the car,
用这个
use that.
红外干扰器  2008年以后制造的汽车
Infrared scrambler-- unlocks 99% of automobiles
99%都能用这个解锁
manufactured after 2008.
难道不是你进车里面吗
I thought you would be the one getting into the car.
我只是给你送来技术工具
I'm just bringing you your own tech,
不是要跟你一起犯罪
Not committing a felony.
要让我去做  我开价可是高得很
For that, I'd need a lot more money,
而且我还得获得你哥哥的同意
and I'd have to clear it with your brother.
滚吧
Go.
求之不得
Pleasure.
人事档案情况
Personnel files?
核弹发射钥匙被偷的时候
There were 35 crew members on board
潜艇上有35名船员
when the launch key was stolen.
你觉得看这些能搞清楚是谁偷的吗
You think you can figure out who took it by reading these?
我觉得一个人的生活经历
I think the sum of a person's life
可以通过一些片段推测出来
can be deduced from its parts.
那个内鬼一定跟中情局保持着联系
The traitor must be communicating with Langley.
怎么做到的
How?
说实话  长官  我不知道
Honestly, sir, I don't know.
找回钥匙不是关键任务之一  副艇长
Finding the key is not a priority, X.O.
而是最关键任务
It's the priority.
而且记住了  你的钥匙也是他们的目标
And remember, your key is a target, too.
我要对艇员们实行宵禁
I'm instituting a curfew on the crew.
我知道失去钥匙
I understand what it means
意味着什么  长官  真的
to be without our launch key, sir, I do,
我也在马不停蹄地寻找着
and I am searching without rest.
但我们应该考虑一下艇员们的士气
But we need to start thinking about the morale of the crew here.
在恰当的时间和地点
There's a time and place
我们的确会考虑艇员们的士气
for taking the morale of the crew into consideration.
但现在  目前  我的潜艇上有个内鬼
But right now, right here, there is a traitor on my boat
让我们命悬一线
who has put us in a position of mortal weakness.
我们在一座岛屿上找一把钥匙
We are searching for a key on an island.
"海底捞针"也比不上这个
"Needle in a haystack" doesn't even come close.
但我会一直找下去  直到你叫停
But I will continue searching until you tell me to stop.
恕我冒犯  长官  但你得看看艇员们了
But with respect, sir, you need to start looking at the crew,
而不是光看档案
not just their files.
其实...
You know...
埋葬人的不只是我们
we're not the only ones putting people in the ground.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
那队追杀我们的秘密行动组
That black-ops team that came after us.
海军今天早上把他们埋了
Navy buried them this morning.
是啊
Yeah.
4张棺材
Four graves.
那支队伍有多少人
How many were on that team?
那第5个秘密行动组的组员呢
Where's the fifth black op?
只有4个
There were four.
你们埋了4个  但是总共有5个人
No, you buried four, but there were five.
说明还有一个活着
One's still alive.
如果是这样  我会知道的
If that were true, I'd know.
艇长或副艇长会告诉我的
Captain or the X.O. would have told me.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
我们走吧  金
Let's go, King.
长官  有没有秘密行动组的人
Sir, did any of the black ops
在BZ袭击中幸存
survive the B.Z. Attack?
没有
No.
为什么这么问
Why do you ask?
鉴于你在找BZ  我忽然想到了而已  长官
Just thought it was relevant since you're searching for B.Z., sir.
你进步很快
You advanced rapidly.
你具体是怎么到我的艇上来就职的
How was it, specifically, you ended up on my boat?
我一直觉得是因为你要求我来
I always assumed it was because you asked for me.
或许我父亲动用了什么关系
Maybe my father pulled some strings.
我不知道  长官
I really don't know, sir.
我希望是因为我有能力
I like to think I'm best qualified,
我证明了自己
that I proved myself.
谢谢你  上尉
Thank you, lieutenant.
对不起  上尉
Sorry, lieutenant.
你背包里装的什么
I-- what's in the backpack?
没什么  长官
Nothing, ma'am.
你知道艇长执行了宵禁吧
You know the captain's implemented a curfew?
知道  长官  在那之前我们会回来的
Yes, ma'am, but we'll be back by then.
就是我和几个女孩们
It was just gonna be me and a couple of girls,
在熄灯号响起之前最后狂欢一下
blow off a little steam before lights out.
对不起  长官  我不应该这样的
I'm sorry, ma'am. I should know better.
去吧  就当你没见过我
Go. You didn't see me.
上尉
Uh... lieutenant?
怎么了  科泰兹
What is it, Cortez?
你现在忙着吗
You doing anything right now?
我警告过你
I warned you.
你告诉你的...
You tell your...
朋友们
friends...
你的老大
Your boss...
以及你的孩子们
And your kids...
不许对海军贩毒
Don't deal to the navy.
再有下次  子弹就打进你的脑袋里
Next time, these go in your head.
你可以不用假装查看推特消息了  辛克莱小姐
You can stop pretending to check your twitter, Ms. Sinclair.
海军上将不会来了
The admiral isn't coming.
你是谁
Who are you?
福雷斯特
Forrest.
我是他的朋友
I'm a friend of his.
现在也是你的朋友
And a friend of yours now.
我不知道你在胡说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
谢帕德上将已经入狱了
Admiral Shepard is in jail,
而且是严格禁止探视的那种密牢
and not the kind where they have visiting hours.
你知道阿曼达・斯昭吗
Do you know Amanda Straugh?
白宫高级顾问  生前喜欢威士忌
White house senior advisor, loved scotch,
上周飞越太平洋时死于空难当中
died last week in a plane crash over the Pacific.
并非如此
Not exactly.
斯昭在圣玛丽娜岛谈判时遭枪击身亡
Straugh was shot and killed during negotiations on Sainte Marina.
总统有问题
The president has a problem.
他说这个女人的尸体葬身海底
He says this woman's body is at the bottom of the ocean.
如果这张照片通过媒体公之于众
If this photo were to show up on the news,
民众们就会知道他撒了谎
millions would know he's lying about it.
他们可能会开始疑心他还撒了别的什么谎
They might start wondering what else he's lying about.
等等  等等  我以为我们在说的是
Wait, wait, wait. I thought we were talking about
我们撒过的最成功的谎
the best lies we ever pulled off.
我可没有这样的黑历史
I don't have any of those.
我可是一直全A优等生
You are looking at a straight-A,
从没作过弊  从没惹过麻烦
never cheated, never got in trouble.
真可悲  不过是事实
Sad, but true.
好吧  刚刚那是谎言
Okay, all that was a lie.
你呢  谢帕德上尉
What about you, Lieutenant Shepard?
她们得到的A再多也没你多吧
Yeah, they don't make 'em more straight-A than you.
我挺随意的
Well, I'm relaxing.
是吗  你的表情可不像啊  上尉
Yeah? Then start looking relaxed, Lieutenant.
那些只不过是矿物样本
They're just mineral samples.
你和塞拉特拥有一样的小瓶
You and Serrat have the same vials.
我不知道你去他那里分享什么秘密
You were at his place sharing I don't know what.
我没必要向你报告
I don't have to answer you.
不  你必须告诉我
Yes, you do.
不然呢  你要像打那个男人一样打我吗
Or what, you'll hurt me like you hurt that man?
-当时我意识不清醒  -得了吧
- That wasn't me. - Oh, come on.
嘿  你干嘛呢
Hey, what are you doing?
看看这个
Look at this.
不  快关掉
No, turn it off.
不  不  不
No. No, no, no.
你看我像是很享受的样子吗
Does it look like I'm enjoying this?
好了  快关掉
Okay, turn it off.
不  不  不  不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
-你看我像是很喜欢这样吗  -山姆
- Does it look like I want this? - Sam.
一切都会好起来的  我保证
Everything's gonna be different now, I promise.
别说了
Stop it.
这是什么
What's this?
无论我走多远  总会回到你身边
I always find my way back, don't I?
在我入军校之前
Well, before I went into the academy,
我曾经替别人参加过高考
I-I took the S.A.T.s for someone else.
那女孩  她真的很聪明
You know, the girl-- the girl was really smart,
但是她一进考场就犯晕
but she just couldn't take tests.
她患有焦虑症
You know, she had this anxiety disorder,
她们家很穷
and her family had no money,
所以  如果她拿不到奖学金
So if, uh, she didn't get a scholarship,
她就上不了大学
she couldn't go to college.
所以我就冒充了她的身份  替她考了
So I copied her I.D. and took the test.
我觉得现在已经过了诉讼时效了
I think the statute of limitations has passed.
敬诉讼时效
To the statute of limitations.
我能问你一些事吗  科泰兹
Can I ask you something, Cortez?
当然  长官
Yes, ma'am.
之前在塞拉特那里是怎么回事
What happened with Serrat?
你跟瑞德和约什在那里被关押了几天
You were locked in that room with Red and Josh for days.
发生什么事了
What happened?
我知道大家都认为我做了什么
I know what everyone thinks I did.
但我没有
But I didn't.
我答应过他  做他的耳目
I promised him I'd be his eyes and ears
前提是他让我们活下来
if he'd let us live.
向他报告潜艇上的情况
Tell him what was going on with the sub.
几小时后  他杀了瑞德
A few hours later, he killed Red.
约定也就失效了
Deal was off.
你会那样做吗
Would you have?
当个叛徒吗
Been a traitor?
我曾养过一只狗
I had a dog...
当时我还是个小孩
when I was a little kid,
有一天  它反了  咬了我
And one day, it turned on me, bit me.
我爸爸  射杀了它
My dad... shot it.
他说  如果小狗反了  你永远不能再信任它
Said once a dog turns on you, you never trust it again.
唯一的办法就是弄死它
Only thing to do is put it down.
对待叛徒也一样
Same with a traitor.
克里斯蒂  你想让美国人民
Christine, what would you like the American people
知道你丈夫的什么情况
to know about your husband?
政府一直称我丈夫为恐怖分子
The administration keeps calling my husband a terrorist.
那他们为何还想与他和谈
But then why were they trying to negotiate with him?
又为何对和谈内容高度保密
And why are they keeping those negotiations such a secret
甚至不惜捏造阿曼达・斯昭的死亡一事
that they had to lie about Amanda Straugh's death?
你这是相当严重的指控
You're making some very serious allegations.
这看上去像是空难造成的吗
Does this look like a plane crash?
阿曼达・斯昭被政府自己人枪击
Amanda Straugh was shot by one of the government's own people,
而白宫试图掩盖这一真相
and the white house is trying to cover it up,
正如同他们试图掩盖关于
Just like they are trying to cover up the truth
我丈夫和美军舰科罗拉多号的真相一样
about my husband and the U.S.S. "Colorado."
多谢  女人
Thank you, mama.
谁把你打成这样的
Who did this to you?
你觉得呢
Who do you think?
好了  全体注意  集合
All right. Listen up. Fall in.
所有人  集合
Everybody, fall in.
都站好了  快点  立正
Tighten it up. Let's go. Lock it down.
别发牢骚了  赶紧来集合
Stop your bellyaching and fall in here.
中尉看见一个小男孩坐在路边
So the Junior l.T. sees this little boy sitting on the sidewalk...
玩着一堆粪便
playing with a pile of manure.
中尉就问小男孩
The L.T. asks the little boy,
"你玩这堆粪便干什么呢"
"What are you doing playing with that manure?"
小男孩说  "我在做军士"
Little boy says, "I'm building an N.C.O."
上尉跑回总部
L.T. runs back to company H.Q.,
找来长官  长官也问小男孩
gets his section chief, who asks the little boy,
"孩子  你为什么玩一堆粪便呢"
"Son... why are you playing with a pile of manure?"
小男孩说  "我在造军士"
Little boy says, "I'm building an N.C.O."
长官又去找来水手长
Chief goes and gets the C.O.B.,
水手长也过去问小男孩
who goes back to the little boy.
"孩子  你  你..."
"Hey, kid, what are you-- what--what--
"你玩粪便干什么"
"what are you doing playing with that manure?"
小男孩说
Little boy says...
"我在造军士"
"I'm building an N.C.O."
"你为什么要造军士"
"Why are you building an N.C.O.?"
小男孩顿了顿说  "长官  因为
Little boy pauses and says, "Because, sir,
"我便便不够用  造不了长官"
"I don't have enough crap to build an officer."
你们知道培养一个西点军校学生
What do you get when you breed
和一个陆军能得到什么吗
a West Point Cadet and a groundhog?
能多踢六周的烂橄榄球
Six more weeks of bad football.
为什么陆军的橄榄球队
How come the army football team
场外不提供冰了
doesn't have ice on the sidelines?
因为知道怎么做的人毕业了
The guy with the recipe graduated.
对  就是这样
That's right.
就是这样  大家听着
That's right. Now listen up.
大家听着  听着
Listen up! Listen up! Listen up!
我知道最近大家经历了很多事
I know we've put you through a hell of a lot lately.
我能跟你们说的就是  那是有原因的
And all I can tell you-- it's for a good reason.
但是
But...
现在我命令你们
I hereby order you...
尽情享受91年陆海两军橄榄球赛
to enjoy the 1991 army/navy football game.
先剧透一下  陆军输了
Spoiler alert-- the crunchies don't win.
快点来  快点来
There you go. There you go. There you go.
大家一起来
有你们这样的艇员
You are the best crew
副艇长真是三生有幸
an X.O. could have the honor of leading.
谢谢大家  我很感激
Thank you, and I appreciate it.
海军  海军
Navy! Navy!
长官  给你拿了瓶啤酒
Sir. Brought you a beer,
如果你想喝的话
if you want it.
谢谢
Thank you.
你应该回去和其他人一起看比赛
You should go back and watch the game with the crew.
我只是...
I just...
我只是想说明一下
I just wanted to state, for the record,
我会一直支持你  艇长
that I'm with you, captain,
绝不改变
all the way...
无论何时
whenever you need me.
科泰兹  谢谢
Cortez, thank you.
但是你不应该单独找我
But you should not seek me out alone.
我们都必须遵守规章程序
There's an order and a morality that we both have to follow.
可是现在一切都变了  艇长
Well, it seems like everything's changed, captain.
并不是一切
Not everything.
明白吗
Understood?
你拿着什么  山姆
What do you got there, Sam?
是你们
Oh, boy.
你在耍我吗
Are you kidding me?
当然是  你们抓住的那个人
Sure. I mean, the guy you got in there
杀了我两个兄弟
killed two of my pals.
所以是应该给瓶冰啤奖励一下
So why not let him enjoy a cold one?
我需要知道他知道的情况
I need to know what he knows.
那我们三个目标一样
Yeah, that makes three of us.
别多管闲事
Stand down.
让我们做我们想做的
Let us do what we do.
搞定之后  我们给他在丛林里好好安葬他
When we're done, we got a nice resting place for him out in the jungle.
听我说  我一直在做他的工作
Listen to me. I've been working him.
我已经快建立起信任了
I'm building trust and I'm close.
所以现在你要一边待着
So right now you gotta back off
让我善始善终
and let me finish what I started.
你觉得他知道什么
What do you think he knows?
我觉得他知道怎么让大家回家
I think he knows how to get us all home.
行了  金
Come on, King.
这家伙是个行外人  我们走
This guy's an amateur. Let's go.
不  霍普  我们让步
No, Hop. We fall back.
这个人暂时归副艇长
X.O.'s got this one. For now.
你睡眠怎么样
How are you sleeping?
不好吗
Not good?
想知道你妻子睡眠如何吗
Wonder how your wife's sleeping?
美国联合特种作战司令部给你看了克里斯蒂的资料
So what, J.S.O.C. gave you the download on Christine,
所以你就以为你了解我了吗
and now you think you know me?
不  他们给我看了你的资料
No. They gave me the download on you--
朝鲜  指着你的头的枪  扣动扳机声
North Korea, the gun to your head, the click.
我知道你一直在自责
I know you can't stop blaming yourself
那七个人的死
for those seven men who died
才换得你能回家
so you could make it back home.
可是现在马库斯又把你送进监狱了
Now Marcus has landed you in prison again.
你的行为是值得肯定
Yeah, it's beautiful,
但是  还是面对现实吧
but... let's be real about what it is.
你愿意为那个人付出多少
How much are you willing to give that man?
休眠者肯定会用安全的无线电频道
Your sleeper will be communicating with Langley
和兰利总部联系
by a secure radio channel,
也就是说岛上有处通讯点
which means there's a comm site somewhere on this island.
找到通讯点就能抓住休眠者
Find that site, you'll have him.
这么说
Now...
你准备好自力更生了
You ready to start helping yourself?
如果我们要这么做的话
If we were to do this,
具体要怎么办
how would we do it?
很简单地诱捕
Simple snatch and grab.
让马库斯远离众人的视线  但是好好对待他
Marcus will be kept out of sight, but treated well
你控制这里
while you run things here
逼迫白宫那边换人掌权
forcing a change of guard at the White House.
然后让新政府安排一次特赦
Then the new administration arranges for amnesty...
赦免你们所有人
for all of you.
秘密行动组的第五个人还活着
That fifth black op is alive.
艇长和副艇长把他锁起来了
Your captain and your X.O. are keeping him locked away.
你总是课堂上第一个举手的  是吧
Bet you always raised your hand first in class, didn't you?
别过来
No, stop!
别走近我
Don't come near me.
大家都离她远一点
Everybody keep away from her!
巡航导弹
斯奈德  保持冷静
Snyder, you need to stay calm.
是定时炸弹
It's on a timer.
还剩多少时间
How much time is left?
我不知道  快点弄走
I don't know. Take it off.
-快点从我身上弄走  -不行
- Just take it off of me. - I can't.
线路绕着皮带扣
It's wired to the buckle.
你得尽量不要哆嗦
You gotta stop shaking.
我尽力了
I'm trying.
再努把力
Try harder.
冷静下来  没事的
Hey, calm down. It's okay.
有我们在
We got you.
还剩多少时间
How much time is left on it?
很多
Plenty.
快把它从我身上弄下来
Just take it out from me.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
怎么回事
What happened?
没事  没事的  放心
Hey, nothing. It's okay. It's okay.
格蕾丝
Grace.
格蕾丝  我需要照明
Grace, I need eyes.
拿着  好了
Here. Okay.
现在我要拔出红线  但不能碰到黄线
Now I gotta get that red wire without touching the yellow.
能帮我摁住那根线吗
Can you keep the lead away?
黄色的那根
The yellow lead.
时间到了
Time's up.
你是不是疯了
Are you out of your mind?
白宫的律师给我打电话
I have White House lawyers calling me
说你今天接受了录像采访
about this interview you taped today.
这完全有违我对你的叮嘱
You did the exact opposite of what I told you.
那个记者说这么做也许会有用
The reporter said that maybe it would help.
记者为了拿到消息什么话都会说
The reporter's gonna say whatever gets her the story!
还有你从哪儿搞到的阿曼达・斯昭的照片
And where the hell did you get this picture of Amanda Straugh?
有人把它放进我信箱里了
Somebody put it in my mailbox.
有人放进你信箱里  你有没有搞错
Somebody put it in your mailbox? What is wrong with you?
别冲我吼  你没资格冲我吼
Stop yelling at me! You don't get to yell at me.
我已经尽力做到最好了
I am doing the best that I can here.
你知道我要承受多大的压力吗
Do you understand how much pressure I am under?
我一个人面对这一切
I am all alone here,
自己的丈夫在外面
and my husband is out there somewhere,
随时都有可能丧命
about to get killed at any second.
你说得对  是我的错
You're right. It's my fault.
我应该看着你的
I should've kept an eye on you.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是...
It's just, um...
那些感觉一下子全涌上来了
It's all just starting to get to me...
空荡荡的家  一个人睡
The empty house, the sleeping alone,
更何况我根本睡不着
except I can't even sleep
-破水龙头老是滴个不停  -冷静下来
- because the damn faucet won't stop dripping. - Hey, hey, calm down.
一切都会好的
It's all gonna be fine.
我帮你看看水龙头吧
Why don't I take a look at the faucet?
我需要一把长头钳
I'm gonna need, uh, long-nose pliers for this.
汽车后备箱里有工具包
I got a tool kit in the trunk.
什么  等一下
What? Wait.
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
听着...
Look...
很抱歉今天让你失望了
I'm sorry that I disappointed you today.
现在只有你一个人还在帮我
You are the only one that's left that's fighting for me.
没有你我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do without you.
不  不行
No, no.
对不起
I-I'm sorry.
是我的原因吗
Was it just me?
不知道  我只是做不到
I don't know. But it can't be me.
我现在心里乱糟糟的
Look, I'm having very confusing feelings right now
你能...再给我一段时间吗
and... can you just be patient with that?
当然
Of course.
你很厉害
You were good.
你也是
So were you.
什么  怎么了
What? What?
一直想看你长发的样子
Been wondering what that looks like.
只此一次
One time thing.
当然
Sure.
谢谢
Thanks.
也谢谢你
Thank you.
他人呢
Where is he?
找我吗
Where am I?
看来你还不清楚自己该找谁
I don't think you know what you are looking for.
把他带上来
Bring him.
我猜你是在找
I presume you are looking for the man
往你的人身上绑炸弹的人吧
who strapped a bomb to one of your people?
我听说了
I just heard.
看见没
You see?
我把他抓来了
I caught him for you.
我是来找你的
I came for you.
我  是啊  你可以把我带走
Uh, me. Yeah, yeah, you could take me,
但是大家不会同意的
but the people won't allow it
因为我是他们的朋友  他们爱我
Because I'm their friend, and they love me.
他们知道我是清白的
And they know I have done nothing.
是这个人绑的炸弹
This is the man responsible for your bomb.
可悲啊
It's sad.
他想让我对他另眼相看
He thought it would impress me.
告诉他
Tell him.
都是我的注意
It was my idea.
是我一个人干的
I did it. Just me.
你们应该感谢我帮忙抓到了他
You should be grateful I brought this man to justice.
我会合理处置他的
I will deal with him appropriately.
不用了  我来
No. I will.
这个人已经承认
This man has admitted
蓄意屠杀我军人员的罪名
to the attempted mass murder of my crew.
再敢挑衅我
Try me again,
我会做你的法官  陪审员并亲自了结你
and I will be your judge, jury, and executioner.
克里斯蒂
Christine.
有人给他打电话
Someone's calling him.
已连接
喂
Hello.
我是科利  有什么新消息
This is Curry. What do you have?
到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
有人把照片放进她信箱里了
Somebody put the photo in her mailbox,
说明是白宫里有人走漏了风声
which means you've got a leak in the White House,
你不要再说是我没看住她了
so you can stop blaming me for not keeping her in line.
听着  我不想再干下去了
And look, I don't want to do this anymore.
你还想不想见丹尼尔了
Do you want to see Daniel again?
当然想
Of course I do.
他是我儿子
He's my son.
我想说的是  你已经把她逼入绝境了
All I'm saying is, you've got her in an impossible situation.
还能指望她怎么做呢
What do you expect her to do?
让我给她点儿线索
Let me throw her a line.
一切按原计划行事
Just stick to the plan
别太入戏了  保罗
and don't get too attached, Paul.
情况变化无常
The parameters can always change.
再联系
I'll check in later.
山姆
Sam.
发生的这些事真疯狂  对吧
Everything that happened was crazy, right?
他们给我们下药  我们都中毒了
They drugged us. The B.Z. Affected us all.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
只有美国人才会为一个吻道歉
Only an American would apologize for a kiss.
我不是和塞拉特共事
I'm not working with Serrat.
我只是在还我前男友的债
I am paying a debt my ex-boyfriend had.
塞拉特雇他从这里土壤中检查稀有矿物
Serrat paid him to test the soil here for rare earth minerals.
那些就是土壤样本
That's what the samples were for.
这座岛很值钱
This island-- it is worth a lot of money.
好的
Okay.
我只是想
I wanted you to know
让你知道我没有骗你
so you would not think I lied to you.
但你得替我保密
But I need you to promise me you will keep it secret,
不仅仅对塞拉特
and not only from Serrat.
对任何人都保密
From everybody.
我现在没法向你作任何承诺
I can't promise you anything right now.
好吧
Okay.
那是你的决定
That can be your choice,
但你现在知道我不会欺骗你
but... now you know that I will not lie to you.
这是我的决定
That's my choice.
放松  放松
All right, easy now. Easy now.
天啊
God--
你好啊
Hey.
你们是这座岛的囚犯
Your men are prisoners on this island.
你为何这么生气
Why are you so angry about them
他们只不过付钱给我让他们离开
paying me for a few hours of escape?
你凭什么觉得你可以控制别人
Why do you feel as though you can control what other people do?
你为什么这么害怕
Why are you so afraid?
我在世界很多地方都待过
I've lived all over the world.
你这种人我见多了
I've seen many men like you.
我觉得你想喝一杯吧
You have a thirst, I think.
你好哪一口
What is your particular poison?
海洛因  可卡因
Heroin? Cocaine?
不是  不是
No. No.
给你来点异域特色的
For you, something more exotic.
窒息性的
Apnoea?
羟甲唑啉
Oxy?
芬太尼
Fentanyl?
眼睛可不会说谎
The eyes don't lie.
你瞳孔刚才像这样  朋友
Your pupils just went like this, my friend.
我戒了
I kicked that--
我戒了很久了
I kicked that a long time ago.
都结束了
End of story.
是吗  像你这样的人
Oh, yeah. You know, for someone like you,
可没那么轻易的能摆脱这个  对吧
the story never really ends, does it?
这是强力止痛药  对吧
This is a powerful painkiller, yes?
我知道疼痛的感觉
I know pain.
你记得我母亲吗
You recall my mother?
我没那闲工夫
I haven't had the pleasure.
不不  你见过
Ah, but you have.
她只有一只胳膊
She's with one arm.
是的  是的  你当然见过过她
Yes. Yes, yes, surely, surely you noticed her.
我这么认为
Aah! Aah! Yes, I think.
知道吗  我还是孩子时
You see, when I was a boy,
有人闯进村子
some men came to my village.
他们想把我带进丛林里
They wanted to take me into the bush with them.
我母亲想去阻止他们
My mother tried to stop them.
放开我
Get 'em away from me!
她生我时只有十二岁
She was only 12 when I was born,
她是我母亲
so she was my mother,
但她更像我姐姐
but she was also like my sister.
那伙人跟我说
The men, they said to me,
他们说  "小子  你拿着这把大砍刀
they said, "You go take this machete now, eah bo.
"去把你妈的胳膊砍了否则我们就杀了她"
"You're going to chop off your mother's arm or we will kill her."
你能想象吗
Can you imagine?
我从那天起就成了战士
That was my first day as a soldier.
上帝啊
Aah! God!
我来帮你止痛
Now I'm going to take the pain away.
舒服了吧
Yes.
这个给你留着再疼的时候用
This is for when the pain comes back.
就是你啊  不就是你吗
You know it's you, you know it's you.
我们现在变成行刑者了吗
So we're executioners now?
别无选择
There's no other option.
你和布斯谈过有什么收获吗
Have your conversations with Booth borne fruit?
他说无论休眠者是谁
Well, he claims that whoever the sleeper agent is
在岛上肯定有通讯点
has a comm site on the island
方便与他上级联系
to communicate with their handlers.
他还说要想回去
He also claims that we're the resistance
最大的阻碍是我们
to what's going on back home.
他也许是对的
Maybe he's right.
我们不去找钥匙了
Okay. We stop looking for the key.
不再搜查船员
No more rousting the crew.
我们去找通讯点
We look for the comm site.
找到叛徒
We find the traitor,
就能找到钥匙
we find the key.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
你去把有权力下达这个命令的人叫来
I'm not going to annihilate 4.3 million Pakistanis
否则我绝不会屠杀430万巴基斯坦国民
without hearing from someone whose authority I recognize.
自己人居然想击沉我们
Our own people tried to sink us?
我们接管了圣玛丽娜岛上的
We have commandeered the NATO early warning station
北约预警雷达站
on the island of Sainte Marina.
我宣布  这座岛周围
I am declaring a 200-mile
方圆两百英里的地区为无人地带
no-man's-land around this island.
若敢挑衅  我们便同归于尽
Test us, and we will all burn.
勿谓言之不预
You've been warned.
唯一知道你还活着的
The only two people who know you're still alive
就是站在你面前的两个人
are the two you're looking at.
你应该庆幸
And that's lucky for you.
我知道有好几个海豹突击队员想向你"问好"
I know a couple of navy seals that would love to come say hi.
那第5个秘密行动组的组员呢
Where's the fifth black op?
只有4个
There were four.
你们埋了4个  但是总共有5个人
No, you buried four, but there were five.
我的律师保罗・威尔斯
My lawyer Paul Wells,
他是山姆的至交  他一直都很棒
he's an old friend of Sam's, and he's been amazing.
不过他是政府派来监视我
But he's a government agent sent to spy on me
策反我跟山姆敌对的特工
and turn me against Sam.
插入车内的USB接口
Plug it into the U.S.B. port of the car.
只要司机用车内免提打电话
Every time the driver makes a call through the hands-free,
电话就会自动转接到这里
you get the call on this.
为什么要偷发射钥匙  为什么不联系外界
Why steal the firing key? Why not reach out?
为什么不形成联盟
Why not form an alliance?
艇长之间一直有传言说
The word among sub captains for a while
中情局在每艘核潜艇上都安插了休眠者
has been that the CIA has a sleeper agent on every nuclear sub.
以防哪个艇长发疯生出糊涂念头
Just in case some crazy captain gets the wrong idea.
休眠者肯定会用安全的无线电频道
Your sleeper will be communicating with Langley
和兰利总部联系
by a secure radio channel,
也就是说岛上有处通讯点
which means there's a comm site somewhere on this island.
我们去找通讯点
We look for the comm site.
找到叛徒  就能找到钥匙
We find the traitor, we find the key.
好了  大家听着
All right. Listen up, people.
五天后  会有一艘船获许通过封锁区
In five days, a ship will be allowed through the blockade
把那些选择离开的人
to transport those of you who have elected to leave
送回美国
back to the States.
那艘船还会带来食物和物资
This ship will also be delivering food and provisions
一定比我们近期吃的豆子和大米好得多
a whole lot better than the beans and rice we've had lately.
太好了
Yeah!
我们也协商获得了24小时的探访时间
We've also negotiated a 24-hour visit
让你们可以和配偶家人团聚一下
with your spouses and family members.
稍后会跟大家再说说具体情况
I'll have more details shortly,
但是很多人会再次见到家人的
but many of you are gonna see your family again.
安德斯  虽然那不是回家
Hey, Anders, I know it's not going home,
但是至少你可以见一见你妻子
but at least you're gonna get to see your wife.
她不会来的
She's not gonna be on that ship.
你觉得呢
So what do you think?
我也不知道  有点美好的太不真实了
I don't know. It seems too good to be true, no?
政府正在不惜一切
The government is spinning every top on the table
获取良好的公关形象
to buy some good P.R..
你知道他们不会让克里斯蒂来的
You know they're not gonna let Christine come.
也不会让格蕾丝或者我的家人来
No one for Grace or me either.
对  他们想挑拨
Right. Well, they want to drive a wedge
长官和艇员之间的关系  是吧
between the officers and enlisted, yeah?
对  他们把我们归为一切麻烦的根源
Yeah, sure. They cast us as the cause of all their troubles,
让艇员们想到他们错过的天伦之乐
remind them what they're missing at home.
真是个高招  他们让我陷入了困境
It's a smart move, and they've got me in a bind.
你只要答应  他们就会高兴
You say "Yes," they look good.
你若不答应  那你就是个疯狂的混蛋
You say "No," you keep looking like the crazy bastard
对自己的艇员毫不关心
who doesn't give a damn about his crew.
正是如此
That's it.
长官
Hey, sir.
我们还缺一把发射钥匙
We're still down a launch key.
一旦发生争端  我们可毫无回击之力
This thing goes sideways, we're defenseless.
所有离开这里的人都要搜身
Everyone who leaves this place gets searched.
我们是少了一把钥匙
We may not have one of our keys,
但是我们不能让别人将此事告诉我们的敌人
but I'm not gonna let someone prove that to our enemies.
-好的  -中情局的那个朋友怎么样了
- Okay. - How's it going with our friend from the, uh, CIA?
六天以来  他就只见过我
I'm the only face he's seen for six days.
他喜欢跟我谈  所以...
And he likes to talk, so--
好  让他继续说下去  看看能发现什么
Okay. Keep him talking. See what you can find out.
一百年前  我们自给自足
A hundred years ago, we were self-sufficient.
我们的文化很单纯
Our culture was pure.
那正是吸引我回来的原因
That's what seduced me back to this island.
船上有足够的物资
There are enough provisions on the ship
可以让我们至少再维持一个月
to feed us all for at least a month.
一个月  塔妮
A month? Tani.
最近一磅面粉都涨到多少钱了
How much is a pound of flour going for these days?
抱歉  父亲  我不想掺和这件事
Sorry, father. I'm not letting you drag me into this.
你是不是需要帮助来对付塞拉特
Do you need help dealing with Serrat?
塞拉特从不对我的人找麻烦
Serrat leaves my people alone.
问题的根源是你们潜艇的到来
The problem begins and ends
也只有你们走了才算完
with that blockade of ships out there.
我一定会尽我所能
I will do everything in my power
处理好这个问题
to fix this.
要知道  你不能改变自己的本性
You know you can't fix what you are.
可能你是好意
And maybe your heart's in the right place,
但说到底  你们也不会比法国人好到哪里去
but finally, you're no better than the French
他们曾强占了这个小岛
when they took this island
攫取了一切值钱的东西
and raided it for anything of value.
确实是
That's true.
本性难移
We are who we are.
现在我们就在这里  这点是不会改变的
And now we're here, and that might not change.
所以
So...
你就得做出改变了
You might have to.
他们也不好过
This is hard for them, too.
你觉得一只脚踩在水里
How long do you think you can keep one foot in the water
另一只踩在岸上  能撑多久
and the other on the shore?
蚱蜢
Grasshopper.
-是短波信号  所有很难定位  -地震
- It's shortwave. It's very difficult to locate. - Earthquake.
-我能判断出来是在岛上...-一
- So I can tell you it's on the island... - One.
-但是无法判断具体地点  -好
- But I can't tell you where. - Okay.
三  飞机场
Three. Airport.
-二  -还有什么事需要我帮忙吗
- Two. - Anything else I can do for you?
-跳房子  -没有了  要是找到
- Hopscotch. - No. Just tell me
-关于信号的其它信息  告诉我就行了  -六
- when you find out more about the signal. - Six.
四
Four.
-书呆子  -好
- Bookworm. - OK.
五  六
Five. Six.
葡萄藤
Grapevine.
一
One.
蚱蜢
Grasshopper.
六  二
Six. Two.
地震
Earthquake.
我们国家有一个节日
We have a holiday in our country
庆祝两种文化的相遇
that celebrates the coming together of two cultures.
面对艰难困苦  两种不同文化的人
Faced with great hardship, these two very different groups
形成了一个团体
formed what could only be called a community
作为生存手段
as a means to survive.
如同错过家乡的诸多传统节日一样
And as with many of our traditions back home,
我们已经错过了感恩节
we've already missed our Thanksgiving.
但是今晚
But tonight,
秉承节日精神传统
in the spirit of that holiday,
我们共享一切
what's ours is yours.
干杯  干杯
Here, here.
什么比较好吃
So... what's good here?
跟昨天的差不多
Pretty much the same as yesterday.
就是些面条
Some kind of noodle.
不管怎样  选择面条总不会太糟糕的
Guess you can't really go wrong with noodles.
你不用这样
You don't have to do this.
哪样
Do what?
闲聊  增加自己的魅力指数
Chitchat. Turn on the charm.
我刚刚是在那样吗
Oh, that's what I was doing?
"什么比较好吃"
"What's good here"?
我是真想知道
It's an honest question.
听着  我们之间发生的事已经发生了
Look, what happened between us happened,
现在我们要回到之前的样子
and now we should just go back to the way things were,
你继续当混蛋  我努力做好本职工作
with you being a jackass and me trying to do my job.
没必要把事情搞得奇奇怪怪的
No need for things to get weird.
对  这一点都不奇怪
Right, 'cause this isn't weird at all.
我以为你现在和那个酒吧女孩在一起
Look, I thought you were with the girl from the bar anyway.
她叫什么
What's her name?
塔妮
Tani.
对
Yeah.
她人很好  而且像是真的喜欢你
She's nice and she really seems to like you.
你不说我也知道
It's been known to happen.
艇长
Captain.
索菲追踪到通讯点了
Sophie tracked the comm site.
休眠者似乎在过去三天使用过两次
Looks like the sleeper's used it twice in the last three days.
使用的这么频繁
That's one time too many.
那个人一定是感觉到紧张的局势了
Whoever it is must be feeling the heat.
布斯有吐露什么信息吗
What's Booth offering?
尚未开口
Nothing yet.
-你信任他吗  -不
- You trust him? - Nope.
-很好  继续关注他  -好的
- Good. Stay on him. - Okay.
一旦饿极了
Get hungry enough...
无味的军用补给粮也能吃出鹅肝的味道
even a hoo-ah bar tastes like damn foie gras.
你吃过鹅肝吗
You ever have foie gras?
就好像一个人把一块精选肉片
Like someone took a prime filet and...
变成了黄油
turned it into butter.
要说最好吃的鹅肝
Best foie gras I ever had
还得是那家澳门小酒馆做的
was at this little bistro in Macao.
那儿的中国人很喜欢法国菜
The Chinese positively love their French food.
该死  肯德尔  我以为我们都说清楚了
Damn, Kendal. I thought we were past all this.
听着  布斯
Listen, Booth,
那个无线站点最近十分活跃
that radio site, it's active.
偷钥匙的人一定在暗中和国内联系
Whoever stole our launch key is talking back to home.
想猜猜对方会下达什么命令吗
You want to guess what the orders are gonna be?
我不喜欢猜
Don't much like guessing.
第一  用炸弹炸死我们  一劳永逸
One, they bomb us all to hell and be done with it.
第二  休眠者狗急跳墙
Two, the sleeper gets desperate
背地里把我和马库斯都干掉
and me and Marcus each get a bullet behind the ear.
至于你
And you...
会饿死在这里  被人遗忘
you starve to death, forgotten out here.
第三
Three...
你选择信任我  我们共同合作
You trust me. We work this thing together.
你坐在这儿  净说些没用的废话
You sit there and you talk platitudes.
你告诉我  我是你理想的合作人选
You tell me I'm the man for your job.
但迄今为止你提供的信息
You haven't given me one single thing
没有一样能为我所用
I can actually use, not one.
没关系  我明白  我都明白
And that's fine. I get it. I get it.
你想把控制权握在手中
You want to be in control.
你想谨慎行事  处处防范
You want to play your hand tight.
直到现在  我都没找到信任你的理由
But right now, you've given me no reason to trust you.
你只是个在等待时机的杀手
You're still just a killer waiting for the moment
你希望劝服我放了你
You talk me out of those cuffs.
你得证明自己值得信任才行  布斯
You gotta make me trust you, Booth.
加油  加油
Come on! Come on!
翻译：圈圈   萌Su   Silmar
翻译：Ethan   hammer_tank   胖大海胖
校对：Ethan   米苏
时间轴：贝壳   Cherry
后期：zzzyusa    总监：渔夫
不  等等  我还没看牌  我要...
No. See, I haven't pulled my cards yet. I'm gonna...
你昨晚没来啊
So you didn't come up last night.
他在哪儿
Where is he?
抓住他
Get him!
不知各位先生有何贵干
Can I help you gentlemen with something?
等等  他们是岛上的执法队
Wait. They're the law on the island.
出了什么事
What happened?
就是他
That's him.
-你们干什么  -等等  住手
- What? Whoa... - Wait! Wait! No!
别伤害他
Don't hurt him.
放开我  放开...
Get off me! Get...
你到底是哪边的  普塔卡
Whose side are you on, Putaika?
我没犯事  救命
I didn't do anything wrong! Help!
救命啊
Help!
请你们立刻放下武器
Hey, lower your weapon right now!
放下武器
Lower your weapon!
谁能告诉我发生了什么事
Who wants to tell me what's going on here?
他们说你的手下将艾瑞塔
They're saying your man took Erita
掳进丛林里强奸了她
into the jungle and raped her.
告诉我这不是真的
Tell me that's not true.
我没有  艇长  我发誓  她在撒谎
I didn't do it, Captain! I swear. She's lying.
根据土法
According to local laws,
他将被砍100刀  以示惩戒
he'll be punished by caning a hundred cuts.
如果他侥幸存活  脖子上将被烙下烙印
If he survives, a brand will be burned into his neck
作为其所犯罪行的永久印记
as a permanent mark of the crime he committed.
-烙印  -老天  不能让他们这么做
- A brand? - Oh, my God. You can't let them do that to me.
马上把他放下来
Cut him down. Now.
此事与你无关  艇长
This is not your affair, Captain.
是我岛内的事物
This is an island matter.
把他放下来
Cut him down!
我们是有法规的
We have laws.
你这么做不合适
This isn't right.
也许很合适
Might is right.
你有你的法规  但我要救我的人
You may have your laws, but I'll have my man.
你认为一个强奸犯不该受到惩罚吗
You don't believe a rapist deserves to be punished?
应该
I do.
但我不接受没有证据的指控
But I don't accept that's what he is, not without proof.
我不认识这个女人
I don't know this woman,
我也没有听过她的控词
And I haven't heard her accusations.
我听过  她说的是事实
I have. She speaks the truth.
那只是她的一面之词
Well, that's an opinion,
对我而言  一切都是塞拉特编造的谎言
and for all I know, this is all a concoction of Serrat's.
我们的人不能还没有经过法定审判
We do not subject our people to summary judgment
就被当场判罪并处以极刑
and punishment without due process.
我们的法规已经存在几百年了
Our system has worked for hundreds of years.
在我这儿是行不通的
It doesn't work for me.
哈尔・安德斯隶属于美国海军
Hal Anders is a member of the United States Navy.
他必须依照我们的法律接受审判
He'll have a trial under my rules.
如果按照你们的法律审他
You try that man under your rules,
岛上没有人会相信审判结果
no one on the island will believe the verdict
而且他们会认为你是个暴君
or believe you to be less than a tyrant.
那我也只能忍受这份失望了
That's a disappointment I'll have to live with.
对方同意按军方的规矩进行审讯
We agreed on a military-style trial.
陪审团有7个人  3名我们的人
Seven member jury, three from the "Colorado,"
3名岛民  1名中立者
three from the island, one neutral.
超过5票即为有罪
It'll take five votes to convict.
我不知道  长官
I don't know, sir.
难道不该让他在"科罗拉多号"上
I think he should be tried on the "Colorado"
接受自己人的审讯吗
by his own people, no?
他只要出了艘潜艇
Once he stepped foot off this boat,
事情就没那么简单了
it got complicated.
这点你清楚  他也清楚
You know that. He knew that.
应该让岛民知道我们并不畏惧真相
This island needs to know that we're not afraid of the truth.
如果安德斯有罪
And if Anders is found guilty,
我们会对他实施惩罚
we'll do the punishing.
第7个陪审员是谁
So who's the seventh juror?
我已经跟索菲谈过了
I already spoke to Sophie.
长官  你知道安德斯是艇上唯一一个
Sir, you know Anders is the only one left
有资格掌管核反应堆的士兵吧
who's rated to work the reactor, right?
我很清楚他的宝贵价值
I'm aware of how valuable he is.
我在核潜艇上执行过两次任务
I did two tours in the nukes.
我可以暂时代替他
I can hold it down for a while.
之后呢
And after that?
如果出了什么岔子你愿意被困在里面吗
You really want to be stuck down there if something goes wrong?
我只希望安德斯没有强奸那个女人
I want Anders not to have done what the woman says he did.
如果真是他呢
What if he did?
我们先姑且认为他是无辜的吧
Let's give him the benefit of the doubt.
克里斯蒂还能怎么样  很生气呗
How do you think Christine was? She was pissed.
很好  她对我们越愤怒
Good. The angrier she is at us,
就越会感激你对她的关怀
the more grateful she'll be when you come through for her.
告诉她你动用了私人关系
Tell her you pulled some strings.
为她争取到了登船的资格
You're getting her on that boat.
跟她说她就要见到自己的丈夫了
Tell her she's getting to see her husband.
她一定会对你知无不言的
She'll trust you with anything after that.
老天  竟然设计让他成为你的白马王子
God. They're setting him up to be your white knight.
他们真的觉得这年头还有女人会上当吗
Do they really think women still fall for that?
-抱歉  -什么
- Sorry.  -What?
山姆  海军大英雄让你的生活不再单调
Sam. Big navy hero sweeps you away from your drab little life.
你有时真像个狂妄的贱人
You could be a real stuck-up bitch at times, can't you?
我知道  娘胎里带的  我正改呢
I know. Genetics. I'm working on it.
科利部长  她上船以后
Secretary Curry, when she's on that ship,
我希望你能保证她的安全
I need you to promise me she'll be safe.
不好意思保罗  我不能保证你任何事
Excuse me, Paul, but I'm not gonna promise you anything.
这可不仅仅是一个女人的问题
This isn't about just one woman.
更重要的是我们国家的未来
It's about the future of our country.
我相信在这点上你和我们是一致的
I thought you believed that as much as we do.
曾是的  我是说  现在也赞同
I did. I-I mean, I-I still do.
很好  现在听好了  有一个女人
Okay, now listen, there's a woman--
凯莉・辛克莱  有印象吗
Kylie Sinclair. Name ring a bell?
有  辛克莱武器财团继承人  怎么了
Yeah, daughter to the Sinclair weapons fortune. Why?
克里斯蒂提过她吗
Christine hasn't mentioned her?
没有  我得挂了
Not yet. Look, I gotta go.
我到了
I'm here.
他要进来了
And so he is.
等等  拿上这个
Wait, wait, wait. Take this. Take this.
拜托千万要是好消息
Please tell me it's good news.
我可以上那艘船吗
Were you able to get me on that boat?
我没能给你争取到机会
I couldn't get you cleared for the trip.
对不起
Sorry.
真的吗
Really?
我找了很多关系  可是他们不许
Went as far up the chain as I could, but they shot it down.
他们不想让你出现在那艘船上
They just don't want you on that ship.
真心希望能帮到你
I wish there was something I could do.
军士长
Chief.
艇长
Oh, captain.
准备出门
You going somewhere?
没有
Uh, no.
只是找些事做
It's, uh, just busy work.
尽量不去想...
Trying to keep my mind off of the...
我现在缺粮缺物资
I'm low on food and provisions.
尤其缺人手
I'm low on crew.
告诉我你没干那种事
Tell me you didn't do this.
告诉我那女人在撒谎
Tell me the woman's lying,
我会尽我所能保护你
and I will do whatever is necessary to protect you.
给我一本圣经  我可以发誓
You give me a bible, and I will swear on it.
我没有  长官
I did not do this, sir.
好的  军士长
Okay, chief.
明天同一时间
Same time tomorrow?
抱歉  上尉
Oh, sorry, lieutenant.
格蕾丝  请进
Come on in, Grace.
你听说过安德斯的事情了吧
You've heard about this, uh, situation with Anders?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
好  我想你来替他辩护
Okay, I want you to handle his defense.
我不太确定自己是否合适
I'm just not sure I'm the right person for the job.
你在军校里曾是荣誉委员会成员
You've put in time on the honor committee at the academy,
已经比我们所有人都出色了
which is... more than the rest of us.
明白  长官
Understood, sir.
你只管尽力为他辩护
You just give him the best defense you can.
惊喜哦
Surprise.
不许动
Don't move!
塑料勺做撞匙很管用
M.R.E. Spoon makes a pretty good bump key.
要是我乐意
I could've been sipping tequila
三天前就在某处海滩上喝龙舌兰了
on a beach in antigua three days ago if that's what I'd wanted,
可我不想那样
but it's not what I want.
现在信我了吗
Trust me now?
我知道通讯点在哪  可以带你去
I know where the site is. I can take you there.
你知道通讯点在哪
You know where the site is?
我可以让你
I can put you on the horn with people
跟上层大人物直接通话
a lot more important than the two of us.
我有话要问他们  布斯
I'm gonna ask them what I need to, booth.
跟他们合作  山姆
You work with 'em, Sam,
他们会给你任何你想要的东西
they'll give you whatever you want.
不耍花招
No more tricks.
他来做什么
What's he doing here?
艇长
Captain.
我想这事肯定与你脱不了干系
I imagined your fingerprints would be all over this.
只是没想到你会主动跳出来
Just never thought they'd be so visible.
你们的争执先放在一边
Whatever your quarrel,
艾瑞塔请塞拉特先生代表原告发言
Erita has asked that Mr. Serrat speak for the prosecution.
朱利安一直对我很好
Julian has always been good to me.
而且他不怕你
And he's not afraid of you.
你确定吗
Are you quite sure of that?
我只想看正义得到伸张
I wish only to see justice served.
我们进去说
Let's go inside.
我发现人在青天白日之下更诚实
I've found that the open air is quite conducive to honesty.
你不同意吗  艇长
Do you not agree, captain?
你明白我们谈话的目的吧
Do you understand why we're all here?
我请他一起走走
I asked him to go for a walk.
我只想说说话
I just wanted to talk, you know?
的确  我们后来开始接吻
It's true, we started kissing.
他开始变得怪怪的
But he started acting strange,
说我应该把头发剪短
Telling me I should cut my hair,
他喜欢头发短一些的女人
that he liked women with shorter hair,
真是奇怪  就好像他自认是我男友
which was weird. Like he thought he was my boyfriend.
你也见过她
I-I mean, you've seen her.
她可以和任何她想要的人搞在一起
She could've gone off with anyone she wanted to.
是她选了我
She chose me.
然后我们开始接吻
Then we started kissing.
他抓住我
He grabbed me,
狠狠吻我
kissed me hard.
我说"不"
I told him "No."
我想逃  可他追过来
I tried to run, but he chased me.
然后他抓住我
After he caught me...
把我压倒
he held me down,
开始撕我的衣服
started tearing at my clothes.
我不否认和她发生过性关系
I'm not denying that we had sex.
我们做了  而且很愉快
We did, and it was nice.
我动弹不得
I couldn't move.
我只能躺在那儿  等待他发泄完
I just laid there waiting for it to be over.
我穿衣服的时候
When I started putting my clothes back on,
她说我欠她一百美元
she said that I owed her 100 bucks.
她可没提这一点
She didn't say anything about that.
她为什么要提
Why would she?
她只要说声"强奸"  我就成了禽兽
All she has to do is say the word "rape," and I become a monster.
这有何公正可言
Now where's the justice in that?
我不是自愿的
I didn't ask for this.
利比亚才是人间地狱
Now Libya-- that was hell.
持续了12天的狂乱
12 days of soul-searching madness.
听说把卡扎菲推上宝座花了不少功夫
I heard it was hard getting Gaddafi on the throne,
可你该看看把他拉下来又费了多大力
but you shoulda seen us trying to get him off.
你呢  有可见的伤疤吗
How about you? Any visible scars?
没有  北朝鲜人不喜欢留下记号
No, North Koreans don't like to leave marks.
对  至少不留在表面
Yeah, at least not on the outside.
我在16个国家被囚禁过
I've been thrown in the hole in 16 different countries.
如果这地方算国家  就是17个
Well, I guess 17 depending what you call this place.
你总被擒获
You get caught a lot.
没想过改行吗
You ever think about a different line of work?
干事业是有代价的
Ah, the price of doing business.
拷打我能承受  身体会恢复
Beatings I can take. The body bounces back.
可是感官剥夺...  眼睛蒙死
But sensory dep--blindfold,
鼻子堵住  耳朵塞上
nose closed, ears plugged--
好了  你说的很明白了
Okay, okay, you made your point.
一条通路直达脑内
One-way ticket straight to the inside of your head.
经历过后回到妻子身边都难
Hard to go back to the wife after that.
你结婚了吗
What, you're married?
结了  维持了几年
Yeah, for a couple of years back when.
不可调和的分歧
Irreconcilable differences.
不是她的错
It wasn't her fault.
她当初并不知道要面对怎样的婚后生活
She didn't know what she signed up for.
懂我意思吗
Know what I mean?
你当然懂
Yeah. You sure as hell do.
主泵读数400度以上
The main pump is reading more than 400 degrees.
你正遭受攻击  需要所有动力
You're under attack and need full power.
接通辅助泵
Bring second pump online,
冷却  动力降到80%
flush for cold while reducing power 80%.
-艇长需要动力全开  -不行
- Your captain needs full power. - He can't have it.
热得化了可哪里都去不了
We melt down, we're going nowhere.
辅助泵读数500度以上
The auxiliary pump is reading 500-plus degrees.
-关闭辅助泵  全停  -你正遭遇攻击
- Shut it down. Full stop. - You're under attack.
不关我事  超过红线40%  必须停
Not my problem. It's 40% over redline. Gotta stop.
您说我能在这样短的时间里掌握核潜艇吗
You think I can really get nuke rated this fast?
掌握潜艇  不能
Uh, nuke rated? No.
但是紧要关头坚持航行
But being able to keep us going when we have to?
才是现阶段的目标
That's the goal right now.
因为一旦我们失去安德斯
Because if we lose Anders,
艇上所有人的性命就掌握在你手里
every life in the sub is gonna be in your hands.
你可以相信我  长官
You can trust me, sir.
请进
Enter.
可以跟你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you, sir?
他对他们说谎
He's lying to them,
说我不想去
telling them that I don't want to go.
你想知道他为什么会这样吗
You ready for it all to start making sense?
保罗・威尔斯升平
The life and times of Paul Wells.
你的保罗从小孤独
So your Paul is one lonely guy.
郊区长大
Grew up in the suburbs.
安纳波利斯毕业之后进了乔治敦法学院
After Annapolis, went to Georgetown Law.
刚一工作就进了大公司
Started working at a big firm,
2007年接了一桩婚姻家庭法相关的案子
and then in 2007, gets a job practicing family law.
就在那时他遇到了她
That's when he met her.
她真漂亮
She's gorgeous.
她是他的委托人
She was his client.
为第二次离婚一案而找的他
Came to him for her second divorce,
他应该据此看清那女人  但他没有
which should've been a clue, but no.
他替她争下丰厚的和解金  作为结婚礼物
He got her a fat settlement as a wedding present.
一年后  她替他生下了丹尼尔
A year later, she gave him Daniel.
九个月后  她带走了丹尼尔
Nine months after that, she took Daniel away.
事先毫无说明
No warning.
直接带上那孩子  搭上了去巴西圣保罗的飞机
Just takes the kid, hops on a plane to Sao Paulo.
他已经两年没跟儿子见面或通电话
He hasn't seen or spoken to his son in two years.
那太不幸了
That's terrible.
那男人总会爱上自己拯救的女人
This is a man who falls for the women he saves.
现在那女人就是你
Right now that's you.
所以你们那晚的吻或许
So that kiss the other night probably lodged itself
直击他缺爱的小心脏中  爱意正在
right in the middle of his needy little heart,
萌芽
where it's growing--
不
No.
我不是说要让你和他上床
I'm not saying you have to sleep with him--
很好  因为我不会的
Good, because I'm not going to.
我是说  你正面临大好机会
I'm saying, you have an opportunity.
利用一个心碎父亲的寂寞吗
To exploit a heartbroken father's loneliness?
他每天过来  都在做一个选择
Every day this guy comes here and makes a choice.
但他每天都选择欺骗你
Every day he chooses to lie to you,
摆布你
to manipulate you,
试图毁掉你和你的婚姻
to try and destroy you and your marriage.
那就是他的真面目  再无其他
That's what this guy is. Nothing more.
现在我们知道他想要什么
Now we know what he wants.
就是你
You.
所以你想要如何去应对
So what are you willing to do about it?
还得上多高
How far up is it?
再爬6公里
Another six klicks.
但上面是笔直的  吉普车到这儿就没用了
But it's straight up. The jeep's useless from here.
好吧  我们就在这儿扎营  明天早点开始
Okay. Let's camp here. Get an early start.
给  你今天的鹅肝口粮
Your, uh, your foie gras rations for the day.
话说...
So, um...
你结婚多久了  肯德尔
how long you been married, Kendal?
你读过我的联合特种作战司令部档案
You read my J.S.O.C. File.
我只是想跟你谈心而已
Just making polite conversation.
好吧
Okay.
我已经结婚两年了
I've been married two years.
你一直在海上  所以加起来也就在一起6周吗
You been at sea, what, all but six weeks?
是的
That's right.
眼下你恐怕得过很久才能回去了吧
Gonna be a while before you get back now, huh?
我一定会回去的
I'll get back.
我一直都喜欢火
Always loved fire.
火焰中是纯净的世界  美丽和死亡
That's purity right there. Beauty and death.
他们把我的手绑在身后
They tied my hands behind my back.
他把我按在一块木板上
He sat me down on a plank.
木板下面堆着砖头
Couple of bricks underneath.
谁知道当一名海军要受那样的罪
Who ever knew sitting on a board could hurt so bad?
过了...
After...
过了不知道多久
I don't know how long it was...
他们走了进来  拿走了木板
They came in, they took the plank away
然后让我跪在砖头上
and made me kneel on the bricks.
然后把枪抵在你的脑袋上吗
That when they put the gun to your head?
我想着我的妻子  支撑我挺过去
I'd get through it thinking about my wife.
她在玩填字游戏时
The way her hair hung down over her face
秀发披在前面的样子
when she was doing the crossword.
那现在是什么支撑着你
What gets you through now, then?
同样的事
Same thing.
我妻子  她
My wife, she, uh...
她有一种习惯  她每次
She has this... She answers "Yes"
在我话没问完的时候  就说"好的"
before I finish asking her for something.
那让她显得过于顺从  但其实不是的  她
It makes her sound like a bit of a pushover, but she's not. It's...
那是种信任
It's trust.
是信赖
It's belief.
我也说不清
I don't know.
那样的女人  老兄
These women, man...
会让我们怀疑已知的一切
make us doubt everything we know.
然后在你根本都毫无预料的时候
And then when you least expect it...
帮助你撑过最艰难的时期
They get you through hell.
是的  没错
Yes, they do.
明天你就离你的目标更近一步
And tomorrow you get a step closer to yours.
作为一个英雄光荣返乡
You'll go home a hero.
他们或许会为你办个阅兵式
Probably throw you a damn parade.
我以为你们这样的不会推举英雄
Thought you guys didn't have heroes.
我们是没有
We don't.
但我们深知如何让别人成为英雄
But we sure as hell know how to make 'em.
每个政变都需要一个完美的故事
Every coup d'etat needs a story.
每个故事都需要主人公
Every story needs a face.
马库斯・查普林显然不是那个大英雄
Marcus Chaplin wasn't gonna be that mug.
相信我  马库斯不需要一场阅兵式
Believe me, Marcus doesn't need a parade
来证明他的身份
to tell him who he is.
那基本不可能
Not by a long shot.
你仍然未下定决心  是吗
You still haven't made up your mind, have you?
如果我告诉你  你那样会救他的命呢
What if I told you, you're saving his life?
布斯
Booth...
如果你想让他死
If you wanted him dead,
他早已经死了
he'd be dead already.
组织向来都不喜欢殉道者
The agency has a bad history with martyrs.
我们十分恐惧他们
We're downright terrified of 'em.
但万不得已  我们只能做殉道者
But we'll make 'em if we have to.
他从没对你动手动脚吗
He never tried anything?
安德斯吗  当然没有
Anders? Hell, no.
他是个正直的好人
He was one of the good guys.
跟艇上的其他男兵形成鲜明对比
As opposed to the rest of the frat boys on this boat.
每次在通道相遇都想揩油  让人避之不及
Somehow there's just never enough space to get by them in a corridor.
咸猪手乱摸...
And the hands...
你为什么不举报
Why don't you report it?
不行  一旦举报  你自己就成了麻烦
Nah. You report it, you become a problem.
幸运的话  你会被调离
Best case, you get transferred.
不幸的话  你会被调到更差劲的地方
Worst case, you get transferred someplace worse.
但安德斯  他一直很规矩对吗
But Anders--he kept his hands to himself?
他是我在核反应堆控制部的军士长
He's my department chief at the reactor.
他从未有过不轨行为
He never tried a thing,
但他最近有些异样
but he's been different lately.
沉默  可能是因为他妻子的事
Quiet. Probably 'cause of his wife.
他妻子怎么了
What happened with his wife?
下海10天后  收到妻子要求断绝关系的家信
Got the "Dear John" family-gram ten days into the tour.
-她提出了离婚申请  -她还怀孕了
- She filed for divorce. - She's pregnant, too.
-天啊  -是啊  真无情
- God. - Yeah, stone cold.
那事发生的几天后
Couple days after it happened,
我发现他盯着我看
I caught him looking at me.
不是色咪咪那种  更像是...
Not really sexual. It was more...
什么
What?
我说不清  伤心
I don't know. Sad.
似乎现在任何一个女人
Like every woman from now on
都只会让他想起她
is only gonna make him think of her.
你认为他强奸了那个女孩吗
Do you think that he raped that girl?
我不知道
I don't know.
她混迹在酒吧
She hangs around the bar,
跟男人们搭讪
chatting up the guys.
她在"鹰巢"酒吧工作
She works at the Buzzard's Nest.
那只是表面上的"工作"罢了
Well, that's one way to put it.
哈尔不是唯一跟她上过的男人
Hal's not the only one she's been with.
我也跟她上过
She was with me, too.
而且不是免费的
And it wasn't for free.
你花钱跟她上床吗
You gave her money for sex?
不  不是钱
No, not money.
而是食物  杂志
Food, magazines, you know...
手边随便什么东西
whatever's lying around.
她可是很乐意接受呢
She was more than happy to take it.
当他向我报告这一信息的时候
When he came to me with this information,
我觉得有必要让双方都知道
I thought it was important to share with both parties.
长官  里士满和安德斯是好朋友
Sir, Richmond and Anders are friends.
他们一起经历...
They came up through the--
我以为你是想找出真相
I thought you wanted to get to the truth.
你的任务是为一位美国军人提供有力的辩护
Your job is to provide an American serviceman with a vigorous defense.
就因为她也和里士满上床了
Just because she may have slept with Richmond,
就因为她事后收受了礼物
just because she may have accepted gifts afterwards,
并不意味着她就不是被强奸的
doesn't mean she wasn't raped.
如果事件有相关性  就好好利用
If it's relevant, use it.
长官  我知道安德斯是你的得力干将
Sir, I know that Anders is your bull nuke.
所以当需要将核反应堆联机时
So when it comes to keeping the reactor online,
他是你的第一选择  也是唯一选择
he's your number one, he's your only one.
所以我能理解你的愿望
So I can understand your desire.
我不喜欢你话里有话  上尉
I do not like the implication, lieutenant.
抱歉  长官
Sorry, sir.
告诉我不会像往常一样内部处理
Just tell me this isn't gonna be navy justice as usual.
告诉我能以更好的方式解决
Tell me we can do better.
干好你的本职工作  上尉
Be the best at your job, lieutenant,
其它事情都会自行解决
and the rest will sort itself out.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
这些是礼物
They were gifts.
我没有要求过这些
I didn't ask for any of it.
他说这些作为嫖资
Well, he said they were payment for sex.
这算什么  你们来质问我吗
What is this? I'm the one you're asking questions about?
为什么不问哈尔・安德斯
What about Hal Anders?
我也在质问他
I'm asking about him, too.
是吗  问问他有没有撞倒过其他姑娘
Are you? Ask him if he ran down any other girls.
有没有把别人推倒在地上
If he pushed anyone else to the ground,
扒光她的衣服  压在她身上
tore off her clothes, and held her down?
你能问问他曾经有没有干过这些吗
Will you ask him if he'd ever done any of that?
因为那就是他
Because that's what he did
对我的暴行
to me.
克里斯蒂
Christine?
别管那些
Leave them off.
电话中你听起来很奇怪
You sounded strange on the phone.
你是不是
Are you, uh...
我得去见我的丈夫
I have to see my husband.
我说过  能做的我都做了
I told you, I've done everything I can.
我知道你思念他  但你
I know you miss him, but you--
不是这样
That's not it.
我得见到山姆
I need to see Sam
这样我才能告诉他我要离开他
so I can tell him that I'm leaving him.
但我得当面告诉他
But I have to tell him in person,
不然他不会相信的
otherwise he'll never believe it.
他只会
He'll just...
他只会认为那是政府的又一个诡计
He'll just think that it's another government trick.
我以为你深爱他
I thought you loved him.
我吻了你
I kissed you.
那个吻
That was, uh--
我知道那意味着什么  你也是
I know what it was, and so do you.
我不喜欢  也感到羞耻  但
And I don't like it and I am not proud of it, but...
但这感觉是真的
but it was real.
所以我得见到我的丈夫
So I need to see my husband.
这样我才能告诉他一切都结束了
So I can tell him that it's over.
世界之巅啊
Top of the world.
你知道发送或接收的信息都会被加密吧
You realize anything in or out will be encrypted?
看来我只能信你一次了
Guess I'm just gonna have to trust you then.
好吧
Okay.
先把话说明白
Just so we're clear,
你提出问题  你为他们工作
you ask the question, you're working for them.
休眠者是谁
Who's the sleeper agent?
你会让查普林知道吗
Intel just for you or Chaplin?
看来我也只能相信你了
Guess I'll just have to trust you.
的确如此
I guess so.
好的
All right.
要等一会  他们要先解码
It'll take a minute for the backup singers to transpose the lyric.
知道吗  我碰到了加扎菲
You know, I met Gadhafi.
他最后成了个疯子
He was one crazy mother in the end.
但之前  你不会想到
But before-- you'd never think it now--
他很谦逊
but he was humble.
抱歉  你刚说他很谦逊吗
I'm sorry. Did you say he was humble?
是啊  他是这样
Yeah, he was,
就像他接到了一个神圣的电话
like he'd been given a sacred calling,
接着就成了他一生的负担
and it was his burden in life to answer.
不  这是妄想而非谦逊
No, that's more delusional than humble.
不  起初不是那样
Nah, wasn't like that at first.
他的确认为他能改变世界
He really thought he could change the world.
最后却是世界改变了他
Then the world changed him.
是世界改变了他吗
The world changed him, huh?
我不知道  布斯
I don't know, Booth.
听起来他一开始就像是个疯子
Sounds like he was a nut job right from the start.
想法不错
Nice to believe that.
天下所有的坏人都和其他人相异
All the bad people in the world are nothing like the rest of us.
他们天生就有缺陷  没得到足够的父爱
They got a defective gene. Daddy didn't love 'em enough.
但事实并非这样
But that ain't the case.
坏人只是那些初尝权利
Bad people are just decent folks
却一发不可收拾的好人
who've had a taste of power and wanted more.
就好比你的长官
Take your captain, for example.
我知道你不想听这些  山姆
I know you don't want to hear it, Sam,
但马库斯・查普林距离
but Marcus Chaplin is one spoonful away
重蹈加扎菲的覆辙只有一步之遥了
from going the way of the Gadhafis of the world.
我知道你在干什么  你可以闭嘴了
I know what you're doing and you can cut the crap, okay?
你不了解他  一点也不
You don't know the man. Not even close.
开玩笑吗  这就是我们干的事  山姆
Are you kidding? It's what we do, Sam.
我们进入其他国家  挑起事端
We go into countries, we stir things up,
然后我们带走某人
then we pick someone.
某些军方人士  某些具有领导能力
Someone from the military, someone with leadership skills,
和正义感的人
and the righteousness
他们相信自己能统领所有人
to think they make up the rules for everyone.
听起来耳熟吗
Sound like anyone you know?
棒球
Baseball.
4  6
Four. Six.
2  1
Two. One.
飞机场
Airport.
6  5  3  6
Six. Five. Three. Six.
帮我个忙
Do me a-a favor.
叫我的名字
Say my name.
搞什么  布斯
Come on, Booth.
不  我的真名  约翰・斯托瑟
No. My real name. John Stosur.
-为什么  -拜托了  山姆
- Why? - Please, Sam.
约翰・斯托瑟
John Stosur.
我已经20年没听到别人这么叫我了
I haven't heard it out loud in 20 years.
我错了
I was wrong.
他们不愿说出休眠者是谁
They won't give up the sleeper.
政府资产比你对他们更重要
Asset's more important to them than you.
美国人认为这是我们在这座岛上
The americans believe that this is the first trial
实行的第一次审判
we've ever had on this island.
不
No!
但我们已经审判过许多次了
But we've had many trials.
对
Yes!
我们刚来这里就有过审判
Trials that began when they first came here.
我们得容忍他们占领我们的街道
We've had to share our streets with them.
我们得看着我们的孩子们挨饿
We've had to watch our children starve
因为他们在船上不能挨饿
because they won't allow in boats.
是的
Yes.
他们不愿离开  所以我们会遭难
We've had to spill our blood because they won't leave.
我们得因为他们引起的战争而失去和平
We've had to give up our peaceful lives for their war.
我们真的能在这找到正义吗
Can we really hope to find justice here?
不  我们真的能相信这个姑娘
No. Can we really believe that this girl--
我们的姐妹  女儿  我们的同胞
our sister, our daughter, our own.
我们能看到
Can expect to see the man
那个强奸她的男人受到制裁吗
responsible for her rape punished for his crime?
不
No.
我不相信这里有正义
I don't believe there is justice here,
但也许你能证明我是错的
but maybe you will prove me wrong.
我们不知道那晚发生了什么
We'll never know what happened that night.
我们不知道是因为没有任何证据
We'll never know because there is no evidence.
没有目击者
No witnesses.
没有物证
No physical proof.
没有伤痕来证明是否做过反抗
No cuts or bruises to indicate a struggle.
没有证据
And without evidence,
只有他俩各执一词
it's just her story against his.
我们不会剥夺自由
We do not take away freedom.
我们不会因为一个人的说词
We do not injure, lash, brand a man
就伤害  鞭打和谴责另一个人
because of what one person says.
我们不会那样
We're better than that.
现在没有证据
There is no evidence.
只有一个女人的说词
Just a word a woman said.
个人说词不能证明一个人有罪
A word does not make a man guilty.
在学校发生过这种事
It happened at the academy.
我把一个渎职的候补军官带到了委员会
I had brought a cadet before the committee for misconduct.
那是他的一个朋友
It was one of his friends.
他想要复仇
He wanted revenge.
他如愿了
He got it.
格蕾丝  我很抱歉
Grace, I'm so sorry.
我向最高领导汇报了这件事
I reported it to the master chief.
他告诉我
And he told me that...
作为一个海军上将的女儿
as an admiral's daughter,
我应该想想外界的看法
I should think about how it would be perceived.
那会是我和他各执一词
That it would be my story against his,
如果我起诉  没人能取胜
and that no one could win if I brought charges.
所以你就放弃了
So you dropped it?
我不得不每天都见到
I had to see the man who raped me...
那个强奸我的人
every day
一直到我毕业
until I graduated.
艾瑞塔肯定被奸污了
Erita was raped.
我和她交谈的时候
When I talked to her,
我能看出来她都经历了什么
I could see what she was going through.
并且她经历的正是
And that is something that...
我努力不再去想
I have tried to never think about again...
不再触碰的事
to never feel again.
但是我看出来了
But I recognized it.
我知道她被强奸了
I knew it.
发生什么事了
What happened?
出结果了
Verdict's in.
无罪
Not guilty.
蹲下
Get down!
快过来
Come on.
雷达站安全  但是有些船员被困在那
The E.W.S. is secure, but there's crew pinned down in the bivouac.
好的  通知他们
Okay, radio back.
不允许朝人群开火
I don't want any shots fired into that crowd.
明白
Got it.
艇长
Captain, uh,
我觉得应该告诉你陪审团的投票情况
I think you should know how the jury voted.
我和两名船员认为他有罪
Two of the crewmembers and myself thought he was guilty.
一名船员和所有的岛民都投了无罪
One of your crew and all the islanders voted not guilty.
我不知道为什么
I-I don't know why.
塞拉特操纵陪审团反对自己
Serrat rigged the jury against himself.
他一手策划这次骚乱
He wanted this to happen.
不用担心
Don't worry.
今晚没人能进来
No one's coming through those doors. Not tonight.
这其实应该是我最后一次出海
This was supposed to be my last tour.
我现在应该在家了
I should be home right now.
听说这次出海期间你老婆生了孩子
Hear you have a baby on the way.
不  她离开我了
No, she left me.
怀孕四个月时  她遇到了一个人
Four months pregnant, and she meets some other guy.
如果我能和她谈谈
If only I could've talked to her,
我可能能让她回心转意
I could have made her see things straight,
但他
But he...
算了  她已经离开我了
No, she's gone.
而且现在
And now, uh...
现在怎么了
Now what?
现在这样  这些人烧自己的街道
Now this. These people burning up their streets,
嚷着要我的命
screaming for my head.
你只不过想回家
You just wanted to go home.
那姑娘当着众人面对我示好
That girl coming on to me in front of everybody...
你就吻她因为你认为
And you kissed her because you thought
她想你那么做
that's what she wanted.
她的确是那样
She did want it.
那不是你的错
Well, it's not your fault--
我知道不是我的错
I know it's not my fault.
他不放我们回家
He won't let me go home.
他不会让我去见我妻子
He won't let me see my wife.
所以当艾瑞塔反抗时  已经太迟了是吗
And by the time Erita told you no, it was too late to stop.
我绝不会做那种事情  绝不会
I would never do something like that. Never.
但你做了
But you did.
她叫你停下
She told you to stop.
她是笑着说的
She said it with a smirk.
你强奸了她
You raped her.
这全是艇长的错
This is the captain's fault!
是他不让我们回家  好吗
He won't let any of us go home. Okay?
这是他的错  不是我的
This is his fault! Not mi--
科利部长  我终于说服她了
Secretary Curry, I finally got her to come around.
她说只有我陪着  她才会去
She said she'll only go if I go with her.
确保他在你身边
Making sure he stays close to you.
好的  听着保罗  我要你
Fine. Listen, Paul, I'm gonna need you
往深了挖一挖
to dig up a little something.
海豹陆战队员都会带着头盔摄像机
Navy SEALS, they wear helmet cams.
摄像机会记录在加密芯片上
The cams record onto encrypted chips.
克里斯蒂的新朋友凯莉・辛克莱
Christine's new friend Kylie Sinclair,
她有读取这些影响的技术权限
she has access to tech that can read them.
如果这个女人这么危险
Look, if this woman's so dangerous to you,
你为何不
why don't you just--
不经意地跟克里斯蒂提一下
Yeah, just mention it to Christine in passing.
我想看看她有什么反应
I want to know how she reacts.
你会联系山姆  告之我会去找他
So you'll reach Sam, tell him I'm coming?
是的  但是你要小心
Yes. Just be careful.
你也是
You, too.
我不怎么交女性朋友
I don't usually make female friends.
老实说  我一直把其他女人当竞争对手
Honestly, I tend to think of other women as the competition.
我意思是  击败她们
You know, to be crushed.
我就说说而已
I'm just saying.
别那么不好意思
Don't strain a muscle.
我也喜欢你
I like you, too.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这些旧木板都发霉了
These old boards are pretty moldy.
你应该把整个地板都换了
You should probably replace the whole floor.
只要一两天时间
Just take me a day or two.
你不必停业太久
You wouldn't have to shut down for long.
常在河边走
You can't keep one foot in the water
哪能不湿鞋
and one on the shore.
你说什么
What?
谢谢你
Thank you.
谢我什么
For what?
就是  谢谢你
Just... thank you.
我再去那些木板来  好吗
Just need to get some more lumber. All right?
好的
Okay.
终于有机会能回艇上了
There's a window to get to the sub.
抓紧时间  快走
Let's not let it close. Let's go!
-长官  -身为"科罗拉多号"艇长
- Sir? - As captain of the "Colorado,"
基于你的不道德的行为
it's my obligation to issue a discharge
我有责任将你解职
based upon immoral conduct.
二级军士长哈罗德・安德斯
Senior Chief Petty Officer Harold Anders,
你被解除所有职务
You're hereby relieved of duty
并需要监禁
and ordered to be taken into custody.
你在说什么  他们认为我是清白的
What the hell are you talking about? They found me innocent.
不  虽然他们认为你无罪
No, they found you not guilty.
但我们都知道你不是清白的
We both know you're not innocent.
你在潜艇里可以受到保护
You will be afforded my protection on the submarine,
但不再作为船员或者访客
but it won't be as a crewmember or as a guest.
你会被铐在禁闭室
It'll be in handcuffs and confined to solitary
直到你安全移交美国有关部门
till you can safely be handed over to American authority.
你这道貌岸然的杂种
You sanctimonious son of a bitch.
我决不允许一个强奸犯
I won't have an admitted rapist
在我的船上走动并和我的船员混在一起
walk free on my boat and mingle with my crew.
你们不能把我铐起来
You're not putting me in cuffs.
你想在我船上待着就得这样
That's the only way you're stepping foot on my boat.
救援船一天后就到了
Relief boat gets here in a day.
你认为我撑不了一天
You think I can't survive until then?
我才不会去想你活下来几率多大
Hey, I won't calculate those odds.
但是  在这岛上  你被判无罪
But it's true, on this island, you're an acquitted man.
你做任何决定是你的自由
You're free to make your own choices.
你就让他这么对我
You're just gonna let him do this?
如果我是你  我认为还是被铐着的好
If it were up to me, it'd be a lot worse than handcuffs.
见你的鬼去吧  长官
I'll see you in hell, sir.
上车
In the jeep.
我们走
Let's go.